<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<records>
		<AllPerson>
			<Artist name="Maes, Nicolaes">
				<description>Englisch description: Nicolaes Maes, also known as Nicolaes Maas (January 1634 – November 24, 1693 (buried)) was a Dutch Golden Age painter of genre and portraits.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schütz d. Ä., Christian Georg">
				<description>German description: Christian Georg Schütz der Ältere (* 24. September 1718 in Flörsheim am Main; † 3. Dezember 1791 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler und Kupferstecher.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deutscher Meister der zweiten Hälfte des 17. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hals, Frans">
				<description>Englisch description: Frans Hals the Elder (/hɑːls/; Dutch: [ɦɑls]; c. 1582 – 26 August 1666) was a Dutch Golden Age portrait painter who lived and worked in Haarlem. He is notable for his loose painterly brushwork, and he helped introduce this lively style of painting into Dutch art. Hals played an important role in the evolution of 17th-century group portraiture.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruysdael, Salomon van">
				<description>Englisch description: Salomon van Ruysdael (c. 1602, Naarden – buried November 3, 1670, Haarlem) was a Dutch Golden Age landscape painter. He was the uncle of Jacob van Ruisdael.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weenix, Jan">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Weenix or Joannis Wenix (between 1640/1649 – 19 September 1719 (buried)) was a Dutch painter. He was trained by his father, Jan Baptist Weenix, together with his cousin Melchior d'Hondecoeter. Like his father, he devoted himself to a variety of subjects, but his fame is chiefly due to his paintings of dead game and of hunting scenes. Many pictures in this genre formerly ascribed to the elder Weenix are now generally considered to be the works of the son.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jordaens, Jacob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob Jordaens (19 May 1593 – 18 October 1678) was a Flemish painter, draughtsman and tapestry designer known for his history paintings, genre scenes and portraits. After Peter Paul Rubens and Anthony van Dyck, he was the leading Flemish Baroque painter of his day. Unlike those contemporaries he never travelled abroad to study Italian painting, and his career is marked by an indifference to their intellectual and courtly aspirations. In fact, except for a few short trips to locations in the Low Countries, he remained in Antwerp his entire life. As well as being a successful painter, he was a prominent designer of tapestries. Like Rubens, Jordaens painted altarpieces, mythological, and allegorical scenes, and after 1640—the year Rubens died—he was the most important painter in Antwerp for large-scale commissions and the status of his patrons increased in general. However, he is best known today for his numerous large genre scenes based on proverbs in the manner of his contemporary Jan Brueghel the Elder, depicting The King Drinks and As the Old Sing, So Pipe the Young. Jordaens' main artistic influences, besides Rubens and the Brueghel family, were northern Italian painters such as Jacopo Bassano, Paolo Veronese, and Caravaggio.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Velde, Adriaen van de">
				<description>Englisch description: Adriaen van de Velde (bapt. 30 November 1636, Amsterdam – bur. 21 January 1672, Amsterdam), was a Dutch animal and landscape painter, son of Willem van de Velde the Elder and brother of Willem van de Velde the Younger, the marine painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schalcken, Godfried">
				<description>Englisch description: Godfried Schalcken or Gottfried Schalken (1643 – November 16, 1706), was a Dutch genre and portrait painter. He was noted for his mastery in reproducing the effect of candlelight, and painted in the exquisite and highly polished manner of the Leiden fijnschilders.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Keyser, Thomas de">
				<description>Englisch description: Thomas de Keyser (c. 1596–1667) was a Dutch painter and architect.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Roos, Johann Heinrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Heinrich Roos (29 September 1631, Otterberg – 3 October 1685, Frankfurt) was a German Baroque era landscape painter and etcher.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Französischer Meister um 1550/1600">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Molenaer, Jan Miense">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Miense Molenaer (1610 – buried 19 September 1668), was a Dutch Golden Age genre painter whose style was a precursor to Jan Steen's work during Dutch Golden Age painting. He shared a studio with his wife, Judith Leyster, also a genre painter, as well as a portraitist and painter of still-life. Both Molenaer and Leyster may have been pupils of the successful Dutch painter, Frans Hals.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rubens, Peter Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Sir Peter Paul Rubens (/ˈruːbənz/; Dutch: [ˈrybə(n)s]; 28 June 1577 – 30 May 1640) was a Flemish Baroque painter. A proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality, Rubens is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces, portraits, landscapes, and history paintings of mythological and allegorical subjects. In addition to running a large studio in Antwerp that produced paintings popular with nobility and art collectors throughout Europe, Rubens was a classically educated humanist scholar and diplomat who was knighted by both Philip IV of Spain and Charles I of England. Rubens was a prolific artist. The catalogue of his works by Michael Jaffé lists 1,403 pieces, excluding numerous copies made in his workshop. His commissioned works were mostly "history paintings", which included religious and mythological subjects, and hunt scenes. He painted portraits, especially of friends, and self-portraits, and in later life painted several landscapes. Rubens designed tapestries and prints, as well as his own house. He also oversaw the ephemeral decorations of the royal entry into Antwerp by the Cardinal-Infante Ferdinand in 1635. His drawings are mostly extremely forceful but not overly detailed. He also made great use of oil sketches as preparatory studies. He was one of the last major artists to make consistent use of wooden panels as a support medium, even for very large works, but he used canvas as well, especially when the work needed to be sent a long distance. For altarpieces he sometimes painted on slate to reduce reflection problems.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Niederländischer Meister der zweiten Hälfte des 18. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Neer, Aert van der">
				<description>Englisch description: Aert van der Neer, or Aernout or Artus (c. 1603 – 9 November 1677), was a landscape painter of the Dutch Golden Age, specializing in small night scenes lit only by moonlight and fires, and snowy winter landscapes, both often looking down a canal or river. He was a contemporary of Albert Cuyp and Meindert Hobbema, and like the latter he lived and died in comparative obscurity.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Steen, Jan">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Havickszoon Steen (c. 1626 – buried 3 February 1679) was a Dutch genre painter of the 17th century (also known as the Dutch Golden Age). His works are known for their psychological insight, sense of humour and abundance of colour.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berckheyde, Job Andriesz">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruysch, Rachel">
				<description>Englisch description: Rachel Ruysch (3 June 1664 – 12 August 1750) was a still-life painter from the Northern Netherlands who specialized in flowers. She invented her own style and achieved international fame in her lifetime, being followed by Jan van Huysum who took flower painting to another degree of popularity. Due to her long and successful career that spanned over 6 decades, she became the best documented woman painter of the Dutch Golden Age.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pforr, Johann Georg">
				<description>German description: Johann Georg Pforr (* 14. Januar 1745 in Ulfen; † 9. Juni 1798 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein hessischer Maler der Goethezeit. Auf Grund seiner Spezialisierung auf die Pferdemalerei wurde er von seinen Zeitgenossen der deutsche Wouwerman genannt.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heyden, Jan van der">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan van der Heyden (5 March 1637, Gorinchem – 28 March 1712, Amsterdam) was a Dutch Baroque-era painter, glass painter, draughtsman and printmaker. Van der Heyden was one of the first Dutch painters to specialize in townscapes and became one of the leading architectural painters of the Dutch Golden Age. He painted a number of still lifes in the beginning and at the end of his career. Jan van der Heyden was also an engineer and inventor who made significant contributions to contemporary firefighting technology. He improved the fire hose in 1672, with his brother Nicolaes, who was a hydraulic engineer. He modified the manual fire engine, reorganised the volunteer fire brigade (1685) and wrote and illustrated the first firefighting manual (Brandspuiten-boek). A comprehensive street lighting scheme for Amsterdam, designed and implemented by van der Heyden, remained in operation from 1669 until 1840 and was adopted as a model by many other towns and abroad.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ochtervelt, Jacob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob Ochtervelt (1634 in Rotterdam – 1682 in Amsterdam), was a Dutch Golden Age painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Walscapelle, Jacob van">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob van Walscapelle (1644, Dordrecht – 1727, Amsterdam), was a Dutch Golden Age flower painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Poelenburch, Cornelis van">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis van Poelenburgh or Cornelis van Poelenburch (1594 – 12 August 1667), was a Dutch landscape painter and draughtsman. He was the leading representative of the first generation of Dutch landscape painters who were active in Rome in the early 17th century. He was known for small-scale paintings depicting Italianate landscapes with small figures enacting biblical or mythological scenes or in contemporary attire.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bega, Cornelis Pietersz">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis Pietersz Bega, or Cornelis Pietersz Begijn (1631/32 – 27 August 1664) was a Dutch Golden Age painter and engraver. Bega was born, lived and worked in Haarlem shake and was the son of sculptor and goldsmith Pieter Jansz. Begijn. His mother Maria was the illegitimate daughter of the Haarlem painter Cornelis van Haarlem. He assumed the name Bega when he started working professionally. He was a student of Adriaen van Ostade, and produced genre scenes of similar subjects, typically groups of a few peasant figures, often in interior settings, or fanciful figures such as The Alchemist (Malibu) or The Astrologer (London). From 1653 to 1654 he traveled by horse and boat on a Grand Tour with fellow painters Dirk Helmbreker, Vincent van der Vinne and Guillam Dubois through Germany, Switzerland and France. This trip was recorded in Vincent van der Vinne's diaries and gives an accurate view of the art in the cities they visited in those times. His dated works begin in 1652, and in 1654 he was accepted into the Haarlem Guild of St. Luke, dying only ten years later, which according to Houbraken was due to the plague. He was close friends with the Haarlem painter Leendert van der Cooghen. When he died he was buried in the grave of his grandfather Cornelis van Haarlem.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ermels, Johann Franciscus">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Verspronck, Jan Cornelisz.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heem, Cornelis de">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis de Heem (8 April 1631 (baptized) – 17 May 1695 (buried) ) was a still-life painter associated with both Flemish Baroque and Dutch Golden Age painting. He was a member of a large family of still-life specialists, of which his father, Jan Davidszoon de Heem (1606–1684), was the most significant. Cornelis was baptised in Leiden on 8 April 1631, and moved with his family to Antwerp in 1636. He appears to have been trained by his father in Antwerp, who, like him, was born in the Dutch Republic but died in the Southern Netherlands. Jan's subsequent career, like many painters—especially after the Peace of Westphalia in 1648—moved fluidly between the two traditionally-connected areas of the north and south Low Countries. He became a member of the Antwerp painters' guild in 1660, and from 1667 until the late 1680s he was variously active in Utrecht, IJsselstein, and The Hague. It is often not easy to distinguish the works of the different members of the family, which included his brother Jan Jansz., nephew Jan Jansz. II, and son David Cornelisz. (1663–after? 1718), who all painted mostly flower and fruit pieces in a similar style and probably often collaborated. Cornelis's works, however, tend to be small, display a preference for strong blues, and, over time, shifted away from the painterly style preferred by his father. He died in Antwerp, aged 64. 
*       
*       
*       
*       
* Pageantry Still Life with copulating sparrows, 1657, Städelsches Kunstinstitut</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruisdael, Jacob Isaacksz. van">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Teniers d. Ä., David">
				<description>Englisch description: David Teniers the Elder (1582 – 29 July 1649), Flemish painter, was born at Antwerp.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vos, Cornelis de">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis de Vos (1584 – 9 May 1651) was a Flemish painter, draughtsman and art dealer. He was one of the leading portrait painters in Antwerp and is best known for his sensitive portraits, in particular of children and families. He was also successful in other genres including history, religious and genre painting. He was a regular collaborator with Rubens.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Massys, Quentin">
				<description>Englisch description: Quentin Matsys (Dutch: Quinten Matsijs) (1466–1530) was a painter in the Flemish tradition and a founder of the Antwerp school. He was born at Leuven, where legend states he was trained as an ironsmith before becoming a painter. Matsys was active in Antwerp for over 20 years, creating numerous works with religious roots and satirical tendencies.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hobbema, Meindert">
				<description>Englisch description: Meindert Hobbema (bapt. October 31, 1638 – December 7, 1709) was a Dutch Golden Age landscape painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Barnaba da Modena">
				<description>Englisch description: As his name indicates, the artist was a native of Modena (Emilia). The first records regarding Barnaba date to 1361 and 1362 when he had already become a Genoese citizen and was hiring Tuscan assistants. His earliest dated paintings relate to his activities in Genoa. He produced paintings for the Palazzo Ducale in Genoa in 1364. His earliest known painting is a polyptych of the Virgin and Child with Saints (Palazzo Bianco, Genoa), which combines the Gothic style of Tuscan polyptychs with Emilian design. Another work, a Virgin and Child (Museum of Fine Arts, Boston), shows the influence of Sienese painting in the rounded faces and the gold-striated highlights on Mary's mantle. He was active in 1370 in Turin. A painting (1377) by Barnaba was documented by Tiraboschi in the church of San Francesco in Alba. Barnaba likely spent time in Pisa around 1380.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lochner, Stefan">
				<description>Englisch description: Stefan Lochner (the Dombild Master or Master Stefan) (c. 1410–1451) was a German painter working in the late "soft style" of the International Gothic. His paintings combine that era's tendency towards long flowing lines and brilliant colours with the realism, virtuoso surface textures and innovative iconography of the early Northern Renaissance. Based in Cologne, a commercial and artistic hub of northern Europe, Lochner was one of the most important German painters before Albrecht Dürer. Extant works include single panel oil paintings, devotional polyptychs and illuminated manuscripts, which often feature fanciful and dark blue winged angels. Today some thirty-seven individual panels are attributed to him with confidence. Less is known of his life. Art historians associating the Dombild Master with the historical Stefan Lochner believe he was born in Meersburg in south-west Germany around 1410, and that he spent some of his apprenticeship in the Low Countries. Records indicate that his career developed quickly but was cut short by an early death. We know that he was commissioned around 1442 by the Cologne council to provide decorations for the visit of Emperor Frederick III, a major city occasion. Records from the following years indicate growing wealth and the purchase of a number of properties around the city. Thereafter he seems to have over-extended his finances and fallen into debt. Plague hit Cologne in 1451 and there, apart from the records of creditors, mention of Stephan Lochner ends; it is presumed he died that year, aged around 40. Lochner's identity and reputation were lost until a revival of 15th century art during the early 19th century romantic period. Despite extensive historical research, attribution remains difficult; for centuries a number of associated works were grouped and loosely attributed to the notname the Dombild Master, a name taken from the Dombild Altarpiece (in English cathedral picture, also known as the Altarpiece of the City's Patron Saints) still in Cologne Cathedral. One of Dürer's diary entries became key, 400 years later, in the 20th century establishment of Lochner's identity. Only two attributed works are dated, and none are signed. His influence on successive generations of northern artists was substantial. Apart from the many direct copies made in the later 15th century, echoes of his panels can be seen in works by Rogier van der Weyden and Hans Memling. Lochner's work was praised by Friedrich Schlegel and Goethe for its qualities, especially the "sweetness and grace" of his Madonnas.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Catena, Vincenzo">
				<description>Englisch description: Vincenzo Catena (c. 1480–1531) was an Italian painter of the Renaissance Venetian school. He is also known as Vincenzo de Biagio.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jacopo del Casentino">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacopo del Casentino (c. 1297 – 1358) was an Italian painter, active mainly in Tuscany in the first half of the 14th century.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Perugino, Pietro">
				<description>Englisch description: Pietro Perugino (Italian: [ˈpjɛːtro peruˈdʒiːno]; c. 1446/1452 – 1523), born Pietro Vannucci, was an Italian Renaissance painter of the Umbrian school, who developed some of the qualities that found classic expression in the High Renaissance. Raphael was his most famous pupil.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der Stalburg-Bildnisse&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weyden, Rogier van der">
				<description>Englisch description: Rogier van der Weyden (Dutch: [roːˈɣiːr vɑn dɛr ˈʋɛi̯də(n)]) or Roger de la Pasture (1399 or 1400 – 18 June 1464) was an Early Netherlandish painter whose surviving works consist mainly of religious triptychs, altarpieces and commissioned single and diptych portraits. He was highly successful and internationally famous in his lifetime; his paintings were exported – or taken – to Italy and Spain, and he received commissions from, amongst others, Philip the Good, Netherlandish nobility and foreign princes. By the latter half of the 15th century, he had eclipsed Jan van Eyck in popularity. However his fame lasted only until the 17th century, and largely due to changing taste, he was almost totally forgotten by the mid-18th century. His reputation was slowly rebuilt during the following 200 years; today he is known, with Robert Campin and van Eyck, as the third (by birth date) of the three great Early Flemish artists ('Vlaamse Primitieven' or 'Flemish Primitives'), and widely as the most influential Northern painter of the 15th century. Karel van Mander wrote that the great artistic contribution of Rogier van der Weyden lies in his ideas, his composition and rendering of the soul's expression through pain, happiness or anger, and the tempering of this emotional testimony to the subject matter of his work. There are few certain facts of van der Weyden's life. What is known of him beyond this has been woven together from secondary sources, and some of it is contestable. However the paintings now attributed to him are generally accepted, despite a tendency in the 19th century to attribute his work to others. Van der Weyden worked from life models, and his observations were acute, yet he often idealised certain elements of his models' facial features, and they are typically statuesque, especially in his triptychs. All of his forms are rendered with rich, warm colourisation and a sympathetic expression, while he is known for his expressive pathos and naturalism. His portraits tend to be half length and half profile, and he is as sympathetic here as in his religious triptychs. Van der Weyden used an unusually broad range of colours and varied tones; in his finest work the same tone is not repeated in any other area of the canvas; even the whites are varied.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Achenbach, Andreas">
				<description>Englisch description: Andreas Achenbach (29 September 1815 – 1 April 1910) was a German landscape painter, associated with the Düsseldorf school of painting.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Netscher, Caspar">
				<description>Englisch description: Caspar (or Gaspar) Netscher (1639 – January 15, 1684) was a Dutch portrait and genre painter. He was a master in depicting oriental rugs, silk and brocade and introduced an international style to the Northern Netherlands.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dürer, Albrecht">
				<description>Englisch description: Albrecht Dürer (/ˈdʊərər, ˈdjʊərər/; German: [ˈalbʁɛçt ˈdyːʁɐ]; 21 May 1471 – 6 April 1528) was a painter, printmaker and theorist of the German Renaissance. Born in Nuremberg, Dürer established his reputation and influence across Europe when he was still in his twenties, due to his high-quality woodcut prints.He was in communication with the major Italian artists of his time, including Raphael, Giovanni Bellini and Leonardo da Vinci, and from 1512 he was patronized by emperor Maximilian I. His vast body of work includes engravings, his preferred technique in his later prints, altarpieces, portraits and self-portraits, watercolours and books. The woodcuts, such as the Apocalypse series (1498), retain a more Gothic flavour than the rest of his work. His well-known engravings include the Knight, Death, and the Devil (1513), Saint Jerome in his Study (1514) and Melencolia I (1514), which has been the subject of extensive analysis and interpretation. His watercolours also mark him as one of the first European landscape artists, while his ambitious woodcuts revolutionized the potential of that medium. Dürer's introduction of classical motifs into Northern art, through his knowledge of Italian artists and German humanists, has secured his reputation as one of the most important figures of the Northern Renaissance. This is reinforced by his theoretical treatises, which involve principles of mathematics, perspective and ideal proportions.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carracci">
				<description>Englisch description: The Carracci were a family of Italian artists. Notable members include:


Agostino Carracci (1557–1602), Italian painter and printmaker
Annibale Carracci (1560–1609), Italian Baroque painter and brother of Agostino Carracci
Ludovico Carracci (1555–1619), Italian painter, etcher, printmaker, and cousin of Agostino and Annibale Carracci
Antonio Marziale Carracci (1583–1618), Italian painter and son of Agostino Carracci
Francesco Carracci (1595–1622), Italian painter and engraver, nephew of Agostino Carracci
Baldassare Aloisi (1578–1638), painter and engraver whose mother, Elena Zenzanini, was a cousin of Agostino and Annibale Carracci
Giovanni Francesco Grimaldi (1606–1680), painter, whose common law wife was Aloisi's daughter</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Veronese, Paolo">
				<description>Englisch description: Paolo Caliari, known as Paolo Veronese (1528–1588), was an Italian Renaissance painter, based in Venice, known for large-format history paintings of religion and mythology, such as The Wedding at Cana(1563) and The Feast in the House of Levi (1573). Included with Titian, a generation older, and Tintoretto, a decade senior, Veronese of the “great trio that dominated Venetian painting of the cinquecento” and the Late Renaissance in the 16th century. Known as a supreme colorist, and after an early period with Mannerism, Paolo Veronese developed naturalist style of painting, influenced by Titian. His most famous works are elaborate narrative cycles, executed in a dramatic and colorful style, full of majestic architectural settings and glittering pageantry. His large paintings of biblical feasts, crowded with figures, painted for the refectories of monasteries in Venice and Verona are especially famous, and he was also the leading Venetian painter of ceilings. Most of these works remain in situ, or at least in Venice, and his representation in most museums is mainly composed of smaller works such as portraits that do not always show him at his best or most typical. He has always been appreciated for "the chromatic brilliance of his palette, the splendor and sensibility of his brushwork, the aristocratic elegance of his figures, and the magnificence of his spectacle", but his work has been felt "not to permit expression of the profound, the human, or the sublime", and of the "great trio" he has often been the least appreciated by modern criticism. Nonetheless, "many of the greatest artists ... may be counted among his admirers, including Rubens, Watteau, Tiepolo, Delacroix and Renoir".</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schadow, Wilhelm von">
				<description>Englisch description: Friedrich Wilhelm von Schadow (7 September 1789 – 19 March 1862) was a German Romantic painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lessing, Carl Friedrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Karl Friedrich Lessing (15 February 1808 – 4 January 1880) was a German historical and landscape painter, grandnephew of Gotthold Ephraim Lessing.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Becker, Jakob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jakob Becker (Dittelsheim at Worms, 15 March 1810, Frankfurt am Main, 22 December 1872) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schwind, Moritz von">
				<description>Englisch description: Moritz von Schwind (21 January 1804 – 8 February 1871) was an Austrian painter, born in Vienna. Schwind's genius was lyrical—he drew inspiration from chivalry, folklore, and the songs of the people. Schwind died in Pöcking in Bavaria, and was buried in the Alter Südfriedhof in Munich.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moretto da Brescia">
				<description>Englisch description: Alessandro Bonvicino (also Buonvicino) (c. 1498 – December 22, 1554), more commonly known as Moretto, or in Italian Il Moretto da Brescia, was an Italian Renaissance painter from Brescia, where he also mostly worked. His dated works extend from 1524 to 1554, but he was already described as a master in 1516. He was mainly a painter of altarpieces that tend towards sedateness, mostly for churches in and around Brescia, but also in Bergamo, Milan, Verona and Asola; many remain in the churches they were painted for. Most are on canvas, but a number even of large ones are on wood panel. Only a handful of drawings survive. He also painted a few portraits, but these are more influential. A full-length Portrait of a Man in the National Gallery, London, dated 1526, seems to be the earliest Italian independent portrait at full-length, all the more unexpected as the "sitter", though clearly a wealthy nobleman, shows no sign of being from a princely ruling family. This format, and the background of an exterior largely closed off by a column the man leans on, was taken up by his main assistant Giovanni Battista Moroni, who mainly painted portraits, and was one of the most important portraitists of the mid-16th century. He was a prominent and pious citizen of the small city of Brescia, belonging to at least two of the most prominent confraternities.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Franchoys II, Lucas">
				<description>Englisch description: Lucas Franchoys the Younger or  Lucas Franchoys II (alternative spellings of name: Lucas Franchois, Lucas François, Louis Franchoys) (28 June 1616 in Mechelen – 3 April 1681 in Mechelen) was a Flemish Baroque painter from Mechelen, who painted numerous altarpieces and portraits in a style reminiscent of Anthony van Dyck.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bol, Ferdinand">
				<description>Englisch description: Ferdinand Bol (24 June 1616 – 24 August 1680) was a Dutch artist, etcher, and draftsman. Although his surviving work is rare, it displays Rembrandt's influence; like his master, Bol favored historical subjects, portraits, numerous self-portraits, and single figures in exotic finery. The street Ferdinand Bolstraat in Amsterdam was named after Bol, just as the FEBO, which is a chain of Dutch walk-up restaurants.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Beham, Barthel">
				<description>Englisch description: Barthel Beham (or Bartel) (1502–1540) was a German engraver, miniaturist and painter. The younger brother of Hans Sebald Beham, he was born into a family of artists in Nuremberg. Learning his art from his elder brother, and Albrecht Dürer, he was particularly active as an engraver during the 1520s, creating tiny works of magnificent detail, positioning him in the German printmaking school known as the "Little Masters". He was also fascinated with antiquity and may have worked with Marcantonio Raimondi in Bologna and Rome at some time in his career. In 1525, along with his brother and Georg Pencz, the so-called "godless painters", he was banished from Lutheran Nuremberg for asserting his disbelief in baptism, Christ, or transubstantiation. Although later pardoned, he moved to Catholic Munich to work for the Bavarian dukes William IV and Ludwig X. Whilst there, his exceptional talent established him as one of Germany's principal portrait painters, favoured by distinguished patrons such as Emperor Charles V. According to Joachim von Sandrart, he died in Italy during a trip under the patronage of Duke William.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Christus, Petrus">
				<description>Englisch description: Petrus Christus (c. 1410/1420 – 1475/1476) was an Early Netherlandish painter active in Bruges from 1444, where, along with Hans Memling, he became the leading painter after the death of Jan van Eyck. He was influenced by van Eyck and Rogier van der Weyden and is noted for his innovations with linear perspective and a meticulous technique which seems derived from miniatures and manuscript illumination. Today, some 30 works are confidently attributed to him. The best-known include the 1446 Portrait of a Carthusian and c. 1470 Berlin Portrait of a Young Girl, both are highly innovative in presentation of the figure against detailed, rather than flat, backgrounds. Christus was an anonymous figure for centuries, his importance not established until the work of modern art historians. Giorgio Vasari barely mentions him in his biographies of painters, written in the Renaissance, and near contemporary records merely list him amongst many others. In the early to mid-nineteenth century, Gustav Waagen (who identified him in Francophile language as "Pierre Christophsen") and Johann David Passavant were important in establishing Christus's biographical details and in attributing works to him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rosso Fiorentino">
				<description>Englisch description: Giovanni Battista di Jacopo (8 March 1495 in Gregorian style, or 1494 according to the calculation of times in Florence where the year began on 25 March – 14 November 1540), known as Rosso Fiorentino (meaning "red Florentine" in Italian), or Il Rosso, was an Italian Mannerist painter, in oil and fresco, belonging to the Florentine school.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Garofalo">
				<description>Englisch description: Garofalo may refer to:
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Savery, Roelant">
				<description>Englisch description: Roelant Savery (or Roeland(t) Maertensz Saverij, or de Savery, or many variants) (1576 - buried 25 February 1639), was a Flanders-born Dutch Golden Age painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Neroccio di Bartolomeo di Benedetto de' Landi">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ramboux, Johann Anton">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Anton Alban Ramboux (5 October 1790, Trier - 2 October 1866, Cologne) was a German painter and lithographer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Olivier, Ferdinand">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Heinrich Ferdinand Olivier (1785–1841) was a German painter associated with the Nazarene movement.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Paolo di Giovanni Fei">
				<description>Englisch description: Paolo di Giovanni Fei (c. 1345 – c. 1411) was a painter of the Sienese school. He came to Siena from San Quirico, Castelvecchio, held public positions in Siena from 1369 and was first mentioned in the Sienese register of painters in 1389. His earliest signed and dated work is of 1381. He appears among the documents of the Duomo di Siena, 1395–1410, and is assumed to have died shortly thereafter.Paolo di Giovanni was influenced by the brothers Pietro Lorenzetti and Ambrogio Lorenzetti and by the Sienese masters Bartolo di Fredi and Simone Martini. His paintings are characterized by their bright clear palette often against a gilded and punched ground, and his wealth of naturalistic and ornamental detail. His artistic personality was first elucidated by Bernard Berenson.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Niccolò di Buonaccorso">
				<description>Englisch description: Very little is known about this painter. It is believed his father was the painter Buonaccorso di Pace (fl c. 1348–c. 1362). In 1355 Niccolò di Buonaccorso enrolled in the Guild of Sienese painters. In May and June 1372 and in March and April 1376 the artist served in the government of Siena. In 1381 he was elected honorary Gonfaloniere in the parish of San Martino. Niccolò di Buonaccorso was commissioned to paint the capello over the high altar of Siena Cathedral in 1376 and a panel of the prophet Daniel for an altar in the Cathedral in 1383.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tiepolo, Giovanni Domenico">
				<description>Englisch description: Giovanni Domenico Tiepolo (August 30, 1727 – March 3, 1804) was an Italian painter and printmaker in etching. He was the son of artist Giovanni Battista Tiepolo and elder brother of Lorenzo Baldissera Tiepolo.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brouwer, Adriaen">
				<description>Englisch description: Adriaen Brouwer (Oudenaarde, c. 1605 – Antwerp, January 1638) was a Flemish painter active in Flanders and the Dutch Republic in the first half of the 17th century. Brouwer was an important innovator of genre painting through his vivid depictions of peasants, soldiers and other 'lower class' individuals engaged in drinking, smoking, card or dice playing, fighting, music making etc. in taverns or rural settings. Brouwer contributed to the development of the genre of tronies, i.e. head or facial studies, which investigate varieties of expression. In his final year he produced a few landscapes of a tragic intensity. Brouwer's work had an important influence on the next generation of Flemish and Dutch genre painters.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heem, Jan Davidsz. de">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Davidsz. de Heem or in-full Jan Davidszoon de Heem, also called Johannes de Heem or Johannes van Antwerpen (c. 17 April 1606, Utrecht – before 26 April 1684, Antwerp), was a still life painter who was active in Utrecht and Antwerp. He is a major representative of that genre in both Dutch and Flemish Baroque painting.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Velázquez, Diego">
				<description>Englisch description: Diego Rodríguez de Silva y Velázquez (/vəˈlɑːskeɪs, -kəs/; also UK /vɪˈlæskwɪz/ and US /vəˈlɑːskɛs, -kwɛs/; Spanish: [ˈdjeɣo roˈðɾiɣeθ de ˈsilba i βeˈlaθkeθ]; baptized on June 6, 1599 – August 6, 1660) was a Spanish painter, the leading artist in the court of King Philip IV, and one of the most important painters of the Spanish Golden Age. He was an individualistic artist of the contemporary Baroque period, important as a portrait artist. In addition to numerous renditions of scenes of historical and cultural significance, he painted scores of portraits of the Spanish royal family, other notable European figures, and commoners, culminating in the production of his masterpiece Las Meninas (1656). From the first quarter of the nineteenth century, Velázquez's artwork was a model for the realist and impressionist painters, in particular Édouard Manet. Since that time, famous modern artists, including Pablo Picasso, Salvador Dalí and Francis Bacon, have paid tribute to Velázquez by recreating several of his most famous works.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berckheyde, Gerrit Adriaensz.">
				<description>Englisch description: Gerrit Adriaenszoon Berckheyde (1638 – 10 June 1698) was a Dutch Golden Age painter, active in Haarlem, Amsterdam, and The Hague, who is best known today for his cityscapes.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Borch d. J., Gerard ter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weenix, Jan Baptist">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Baptist Weenix (1621–1660?) was a painter of the Dutch Golden Age. Despite his relatively brief career, he was a very productive and versatile painter. His favourite subjects were Italian landscapes with large figures among ruins, seaside views, and, later in life, large still life pictures of dead game or dogs. He was mainly responsible for introducing the Italian harbour scene into Dutch art, in mid-size paintings with a group of figures in the foreground.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stevens, Pieter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Holbein d. J., Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Holbein the Younger (c. 1497 – between 7 October and 29 November 1543) was a German and Swiss artist and printmaker who worked in a Northern Renaissance style. He is best known as one of the greatest portraitists of the 16th century. He also produced religious art, satire and Reformation propaganda, and made a significant contribution to the history of book design. He is called "the Younger" to distinguish him from his father, Hans Holbein the Elder, an accomplished painter of the Late Gothic school. Born in Augsburg, Holbein worked mainly in Basel as a young artist. At first he painted murals and religious works and designed for stained glass windows and printed books. He also painted the occasional portrait, making his international mark with portraits of the humanist Desiderius Erasmus of Rotterdam. When the Reformation reached Basel, Holbein worked for reformist clients while continuing to serve traditional religious patrons. His Late Gothic style was enriched by artistic trends in Italy, France and the Netherlands, as well as by Renaissance humanism. The result was a combined aesthetic uniquely his own. Holbein travelled to England in 1526 in search of work, with a recommendation from Erasmus. He was welcomed into the humanist circle of Thomas More, where he quickly built a high reputation. After returning to Basel for four years, he resumed his career in England in 1532. This time he worked under the patronage of Anne Boleyn and Thomas Cromwell. By 1535, he was King's Painter to King Henry VIII. In this role, he produced not only portraits and festive decorations but designs for jewellery, plate and other precious objects. His portraits of the royal family and nobles are a record of the court in the years when Henry was asserting his supremacy over the English church. Holbein's art was prized from early in his career. The French poet and reformer Nicholas Bourbon dubbed him "the Apelles of our time," a typical contemporary accolade. Holbein has also been described as a great "one-off" of art history, since he founded no school. After his death, some of his work was lost, but much was collected, and by the 19th century, Holbein was recognised among the great portrait masters. Recent exhibitions have also highlighted his versatility. He turned his fluid line to designs ranging from intricate jewellery to monumental frescoes. Holbein's art has sometimes been called realist, since he drew and painted with a rare precision. His portraits were renowned in their time for their likeness; and it is through Holbein's eyes that many famous figures of his day, such as Erasmus and More, are now "seen". Holbein was never content, however, with outward appearance. He embedded layers of symbolism, allusion, and paradox in his art, to the lasting fascination of scholars. In the view of art historian Ellis Waterhouse, his portraiture "remains unsurpassed for sureness and economy of statement, penetration into character, and a combined richness and purity of style".</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cranach d. Ä., Lucas">
				<description>Englisch description: Lucas Cranach the Elder (Lucas Cranach der Ältere, c. 1472 – 16 October 1553) was a German Renaissance painter and printmaker in woodcut and engraving. He was court painter to the Electors of Saxony for most of his career, and is known for his portraits, both of German princes and those of the leaders of the Protestant Reformation, whose cause he embraced with enthusiasm, becoming a close friend of Martin Luther. He also painted religious subjects, first in the Catholic tradition, and later trying to find new ways of conveying Lutheran religious concerns in art. He continued throughout his career to paint nude subjects drawn from mythology and religion. He had a large workshop and many works exist in different versions; his son Lucas Cranach the Younger, and others, continued to create versions of his father's works for decades after his death. Lucas Cranach the Elder has been considered the most successful German artist of his time.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goyen, Jan van">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Josephszoon van Goyen (Dutch pronunciation: [ˈjɑn vɑŋ ˈɣoːjə(n)]; 13 January 1596 – 27 April 1656) was a Dutch landscape painter. Van Goyen was an extremely prolific artist; approximately twelve hundred paintings and more than one thousand drawings by him are known.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fiorenzo di Lorenzo">
				<description>Englisch description: Fiorenzo di Lorenzo (c. 1440 – 1522) was an Italian painter, of the Umbrian school. He lived and worked at Perugia, where most of his authentic works are still preserved in the Galleria Nazionale dell'Umbria. Fiorenzo is known from a few signed works, including the Madonna of the Recommended (1476) and a niche with lunette, two wings and predella (1487), as well as from the documentary evidence that he was decemvir of that city in 1472, in which year he entered into a contract to paint an altarpiece for the church of Santa Maria Nuova, the pentatych of the Madonna and Saints. Of his birth and death and pupilage nothing is known. Renaissance art biographer Giorgio Vasari does not even mention Fiorenzo's name, though he probably refers to him when he says that Cristofano, Perugino's father, sent his son to be the shop drudge of a painter in Perugia, who was not particularly distinguished in his calling, but held the art in great veneration and highly honoured the men who excelled therein. Certain it is that the early works both of Perugino and of Pinturicchio show certain mannerisms which point towards Fiorenzo's influence, if not to his direct teaching. The list of some fifty pictures which modern critics have ascribed to Fiorenzo includes works of such widely varied character that the scholars' suggestions of the masters under whom Fiorenzo is supposed to have studied varies. Pisanello, Verrocchio, Benozzo Gozzoli, Antonio Pollaiuolo, Benedetto Bonfigli, Andrea Mantegna, Francesco Squarcione, Filippo Lippi, Luca Signorelli and Domenico Ghirlandaio have all been mentioned. According to the 1911 edition of the Encyclopaedia Britannica: Fiorenzo's authentic works are remarkable for their sense of space and for the expression of that peculiar clear, soft atmosphere which is so marked a feature in the work of Perugino. But Fiorenzo has an intensity of feeling and a power of expressing character which are far removed from the somewhat affected grace of Perugino. Of the forty-five pictures bearing Fiorenzo's name in the Pinacoteca of Perugia, the eight charming St Bernardino panels are so different from his well-authenticated works, so Florentine in conception and movement, that the Perugian's authorship is very questionable.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dou, Gerrit">
				<description>Englisch description: Gerrit Dou (7 April 1613 – 9 February 1675), also known as Gerard and Douw or Dow, was a Dutch Golden Age painter, whose small, highly polished paintings are typical of the Leiden fijnschilders. He specialised in genre scenes and is noted for his trompe l'oeil "niche" paintings and candlelit night-scenes with strong chiaroscuro. He was a student of Rembrandt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="David, Gerard">
				<description>Englisch description: Gerard David (c. 1460 – 13 August 1523) was an Early Netherlandish painter and manuscript illuminator known for his brilliant use of color. Only a bare outline of his life survives, although some facts are known. He may have been the "Meester gheraet van brugghe" who became a master of the Antwerp guild in 1515. He was very successful in his lifetime and probably ran two workshops, in Antwerp and Bruges. His reputation diminished in the 17th century until he was rediscovered in the 19th century.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Richter, Ludwig">
				<description>Englisch description: Adrian Ludwig Richter (September 28, 1803 – June 19, 1884), a German painter and etcher, was born at Dresden, the son of the engraver Karl August Richter, from whom he received his training; but he was strongly influenced by Erhard and Chodowiecki. He was the most popular, and in many ways the most typical German illustrator of the middle of the 19th century. His work is as typically German and homely as are the fairy-tales of Grimm. Richter visited Italy from 1823–1826, and his Thunderstorm in the Sabine Mountains at the Staedel Museum in Frankfurt is one of the rare Italian subjects from his brush. In 1828 he worked as designer for the Meissen factory, and in 1841 he became professor and head of the landscape atelier at the Dresden Academy, (now Hochschule für Bildende Künste Dresden). The Dresden Gallery owns one of his best and most characteristic paintings: Bridal Procession in a Spring Landscape. An eye disease put a stop to the practice of his art in 1874; he was pensioned in 1877, and died at Loschwitz, near Dresden.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Reni, Guido">
				<description>Englisch description: Guido Reni (4 November 1575 – 18 August 1642) was an Italian painter of high-Baroque style.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Clouet, François">
				<description>Englisch description: François Clouet (c. 1510 – 22 December 1572), son of Jean Clouet, was a French Renaissance miniaturist and painter, particularly known for his detailed portraits of the French ruling family.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brueghel d. Ä., Jan">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Brueghel the Elder (/ˈbruːɡəl/; also Breughel /brɔɪɡəl/; Dutch: [ˈjɑn ˈbrøːɣəl]; 1568 – 13 January 1625) was a Flemish painter, son of Pieter Bruegel the Elder and father of Jan Brueghel the Younger. Nicknamed "Velvet" Brueghel, "Flower" Brueghel, and "Paradise" Brueghel, of which the latter two were derived from his floral still lifes and paradise landscapes, while the former may refer to the velveteen sheen of his colors.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Veit, Philipp">
				<description>Englisch description: Philipp Veit (13 February 1793 – 18 December 1877) was a German Romantic painter. To Veit is due the credit of having been the first to revive the almost forgotten technique of fresco painting. Veit was born in Berlin, Prussia. He was the son of a banker Simon Veit and his wife Dorothea, daughter of Moses Mendelssohn, who subsequently left him to marry Friedrich Schlegel. Veit received his first art education in Dresden, where he was taught by Caspar David Friedrich, and Vienna. Although a prodigious talent when it came to drawing, Veit was not comfortable with oil painting. Therefore, in Vienna he took to working with watercolor. In Vienna, he made the acquaintance of Schlegel, and through him came to know several Viennese Romantics, one of whom was the poet and novelist Joseph von Eichendorff. He was strongly influenced by, and joined, the Nazarene movement in Rome, where he worked for some years before moving to Frankfurt. Veit participated in the struggle against Napoleon in 1813-14, returning to Berlin for a short period. In 1815, he finished the Virgin with Christ and St John, a votive painting for the church of St James in Heiligenstadt, Vienna. The painting was inspired by the style of Pietro Perugino and Raphael. In Frankfurt, where his most important works are preserved at the Städel, he was active from 1830 to 1843 as director of the art collections and as professor of painting. From 1853 till his death in 1877 he held the post of director of the municipal gallery in Mainz. Like his fellow Nazarenes he was more draughtsman than painter, and though his sense of colour was stronger than that of Overbeck or Cornelius, his works are generally more of the nature of coloured cartoons than of paintings in the modern sense. Veit's principal work is the large fresco of The Introduction of Christianity into Germany by St Boniface, at the Städel. In the Frankfurt Cathedral is his Assumption, while the Alte Nationalgalerie of Berlin has his painting of The Two Marys at the Sepulchre. An example of his romantic work is Germania, a national personification of Germany, located in the Germanisches Nationalmuseum of Nuremberg. Veit died in Mainz.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tizian">
				<description>Englisch description: Tiziano Vecelli or Tiziano Vecellio (pronounced [titˈtsjaːno veˈtʃɛlljo]; c. 1488/1490 – 27 August 1576), known in English as Titian /ˈtɪʃən/, was an Italian painter, the most important member of the 16th-century Venetian school. He was born in Pieve di Cadore, near Belluno (in Veneto, Republic of Venice). During his lifetime he was often called da Cadore, taken from the place of his birth. Recognized by his contemporaries as "The Sun Amidst Small Stars" (recalling the famous final line of Dante's Paradiso), Titian was one of the most versatile of Italian painters, equally adept with portraits, landscape backgrounds, and mythological and religious subjects. His painting methods, particularly in the application and use of color, would exercise a profound influence not only on painters of the Italian Renaissance, but on future generations of Western art. During the course of his long life, Titian's artistic manner changed drastically, but he retained a lifelong interest in color. Although his mature works may not contain the vivid, luminous tints of his early pieces, their loose brushwork and subtlety of tone are without precedent in the history of Western painting.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kraus, Georg Melchior">
				<description>Englisch description: Georg Melchior Kraus (26 July 1737, in Frankfurt am Main – 5 November 1806, in Weimar) was a German painter. A student of Johann Heinrich Tischbein, he was also a teacher himself (his pupils included Ferdinand Jagemann), as well as an entrepreneur and friend of Goethe. He was a co-founder of the Fürstliche freie Zeichenschule Weimar with Friedrich Justin Bertuch in 1776.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bronzino, Agnolo">
				<description>Englisch description: Agnolo di Cosimo (Italian: [ˈaɲɲolo di ˈkɔːzimo]; November 17, 1503 – November 23, 1572), usually known as Bronzino ("Il Bronzino" [il bronˈdziːno] in Italian), or Agnolo Bronzino, was a Florentine Mannerist painter. His sobriquet, Bronzino, in all probability refers to his relatively dark skin. He lived all his life in Florence, and from his late 30s was kept busy as the court painter of Cosimo I de' Medici, Grand Duke of Tuscany. He was mainly a portraitist but also painted many religious subjects, and a few allegorical subjects, which include what is probably his best known work, Venus, Cupid, Folly, and Time, c. 1544–45, now in London. Many portraits of the Medicis exist in several versions with varying degrees of participation by Bronzino himself, as Cosimo was a pioneer of the copied portrait sent as a diplomatic gift. He trained with Pontormo, the leading Florentine painter of the first generation of Mannerism, and his style was greatly influenced by him, but his elegant and somewhat elongated figures always appear calm and somewhat reserved, lacking the agitation and emotion of those by his teacher. They have often been found cold and artificial, and his reputation suffered from the general critical disfavour attached to Mannerism in the 19th and early 20th centuries. Recent decades have been more appreciative of his art.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fries, Ernst">
				<description>Englisch description: Ernst Fries (22 June 1801 – 11 October 1833) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vermeer, Johannes">
				<description>Englisch description: Johannes, Jan or Johan Vermeer (/vərˈmɪər/; Dutch: [joːˈɦɑnəs jɑn vərˈmeːr]; 1632 – December 1675) was a Dutch painter who specialized in domestic interior scenes of middle-class life. Vermeer was a moderately successful provincial genre painter in his lifetime. He evidently was not wealthy, leaving his wife and children in debt at his death, perhaps because he produced relatively few paintings. Vermeer worked slowly and with great care, and frequently used very expensive pigments. He is particularly renowned for his masterly treatment and use of light in his work. Vermeer painted mostly domestic interior scenes. "Almost all his paintings are apparently set in two smallish rooms in his house in Delft; they show the same furniture and decorations in various arrangements and they often portray the same people, mostly women." He was recognized during his lifetime in Delft and The Hague, but his modest celebrity gave way to obscurity after his death. He was barely mentioned in Arnold Houbraken's major source book on 17th-century Dutch painting (Grand Theatre of Dutch Painters and Women Artists), and was thus omitted from subsequent surveys of Dutch art for nearly two centuries.In the 19th century, Vermeer was rediscovered by Gustav Friedrich Waagen and Théophile Thoré-Bürger, who published an essay attributing 66 pictures to him, although only 34 paintings are universally attributed to him today. Since that time, Vermeer's reputation has grown, and he is now acknowledged as one of the greatest painters of the Dutch Golden Age.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Feuerbach, Anselm">
				<description>Englisch description: Anselm Feuerbach (12 September 1829 – 4 January 1880) was a German painter. He was the leading classicist painter of the German 19th-century school.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morgenstern, Carl">
				<description>German description: Carl Morgenstern (* 25. Oktober 1811 in Frankfurt am Main; † 10. Januar 1893 ebenda) war ein deutscher Landschaftsmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Burnham-Meister&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Florentiner Meister um 1480">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baldung Grien, Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Baldung Grien or Grün (c. 1484 – September 1545) was a German artist in painting and printmaking who was considered the most gifted student of Albrecht Dürer. Throughout his lifetime, Baldung developed a distinctive style, full of color, expression and imagination. His talents were varied, and he produced a great and extensive variety of work including portraits, woodcuts, altarpieces, drawings, tapestries, allegories and mythological motifs.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deger, Ernst">
				<description>Englisch description: Ernst Deger (15 April 1809 in Bockenem – 27 January 1885 in Düsseldorf) was a 19th-century German religious artist. He is associated with the Düsseldorf school of painting. In 1869 he became a professor in the Kunstakademie Düsseldorf (Düsseldorf Academy of Fine Arts).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Zick, Januarius">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Rasso Januarius Zick (6 February 1730 – 14 November 1797) was a German painter and architect. He is considered to be one of the main masters of the Late-Baroque.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nattier, Jean-Marc">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Marc Nattier (17 March 1685 – 7 November 1766), French painter, was born in Paris, the second son of Marc Nattier (1642–1705), a portrait painter, and of Marie Courtois (1655–1703), a miniaturist. He is noted for his portraits of the ladies of King Louis XV's court in classical mythological attire.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Willebeeck, Peter">
				<description>Englisch description: Peter Willebeeck or Petrus Willebeeck (fl. 1632–1648) was a Flemish still life painter who was active in Antwerp in the second quarter of the 17th century. He is known for his fruit still lifes, vanitas still lifes, pronkstillevens and banquet pieces executed in a very delicate manner.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brueghel d. J., Jan">
				<description>German description: Jan Brueghel der Jüngere [ˈbɾøːɣəl] (* 13. September 1601 in Antwerpen; † 1. September 1678 ebenda) war ein flämischer Landschafts-, Blumen- und Tiermaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Teniers d. J., David">
				<description>German description: David Teniers (getauft 15. Dezember 1610 in Antwerpen; † 25. April 1690 in Brüssel) war ein flämischer Maler, Zeichner und Kurator. Er war ein äußerst vielseitiger Künstler, der für seine umfangreich Produktion bekannt ist. Er war ein Erneuerer
in einer Vielzahl von Genres wie Historienmalerei, Genremalerei, Landschaft, Porträt und Stillleben. Er ist heute am meisten erinnert als der führende flämische Genremaler seiner Zeit. Teniers ist besonders bekannt für die Entwicklung des Bauerngenres, der Schenkstubenszene, Bilder von Kunstsammlungen und Szenen mit Alchimisten und Ärzten.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mieris d. Ä., Frans van">
				<description>Englisch description: Frans van Mieris, the elder (16 April 1635 – 12 March 1681), was a Dutch Golden Age genre and portrait painter. The leading member of a Leiden family of painters, his sons Jan (1660–1690) and Willem (1662–1747) and his grandson Frans van Mieris the Younger (1689–1763) were also accomplished genre painters.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Müller, Victor">
				<description>Englisch description: Victor Müller (born Frankfurt am Main, 29 March 1829; died Munich, 21 December 1871) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Böcklin, Arnold">
				<description>Englisch description: Arnold Böcklin (16 October 1827 – 16 January 1901) was a Swiss symbolist painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Badalocchio, Sisto">
				<description>Englisch description: Sisto Badalocchio Rosa (28 June 1585 – c. 1647) was an Italian painter and engraver of the Bolognese School. Born in Parma, he worked first under Agostino Carracci in Bologna, then Annibale Carracci, in Rome. He worked with Annibale till 1609, then moved back to Parma. His best known work as an engraver was the Raphael's Bible series, which he created together with his fellow student, Giovanni Lanfranco. The images depict a series of frescoes by Raphael's workshop in the Vatican loggia. As a painter, his most important work is the frescoes the church of San Giovanni Evangelista, Reggio Emilia, which are based on Caravaggio's earlier works. He executed the decoration of the cupula and pendentives of the church of San Giovanni Evangelista in Reggio. Though he often cooperated in fresco painting with Lanfranco, for example in Annibale-designed series the San Diego Chapel in San Giacomo degli Spagnoli (1602–1607) and in Palazzo Costaguti (Nessus and Deianeira), Badalocchio never received the same recognition as his peer. Nevertheless, he is recognized today as an important figure in bringing the artistic styles of the Italian Baroque to northern Italy.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Loeding, Harmen">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sassoferrato, Giovanni Battista Salvi gen.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Unterberger, Ignaz">
				<description>Englisch description: Ignaz Unterberger was an Italian and Austrian artist as a painter and printmaker, who was also a keen inventor. He was a member of a large dynasty of Tyrolian artists. Unterberger was probably born on 24 July 1748 in Cavalese, located in the County of Tyrol, today in Italy. His initial artistic instruction came from his uncle Franz Sebald Unterberger (1706-1776). Unterberger Senior taught his nephew the style of the Tyrol. This was High Baroque - famed for intricate church altarpieces, sculpture and frescoes. Artists working in Vienna and Salzburg found themselves training in Rome, including Ignaz's elder brother. Christoph Unterberger (1732-1798)'s influence as a member of the Accademia di San Luca provided Ignaz with access to a pivotal group of Italian artists when he arrived in Rome in 1769. His ability to capture the Italian style was such that his painting 'Maternal Love' was thought to have been Correggio's. Unterberger was a highly capable artist, with experience in creating frescoes, altarpiece paintings, bambocciata and marble work. The artist stated that he only painted for a livelihood, but printmaking was his real passion. Unterberger's printmaking is not particularly well-known, although some of his prints were included in the British Museum's 1994 exhibition and catalogue 'Printmaking in the Age of Goethe'. He did not engage in printmaking until he returned to Vienna from Rome in 1773, when he applied himself exclusively to the mezzotint. His inventions included an excavating machine for digging canals, a foot-pedal for the harp, and a machine for preparing mezzotint plates. Unterberger was never made a member of the Academy in Vienna, despite exhibiting there. Nevertheless his work was highly regarded, and the Imperial Chancellor Wenzel Anton, Prince of Kaunitz-Rietberg was a patron. His painting Hebe (1795) was a sensation for its lighting effects, and bought by Emperor Francis II for a large amount. He was also made a Royal and Imperial Court Painter. Unfortunately, he only benefited from this role for two years before heart failure lead to his death on 4 December 1797, leaving a widow and nine children.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Flämischer Meister um 1600">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Coninxloo, Gillis van">
				<description>Englisch description: Gillis van Coninxloo (now also referred to as Gillis van Coninxloo II but previously referred to as Gillis van Coninxloo III) (24 January 1544 – January 1607) was a Flemish painter of landscapes who played an important role in the development of Northern landscape art at the turn of the 17th century. He spent the last 20 years of his life abroad, first in Germany and later in the Dutch Republic.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Romney, George">
				<description>Englisch description: George Romney may refer to:

George Romney (painter) (1734–1802), English portrait painter
George S. Romney (1874–1935), president of the college now known as Brigham Young University-Idaho
George W. Romney (1907–1995), businessman, Governor of Michigan, U.S. presidential candidate, Secretary of Housing &amp;amp; Urban Development, Mitt Romney's father
G. Scott Romney (born 1941), Michigan lawyer and politician, son of George W. Romney and brother of Mitt Romney
G. Ott Romney (1892–1973), American football player, coach and college athletics administrator</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Leibl, Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Wilhelm Maria Hubertus Leibl (October 23, 1844 – December 4, 1900) was a German realist painter of portraits and scenes of peasant life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sisley, Alfred">
				<description>Englisch description: Alfred Sisley (/ˈsɪsli/; French: [sislɛ]; 30 October 1839 – 29 January 1899) was an Impressionist landscape painter who was born and spent most of his life in France, but retained British citizenship. He was the most consistent of the Impressionists in his dedication to painting landscape en plein air (i.e., outdoors). He deviated into figure painting only rarely and, unlike Renoir and Pissarro, found that Impressionism fulfilled his artistic needs. Among his important works are a series of paintings of the River Thames, mostly around Hampton Court, executed in 1874, and landscapes depicting places in or near Moret-sur-Loing. The notable paintings of the Seine and its bridges in the former suburbs of Paris are like many of his landscapes, characterized by tranquillity, in pale shades of green, pink, purple, dusty blue and cream. Over the years Sisley's power of expression and color intensity increased.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Liebermann, Max">
				<description>Englisch description: Max Liebermann (20 July 1847 – 8 February 1935) was a German-Jewish painter and printmaker, and one of the leading proponents of Impressionism in Germany.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Spitzweg, Carl">
				<description>Englisch description: Carl Spitzweg (February 5, 1808 – September 23, 1885) was a German romanticist painter, especially of genre subjects. He is considered to be one of the most important artists of the Biedermeier era.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pidoll, Karl von">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Chintreuil, Antoine">
				<description>Englisch description: Antoine Chintreuil (May 15, 1814 – August 8, 1873) was a French landscape painter. He was born in Pont-de-Vaux, Ain and grew up in Bresse. In 1838 he moved to Paris, where he began studying under Paul Delaroche in 1842. The following year he met Corot, who influenced him profoundly by encouraging him to paint landscape en plein air. Art historian Athena S. E. Leoussi suggests that Chintreuil's work can be divided into three periods: From c. 1846–1850 he painted Paris and its surroundings, particularly Montmartre; from 1850–1857 he lived in Igny and frequently painted in Barbizon, and from 1857 on he lived and worked in La Tournelle-Septeuil in the Seine valley. During this final period his work reached its fullest development, and he achieved critical recognition. In the breadth and simplicity of his execution, and in his attention to capturing light and atmosphere, Chintreuil can be placed alongside Eugène Boudin, Johan Barthold Jongkind, and the painters of the Barbizon school, as an important forerunner of Impressionism. He died in Septeuil, Seine-et-Oise in 1873.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Robert, Hubert">
				<description>Englisch description: Hubert Robert (22 May 1733 – 15 April 1808) was a French painter, noted for his landscape paintings and capriccio, or semi-fictitious picturesque depictions of ruins.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meyerheim, Paul">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Aertsen, Pieter">
				<description>Englisch description: Pieter Aertsen (Amsterdam, 1508 – 3 June 1575), called Lange Pier ("Tall Pete") because of his height, was a Dutch painter in the style of Northern Mannerism, who invented the monumental genre scene combining still life and genre painting, and very often also including a biblical scene in the background. He was born and died in Amsterdam, in his lifetime a relatively minor city, and painted there but mainly in Antwerp, then the centre of artistic life in the Netherlands. His genre scenes were influential on later Flemish Baroque painting, and also in Italy, and his peasant scenes preceded by a few years the much better-known paintings produced in Antwerp by Pieter Bruegel the Elder.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Monet, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Oscar-Claude Monet (/moʊˈneɪ/; French: [klod mɔnɛ]; 14 November 1840 – 5 December 1926) was a founder of French Impressionist painting, and the most consistent and prolific practitioner of the movement's philosophy of expressing one's perceptions before nature, especially as applied to plein-air landscape painting. The term "Impressionism" is derived from the title of his painting Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which was exhibited in 1874 in the first of the independent exhibitions mounted by Monet and his associates as an alternative to the Salon de Paris. Monet's ambition of documenting the French countryside led him to adopt a method of painting the same scene many times in order to capture the changing of light and the passing of the seasons. From 1883 Monet lived in Giverny, where he purchased a house and property, and began a vast landscaping project which included lily ponds that would become the subjects of his best-known works. In 1899 he began painting the water lilies, first in vertical views with a Japanese bridge as a central feature, and later in the series of large-scale paintings that was to occupy him continuously for the next 20 years of his life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Waldmüller, Ferdinand Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: (15 January 1793 in Vienna – 23 August 1865 in Hinterbrühl, Austria) was an Austrian painter and writer. Waldmüller was one of the most important Austrian painters of the  Biedermeier period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Blanche, Jacques-Émile">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacques-Émile Blanche (French: [blɑ̃ʃ]; 1 January 1861 – 20 September 1942) was a French artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Courbet, Gustave">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean Désiré Gustave Courbet (French: [ɡystav kuʁbɛ]; 10 June 1819 – 31 December 1877) was a French painter who led the Realist movement in 19th-century French painting. Committed to painting only what he could see, he rejected academic convention and the Romanticism of the previous generation of visual artists. His independence set an example that was important to later artists, such as the Impressionists and the Cubists. Courbet occupies an important place in 19th-century French painting as an innovator and as an artist willing to make bold social statements through his work. Courbet's paintings of the late 1840s and early 1850s brought him his first recognition. They challenged convention by depicting unidealized peasants and workers, often on a grand scale traditionally reserved for paintings of religious or historical subjects. Courbet's subsequent paintings were mostly of a less overtly political character: landscapes, seascapes, hunting scenes, nudes and still lifes. He was imprisoned for six months in 1871 for his involvement with the Paris Commune, and lived in exile in Switzerland from 1873 until his death. I am fifty years old and I have always lived in freedom; let me end my life free; when I am dead let this be said of me: 'He belonged to no school, to no church, to no institution, to no academy, least of all to any régime except the régime of liberty.'</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Millet, Jean François">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-François Millet (French: [milɛ]; October 4, 1814 – January 20, 1875) was a French painter and one of the founders of the Barbizon school in rural France. Millet is noted for his scenes of peasant farmers; he can be categorized as part of the Realism art movement.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Palma il Vecchio, Jacopo">
				<description>Englisch description: Palma il Vecchio (c. 1480 – July 1528), born Jacopo Palma and also known as Jacopo Negretti, was an Italian painter of the Venetian school born at Serina Alta near Bergamo. He is called Palma Vecchio in English ("Old Palma" in Italian Palma il Vecchio) to distinguish him from Palma Giovane, his great-nephew. When Palma arrived in Venice early in the 16th century, he reputedly was a companion and competitor of Lorenzo Lotto, and to some extent a pupil of Titian. He may also have taught Bonifazio Pitati and influenced Giovanni Busi. Palma's earlier works betray the influence of Giovanni Bellini. Palma's work demonstrates superior richness of color, but he did not excel with regard to invention nor vigorous draughtsmanship. His paintings frequently feature his (so-called) daughter Violante, of whom Titian was said to be enamoured. Famous works by Palma include a composition of six paintings in the Venetian church of Santa Maria Formosa, with St Barbara in the centre, under the dead Christ, and to right and left SS. Dominic, Sebastian, John Baptist and Anthony. A second work is in the Dresden Gallery, representing three sisters seated in the open air; it is frequently named The Three Graces. A third work, discovered in Venice in 1900, is a portrait supposed to represent Violante. Other leading examples are: the Last Supper in the National Gallery for Foreign Art; a Madonna, in the church of Santo Stefano in Vicenza; the Epiphany, (Brera Gallery, Milan); the Holy Family with a young shepherd (Louvre, Paris), The Holy Family with St. Catherine, St. John and Donor  and Self Portrait (Beli Dvor, Belgrade ), St Stephen and other Saints, Christ and the Widow of Nain and the Assumption of the Virgin, (Gallerie dell'Accademia, Venice), Lady with a Lute (Alnwick Castle, England) and Christ at Emmaus (Pitti Palace).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Göbel, Angilbert">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gogh, Vincent van">
				<description>Englisch description: ("Van Gogh" redirects here. For other uses, see Van Gogh (disambiguation).) Vincent Willem van Gogh (Dutch: [ˈvɪnsɛnt ˈʋɪləm vɑn ˈɣɔx] ; 30 March 1853 – 29 July 1890) was a Dutch Post-Impressionist painter who is among the most famous and influential figures in the history of Western art. In just over a decade he created about 2100 artworks, including around 860 oil paintings, most of them in the last two years of his life. They include landscapes, still lifes, portraits and self-portraits, and are characterised by bold, symbolic colours, and dramatic, impulsive and highly expressive brushwork that contributed to the foundations of modern art. He sold only one painting during his lifetime and became famous after his suicide at age 37, which followed years of poverty and mental illness. Born into an upper-middle-class family, Van Gogh drew as a child and was serious, quiet and thoughtful, but showed signs of mental instability. As a young man he worked as an art dealer, often travelling, but became depressed after he was transferred to London. He turned to religion, and spent time as a missionary in southern Belgium. Later he drifted in ill health and solitude. He was keenly aware of modernist trends in art and, while back with his parents, took up painting in 1881. His younger brother, Theo, supported him financially, and the two kept up a long correspondence by letter. Van Gogh's early works, mostly still lifes and depictions of peasant labourers, contain few signs of the vivid colour that distinguished his later work. In 1886 he moved to Paris and became interested in the French Impressionists. As his work developed he created a new approach to still lifes and local landscapes. His paintings grew brighter in colour as he developed a style that became fully realised during his stay in Arles in the south of France in 1888. He lived there in the Yellow House and, with the French artist Paul Gauguin, developed a concept of colour that symbolised inner emotion. During this period he broadened his subject matter to include olive trees, cypresses, wheat fields and sunflowers. Van Gogh suffered from psychotic episodes and delusions and, though he worried about his mental stability, he often neglected his physical health, not eating properly and drinking heavily. His friendship with Gauguin came to an end after he threatened the Frenchman with a razor, and in a rage, cut off part of his own left ear. While in a psychiatric hospital in Saint-Rémy his condition stabilised, leading to one of the more productive periods of his life. He moved to the Auberge Ravoux in Auvers-sur-Oise near Paris under the care of the homeopathic doctor and artist, Paul Gachet. On 27 July 1890, Van Gogh shot himself in the chest with a revolver. He died from his injuries two days later. Considered a madman and a failure in his lifetime, Van Gogh exists in the public imagination as the quintessential misunderstood genius, the artist "where discourses on madness and creativity converge". His reputation began to grow in the early 20th century as elements of his painting style came to be incorporated by the Fauves and German Expressionists. He attained widespread critical, commercial and popular success over the ensuing decades, and is remembered as an important but tragic painter, whose troubled personality typifies the romantic ideal of the tortured artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Daubigny, Charles François">
				<description>Englisch description: Charles-François Daubigny (15 February 1817 – 19 February 1878) was one of the painters of the Barbizon school, and is considered an important precursor of Impressionism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Capella gen. Il Daggiù, Francesco">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Delacroix, Eugène">
				<description>Englisch description: Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix (French: [ø.ʒɛn də.la.kʁwa]; 26 April 1798 – 13 August 1863) was a French Romantic artist regarded from the outset of his career as the leader of the French Romantic school. As a painter and muralist, Delacroix's use of expressive brushstrokes and his study of the optical effects of colour profoundly shaped the work of the Impressionists, while his passion for the exotic inspired the artists of the Symbolist movement. A fine lithographer, Delacroix illustrated various works of William Shakespeare, the Scottish author Walter Scott and the German author Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. In contrast to the Neoclassical perfectionism of his chief rival Ingres, Delacroix took for his inspiration the art of Rubens and painters of the Venetian Renaissance, with an attendant emphasis on colour and movement rather than clarity of outline and carefully modelled form. Dramatic and romantic content characterized the central themes of his maturity, and led him not to the classical models of Greek and Roman art, but to travel in North Africa, in search of the exotic. Friend and spiritual heir to Théodore Géricault, Delacroix was also inspired by Lord Byron, with whom he shared a strong identification with the "forces of the sublime", of nature in often violent action. However, Delacroix was given to neither sentimentality nor bombast, and his Romanticism was that of an individualist. In the words of Baudelaire, "Delacroix was passionately in love with passion, but coldly determined to express passion as clearly as possible."</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Manet, Édouard">
				<description>Englisch description: Édouard Manet (US /mæˈneɪ/ or UK /ˈmæneɪ/; French: [edwaʁ manɛ]; 23 January 1832 – 30 April 1883) was a French painter. He was one of the first 19th-century artists to paint modern life, and a pivotal figure in the transition from Realism to Impressionism. Born into an upper-class household with strong political connections, Manet rejected the future originally envisioned for him, and became engrossed in the world of painting. His early masterworks, The Luncheon on the Grass (Le déjeuner sur l'herbe) and Olympia, both 1863, caused great controversy and served as rallying points for the young painters who would create Impressionism. Today, these are considered watershed paintings that mark the genesis of modern art. The last 20 years of Manet's life saw him form bonds with other great artists of the time, and develop his own style that would be heralded as innovative and serve as a major influence for future painters.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Parmigianino">
				<description>Englisch description: Girolamo Francesco Maria Mazzola (also known as Francesco Mazzola or, more commonly, as Parmigianino (Italian pronunciation: [parmidʒanˈiːno], "the little one from Parma"); 11 January 1503 – 24 August 1540) was an Italian Mannerist painter and printmaker active in Florence, Rome, Bologna, and his native city of Parma. His work is characterized by a "refined sensuality" and often elongation of forms and includes Vision of Saint Jerome (1527) and the iconic if somewhat untypical Madonna with the Long Neck (1534), and he remains the best known artist of the first generation whose whole careers fall into the Mannerist period. His prodigious and individual talent has always been recognised, but his career was disrupted by war, especially the Sack of Rome in 1527, three years after he moved there, and then ended by his death at only 37. He produced outstanding drawings, and was one of the first Italian painters to experiment with printmaking himself. While his portable works have always been keenly collected and are now in major museums in Italy and around the world, his two large projects in fresco are in a church in Parma and a palace in a small town nearby. This in conjunction with their lack of large main subjects has resulted in their being less well known than other works by similar artists. He painted a number of important portraits, leading a trend in Italy towards the three-quarters or full-length figure, previously mostly reserved for royalty.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Corot, Camille">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Baptiste-Camille Corot (French: [ʒɑ̃ ba.tist ka.mij kɔ.ʁo]; July 16, 1796 – February 22, 1875) was a French landscape and portrait painter as well as a printmaker in etching. He is a pivotal figure in landscape painting and his vast output simultaneously references the Neo-Classical tradition and anticipates the plein-air innovations of Impressionism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Longhi, Pietro">
				<description>Englisch description: Pietro Longhi (1702 or November 5, 1701 – May 8, 1785) was a Venetian painter of contemporary genre scenes of life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lanfranco, Giovanni">
				<description>Englisch description: Giovanni Lanfranco (26 January 1582 – 30 November 1647) was an Italian painter of the Baroque period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tintoretto">
				<description>Englisch description: Tintoretto (Italian pronunciation: [tintoˈretto]; born Jacopo Comin, late September or early October, 1518 – May 31, 1594) was an Italian painter and a notable exponent of the Renaissance school. For his phenomenal energy in painting he was termed Il Furioso. His work is characterized by its muscular figures, dramatic gestures, and bold use of perspective in the Mannerist style, while maintaining color and light typical of the Venetian School. In his youth, Tintoretto was also known as Jacopo Robusti as his father had defended the gates of Padua in a way that others called robust, against the imperial troops during the War of the League of Cambrai (1509–1516). His real name "Comin" has only recently been discovered by Miguel Falomir, the curator of the Museo del Prado, Madrid, and was made public on the occasion of the retrospective of Tintoretto at the Prado in 2007. Comin translates to the spice cumin in the local language.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Crespi gen. Il Cerano, Giovanni Battista">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Venezianischer Meister des 18. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Italienischer Meister um 1600/1610">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hackert, Jakob Philipp">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob Philipp Hackert (15 September 1737 – 28 April 1807) was a landscape painter from Brandenburg, who did most of his work in Italy.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Doré, Gustave">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Gustave Louis Christophe Doré (/dɔːˈreɪ/; French: [ɡys.tav dɔ.ʁe]; 6 January 1832 – 23 January 1883) was a French artist, printmaker, illustrator and sculptor. Doré worked primarily with wood engraving.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Segantini, Giovanni">
				<description>Englisch description: Giovanni Segantini (15 January 1858 – 28 September 1899) was an Italian painter known for his large pastoral landscapes of the Alps. He was one of the most famous artists in Europe in the late 19th century, and his paintings were collected by major museums. In later life he combined a Divisionist painting style with Symbolist images of nature. He was active in Switzerland for most of his life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bosch, Hieronymus">
				<description>Englisch description: Hieronymus Bosch (/ˌhaɪ.əˈrɒnᵻməs ˈbɒʃ/; Dutch: [ɦijeːˈroːnimɵz ˈbɔs]; born Jheronimus van Aken [jeːˈroːnimɵs fɑn ˈaːkə(n)]; c. 1450 – 9 August 1516) was an Early Netherlandish painter. His work is known for its fantastic imagery, detailed landscapes, and illustrations of religious concepts and narratives. Within his lifetime his work was collected in the Netherlands, Austria, and Spain, and widely copied, especially his macabre and nightmarish depictions of hell. Little is known of Bosch's life, though there are some records. He spent most of it in the town of 's-Hertogenbosch, where he was born in his grandfather's house. The roots of his forefathers are in Nijmegen and Aachen (which is visible in his surname: Van Aken). His pessimistic and fantastical style cast a wide influence on northern art of the 16th century, with Pieter Bruegel the Elder being his best known follower. His paintings have been difficult to translate from a modern point of view; attempts to associate instances of modern sexual imagery with fringe sects or the occult have largely failed. Today he is seen as a hugely individualistic painter with deep insight into humanity's desires and deepest fears. Attribution has been especially difficult; today only about 25 paintings are confidently given to his hand along with 8 drawings. Approximately another half dozen paintings are confidently attributed to his workshop. His most acclaimed works consist of a few triptych altarpieces, the most outstanding of which is The Garden of Earthly Delights.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bloemaert, Abraham">
				<description>Englisch description: Abraham Bloemaert (1566 – 27 January 1651) was a Dutch painter and printmaker in etching and engraving. He was one of the "Haarlem Mannerists" from about 1585, but in the new century altered his style to fit new Baroque trends. He mostly painted history subjects and some landscapes. He was an important teacher, who trained most of the Utrecht Caravaggisti, at least for a period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Elsheimer, Adam">
				<description>Englisch description: Adam Elsheimer (18 March 1578 – 11 December 1610) was a German artist working in Rome who died at only thirty-two, but was very influential in the early 17th century in the field of Baroque paintings. His relatively few paintings were small scale, nearly all painted on copper plates, of the type often known as cabinet paintings. They include a variety of light effects, and an innovative treatment of landscape. He was an influence on many other artists, including Rembrandt and Peter Paul Rubens.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Juncker, Justus">
				<description>German description: Justus Juncker (* 24. Juli 1703 in Mainz; † 15. Juni 1767 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Genre- und Blumenmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Giordano, Luca">
				<description>Englisch description: Luca Giordano (18 October 1634 – 12 January 1705) was an Italian late Baroque painter and printmaker in etching. Fluent and decorative, he worked successfully in Naples and Rome, Florence and Venice, before spending a decade in Spain.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hoppner, John">
				<description>Englisch description: John Hoppner RA (4 April 1758 – 23 January 1810) was an English portrait painter, much influenced by Reynolds who achieved fame as a brilliant colourist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Steinle, Edward von">
				<description>German description: Edward Jakob von Steinle (auch Eduard von Steinle; * 2. Juli 1810 in Wien; † 19. September 1886 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein österreichischer Maler des 19. Jahrhunderts.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Singleton, Henry">
				<description>Englisch description: Henry Singleton may refer to:

Henry Singleton (judge) (1682–1759), Irish judge
Henry Singleton (painter) (1766–1839), English painter
Henry Earl Singleton (1916–1999), American industrialist</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guigou, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Camille Guigou (15 February 1834 – 21 December 1871) was a French landscape painter. Guigou was born in Villars, Vaucluse in a wealthy family of farmers and notaries. He studied painting in Apt and later with Émile Loubon in Marseille. In 1851, he became clerk at Apt and in 1854 at Marseille where he also moved. Guigou painted mostly Provence landscapes using oil and watercolour. At his beginnings, he was influenced by Loubon, later by Barbizon school and Gustave Courbet. During his lifetime, he was not recognised and met with indifference of both jury and public exhibitions. Struggling with financial problems, he had to give painting lessons and write reviews. He died in Paris at the age of 37 from stroke. After his death, he and his works were mostly forgotten. Revival of interest in him began early in the 20th century at exhibitions in Paris and Marseille. Currently his works are highly valued at auctions.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guardi, Giacomo">
				<description>Englisch description: Giacomo Guardi (13 April 1764 – 3 November 1835) was an Italian painter from Venice. The son of famous veduta painter Francesco Guardi, he continued his father's line of work, though without the same level of renown. The majority of his works are quite small views of only minor artistic interest, more akin to postcards than to his father's grand scenes, but he produced several paintings showcasing a notable level of artistic skill as well. Evaluating his legacy is somewhat complicated due to the frequency with which paintings are misattributed to him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morland, George">
				<description>Englisch description: George Morland (26 June 1763 in London – 29 October 1804 in Brighton) was an English painter of animals and rustic scenes.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Urlaub, Georg Karl">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ziesenis, Johann Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Georg Ziesenis (1716, Copenhagen - 4 March 1776, Hannover) was a German - Danish portrait painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Faber von Kreuznach, Conrad">
				<description>Englisch description: Conrad Faber von Kreuznach (c. 1500 in Kreuznach, Germany – between 10 September 1552 and 15 May 1553 in Frankfurt am Main) was a German painter and woodcuts designer formerly known as Master of Holzhausen-portraits.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Uffenbach, Philipp">
				<description>Englisch description: Philipp Uffenbach (15 January 1566 – 6 April 1636) was a German painter and etcher. He was born in Frankfurt, and trained under Hans Grimmer. One of his pupils was Adam Elsheimer. 1598 Philipp Uffenbach obtained the citizenship of Frankfurt, after he had married and had taken over the painter’s workshop of his father in law 1592. Only a view oft the artistic works of and his paintings and engravings are preserved, e.g. so z.B. oil painting "Adoration oft he Magi" (1587). His chief work is "Ascension of Jesus" of 1599, which he painted for the Dominican-Church in Frankfurt on Main. Conserved fragments can be found in the Historical Museum of the City of Frankfurt. It is known that he worked on behalf oft he council of the city, e.g. he represented the Brückenfreiheit at the tower of Old Bridge of Frankfurt on Main (1610), he colored the figure "Justitia" for the "Fountain of Justicia" on "Römerberg". 1887 this figure had been replaced by a sculpture in bronze. For Landgrave Philipp III. (Hessen-Butzbach) of Hessen-Butzbach he made the ceiling fresco for the "Landgrafschloss" (landgrave's castle). Beside that Uffenbach was interested in mechanic, geometry alchemy, anatomy. He wrote 1898 the booklet Zeitweiser (time pointer) containing a printed diptych sundial. On the horizontal part of this sundial he presented the oldest gnomonic world map known so far. He also was interested in the problem of squaring the circle and published the book with the title De quadratura circuli mechanici.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kaldenbach, Martin">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gentile da Fabriano">
				<description>Englisch description: Gentile da Fabriano (c. 1370 – 1427) was an Italian painter known for his participation in the International Gothic painter style. He worked in various places in central Italy, mostly in Tuscany. His best-known works are his Adoration of the Magi from the Strozzi Altarpiece, (1423) and the Flight into Egypt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Troger, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Troger (30 October 1698 – 20 July 1762) was an Austrian painter, draughtsman and printmaker of the late Baroque period. Troger's illusionistic ceiling paintings in fresco are notable for their dramatic vitality of movement and their palette of light colors. Paul Troger’s style, particularly in his frescoes, dominated Austrian painting until the end of the 18th century and profoundly influenced significant artists of the next generation, notably Franz Anton Maulbertsch, Josef Ignaz Mildorfer, Johann Wenzel Bergl and Johann Lucas Kracker.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Nürnberger Marienaltars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fränkisch-Schwäbischer Meister um 1440/50">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Khnopff, Fernand">
				<description>Englisch description: Fernand Edmond Jean Marie Khnopff (12 September 1858 – 12 November 1921) was a Belgian symbolist painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klinger, Max">
				<description>Englisch description: Max Klinger (18 February 1857 – 5 July 1920) was a German symbolist painter, sculptor, printmaker, and writer. Klinger was born in Leipzig and studied in Karlsruhe. An admirer of the etchings of Menzel and Goya, he shortly became a skilled and imaginative engraver in his own right. He began creating sculptures in the early 1880s. From 1883–1893 he lived in Rome, and became increasingly influenced by the Italian Renaissance and antiquity.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Evenepoel, Henri">
				<description>Englisch description: Henri-Jacques-Edouard Evenepoel (3 October 1872 in Nice – 27 December 1899 in Paris) was a Belgian artist whose most important works are associated with Fauvism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lenbach, Franz von">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz von Lenbach (13 December 1836 – 6 May 1904) was a German painter of Realist style. He travelled to Italy and Spain and completed many notable portraits.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Friedrich, Caspar David">
				<description>Englisch description: Caspar David Friedrich (5 September 1774 – 7 May 1840) was a 19th-century German Romantic landscape painter, generally considered the most important German artist of his generation. He is best known for his mid-period allegorical landscapes which typically feature contemplative figures silhouetted against night skies, morning mists, barren trees or Gothic ruins. His primary interest as an artist was the contemplation of nature, and his often symbolic and anti-classical work seeks to convey a subjective, emotional response to the natural world. Friedrich's paintings characteristically set a human presence in diminished perspective amid expansive landscapes, reducing the figures to a scale that, according to the art historian Christopher John Murray, directs "the viewer's gaze towards their metaphysical dimension". Friedrich was born in the Pomeranian town of Greifswald at the Baltic Sea, where he began his studies in art as a young man. He studied in Copenhagen until 1798, before settling in Dresden. He came of age during a period when, across Europe, a growing disillusionment with materialistic society was giving rise to a new appreciation of spirituality. This shift in ideals was often expressed through a reevaluation of the natural world, as artists such as Friedrich, J. M. W. Turner (1775–1851) and John Constable (1776–1837) sought to depict nature as a "divine creation, to be set against the artifice of human civilization". Friedrich's work brought him renown early in his career, and contemporaries such as the French sculptor David d'Angers (1788–1856) spoke of him as a man who had discovered "the tragedy of landscape". Nevertheless, his work fell from favour during his later years, and he died in obscurity, and in the words of the art historian Philip B. Miller, "half mad". As Germany moved towards modernisation in the late 19th century, a new sense of urgency characterised its art, and Friedrich's contemplative depictions of stillness came to be seen as the products of a bygone age. The early 20th century brought a renewed appreciation of his work, beginning in 1906 with an exhibition of thirty-two of his paintings and sculptures in Berlin. By the 1920s his paintings had been discovered by the Expressionists, and in the 1930s and early 1940s Surrealists and Existentialists frequently drew ideas from his work. The rise of Nazism in the early 1930s again saw a resurgence in Friedrich's popularity, but this was followed by a sharp decline as his paintings were, by association with the Nazi movement, interpreted as having a nationalistic aspect. It was not until the late 1970s that Friedrich regained his reputation as an icon of the German Romantic movement and a painter of international importance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dahl, Johan Christian Clausen">
				<description>Englisch description: Johan Christian Claussen Dahl (24 February 1788 – 14 October 1857), often known as J. C. Dahl or I. C. Dahl, was a Norwegian artist who is considered the first great romantic painter in Norway, the founder of the "golden age" of Norwegian painting, and one of the greatest European artists of all time. He is often described as "the father of Norwegian landscape painting" and is regarded as the first Norwegian Painter ever to reach a level of artistic accomplishment comparable to that attained by the greatest European artists of his day. He was also the first acquire genuine fame and cultural renown abroad. As one critic has put it, "J.C. Dahl occupies a central position in Norwegian artistic life of the first half of the 19th century. Although Dahl spent much of his life outside of Norway, his love for his country is clear in the motifs he chose for his paintings and in his extraordinary efforts on behalf of Norwegian culture generally. Indeed, if one sets aside his own monumental artistic creations, his other activities on behalf of art, history, and culture would still have guaranteed him a place at the very heart of the artistic and cultural history of Norway. He was, for example, a key figure in the founding of the Norwegian National Gallery and of several other major art institutions in Norway, as well as in the preservation of Norwegian stave churches and the restoration of the Nidaros Cathedral in Trondheim and Håkonshallen in Bergen.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jawlensky, Alexej von">
				<description>Englisch description: Alexej Georgewitsch von Jawlensky (13 March 1864 – 15 March 1941) was a Russian expressionist painter active in Germany. He was a key member of the New Munich Artist's Association (Neue Künstlervereinigung München), Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider) group and later the Die Blaue Vier (The Blue Four).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pseudo-Félix Chrétien">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Burnitz, Karl Peter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deodato Orlandi">
				<description>Englisch description: Deodato Orlandi (active 1284-1315, died before 1331) was an Italian painter of Medieval art. Orlandi was active in Lucca and Pisa between 1284 and 1315. He primarily painted religious-themed works on commissions for churches. Some of his works show a Byzantine art style, and an influence of Giotto can also be seen. He painted frescos for the San Piero a Grado church which was commissioned by the Caetani family for the 1300 jubilee. In the lower part are Portraits of Popes, from St. Peter to John XVIII (1303); the intermediate portion has thirty panels with Histories of St. Peter's Life (as well of those of St. Paul, Constantine and St. Sylvester), similar to those in the Old St. Peter's Basilica and to Cimabue's work at San Francesco in Assisi. In the upper area are portrayed the Walls of the Heaven City, largely restored in the following centuries. A St John Evangelist Mourning attributed to Deodato is displayed in the Städel Gallery in Frankfurt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mayr, Johann Ulrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Ulrich Mayr (1629, Augsburg – 1704, Augsburg), was a German Baroque painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Thoma, Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Thoma (October 2, 1839 – November 7, 1924) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Macke, August">
				<description>Englisch description: August Macke (3 January 1887 – 26 September 1914) was one of the leading members of the German Expressionist group Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider). He lived during a particularly innovative time for German art: he saw the development of the main German Expressionist movements as well as the arrival of the successive avant-garde movements which were forming in the rest of Europe. Like a true artist of his time, Macke knew how to integrate into his painting the elements of the avant-garde which most interested him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fantin-Latour, Henri">
				<description>Englisch description: Henri Fantin-Latour (14 January 1836 – 25 August 1904) was a French painter and lithographer best known for his flower paintings and group portraits of Parisian artists and writers.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Murillo, Bartolomé Esteban">
				<description>Englisch description: Bartolomé Esteban Murillo (born late December 1617, baptized January 1, 1618 – April 3, 1682) was a Spanish Baroque painter. Although he is best known for his religious works, Murillo also produced a considerable number of paintings of contemporary women and children. These lively, realist portraits of flower girls, street urchins, and beggars constitute an extensive and appealing record of the everyday life of his times.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Flegel, Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: Georg Flegel (1566 Olomouc – 23 March 1638, Frankfurt-am-Main) was a German painter, best known for his still life works.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Michau, Theobald">
				<description>Englisch description: Théobald Michau (1676–1765) was a conservative Flemish painter of landscapes, more famous in his own time than he is today. Michau was born in Tournai and was a pupil of Lucas Achtschellinck. Subjects of the country festivals (Kermesse) that were popularized by David Teniers, father and son to the extent that paintings and tapestries showing such rustic themes were called Ténières. Michau painted designs and perhaps provided full-scale cartoons for tapestry weavers, for surviving records of the Brussels tapestry workshop of Pieter van der Borcht record Teniers peints par le fameux Sr Michau, such Teniers-like subjects painted by "the famous Sieur Michau". Among his work, on wooden or copper panels, in public collections are the Summer and Winter landscapes in Vienna. Michau died in Antwerp. Among his pupils was Martin J. Geeraerts, who specialized in painted bas-reliefs en camaïeu.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meister aus dem Umkreis Friedrich Herlins">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Corinth, Lovis">
				<description>Englisch description: Lovis Corinth (21 July 1858 – 17 July 1925) was a German artist and writer whose mature work as a painter and printmaker realized a synthesis of impressionism and expressionism. Corinth studied in Paris and Munich, joined the Berlin Secession group, later succeeding Max Liebermann as the group's president. His early work was naturalistic in approach. Corinth was initially antagonistic towards the expressionist movement, but after a stroke in 1911 his style loosened and took on many expressionistic qualities. His use of color became more vibrant, and he created portraits and landscapes of extraordinary vitality and power. Corinth's subject matter also included nudes and biblical scenes.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig">
				<description>Englisch description: Ernst Ludwig Kirchner (6 May 1880 – 15 June 1938) was a German expressionist painter and printmaker and one of the founders of the artists group Die Brücke or "The Bridge", a key group leading to the foundation of Expressionism in 20th-century art. He volunteered for army service in the First World War, but soon suffered a breakdown and was discharged. In 1933, his work was branded as "degenerate" by the Nazis and in 1937, over 600 of his works were sold or destroyed. In 1938, he committed suicide by gunshot.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ammon, Hans">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der Madonna von Covarrubias&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Marc, Franz">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz Marc (February 8, 1880 – March 4, 1916) was a German painter and printmaker, one of the key figures of the German Expressionist movement. He was a founding member of Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider), a journal whose name later became synonymous with the circle of artists collaborating in it.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kern, Anton">
				<description>German description: Anton Kern ist der Name folgender Personen:

Anton Kern (Maler) (1710–1747), deutscher Maler
Anton Kern (Bibliothekar) (1883–1956), österreichischer Bibliothekswissenschafter
Anton Kern (Politiker) (* 1951), deutscher Politiker (CSU), MdL Bayern</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kalf, Willem">
				<description>Englisch description: Willem Kalf (1619 – 31 July 1693)was a Dutch Golden Age painter who specialized in still lifes. Later in his life, Kalf became an art dealer and appraiser.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klee, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Klee (German: [paʊ̯l ˈkleː]; 18 December 1879 – 29 June 1940) was a Swiss-German artist. His highly individual style was influenced by movements in art that included Expressionism, Cubism, and Surrealism. Klee was a natural draftsman who experimented with and eventually deeply explored color theory, writing about it extensively; his lectures Writings on Form and Design Theory (Schriften zur Form und Gestaltungslehre), published in English as the Paul Klee Notebooks, are held to be as important for modern art as Leonardo da Vinci's A Treatise on Painting for the Renaissance. He and his colleague, Russian painter Wassily Kandinsky, both taught at the Bauhaus school of art, design and architecture. His works reflect his dry humor and his sometimes childlike perspective, his personal moods and beliefs, and his musicality.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Chardin, Jean-Baptiste Siméon">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Baptiste-Siméon Chardin (French: [ʃaʁdɛ̃]; 2 November 1699 – 6 December 1779) was an 18th-century French painter. He is considered a master of still life, and is also noted for his genre paintings which depict kitchen maids, children, and domestic activities. Carefully balanced composition, soft diffusion of light, and granular impasto characterize his work.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bril, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Bril (1554 – 7 October 1626) was a Flemish painter and printmaker principally known for his landscapes. He spent most of his active career in Rome. His Italianate landscapes had a major influence on landscape painting in Italy and Northern Europe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cipper gen. Il Todeschini, Giacomo Francesco">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Modersohn-Becker, Paula">
				<description>Englisch description: Paula Modersohn-Becker (February 8, 1876 – November 21, 1907) was a German painter and one of the most important representatives of early expressionism. In a brief career, cut short by an embolism at the age of 31, she created a number of groundbreaking images of great intensity. She is becoming recognized as the first female painter to paint female nudes. Using bold forays into subject matter and chromatic color choices, she and fellow-artists Picasso and Matisse introduced the world to modernism at the start of the twentieth century.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bock d. Ä., Hans">
				<description>German description: Hans Bock der Ältere (* um 1550 in Zabern; † 16. März 1624 in Basel) war ein Maler, Zeichner, Restaurator und Geometer.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baburen, Dirck van">
				<description>Englisch description: Dirck Jaspersz. van Baburen (c. 1595 – 21 February 1624) was a Dutch painter and one of the Utrecht Caravaggisti.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der von Grooteschen Anbetung&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Katz, Hanns Ludwig">
				<description>German description: Hanns Ludwig Katz (geboren 24. Juli 1892 in Karlsruhe; gestorben 17. November 1940 in Johannesburg) war ein deutscher expressionistischer Maler und Grafiker jüdischer Abstammung.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Umbrischer Meister um 1500">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goes, Hugo van der">
				<description>Englisch description: Hugo van der Goes (probably Ghent c. 1430/1440 – Auderghem 1482) was a Flemish painter. He was, along with Jan van Eyck, Rogier van der Weyden, Hans Memling and Dieric Bouts, one of the most important Flemish painters of the late 15th century. He introduced important innovations such as a new monumentalism, a specific colour spectrum and an individualistic manner of portraiture. The presence of his masterpiece, the Portinari Triptych in Florence, from the late 15th century onwards played a role in the development of realism in Italian Renaissance art.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brügger (?) Meister um 1485/90">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Macrino d'Alba">
				<description>Englisch description: Macrino d'Alba (c. 1460–1465 – c. 1510–1520) was an Italian painter of the Renaissance period, active mainly in Piedmont, who is known for his altarpieces and portraits. His birth name was Gian Giacomo de' Alladio.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lorenzetti, Pietro">
				<description>Englisch description: Pietro Lorenzetti (or Pietro Laurati; c. 1280 – 1348) was an Italian painter, active between c.1306 and 1345. Together with his younger brother Ambrogio, he introduced naturalism into Sienese art. In their artistry and experiments with three-dimensional and spatial arrangements, the brothers foreshadowed the art of the Renaissance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lawrence, Thomas">
				<description>Englisch description: Sir Thomas Lawrence PRA FRS (13 April 1769 – 7 January 1830) was a leading English portrait painter and the fourth president of the Royal Academy. Lawrence was a child prodigy. He was born in Bristol and began drawing in Devizes, where his father was an innkeeper. At the age of ten, having moved to Bath, he was supporting his family with his pastel portraits. At eighteen he went to London and soon established his reputation as a portrait painter in oils, receiving his first royal commission, a portrait of Queen Charlotte, in 1790. He stayed at the top of his profession until his death, aged 60, in 1830. Self-taught, he was a brilliant draughtsman and known for his gift of capturing a likeness, as well as his virtuoso handling of paint. He became an associate of the Royal Academy in 1791, a full member in 1794, and president in 1820. In 1810 he acquired the generous patronage of the Prince Regent, was sent abroad to paint portraits of allied leaders for the Waterloo chamber at Windsor Castle, and is particularly remembered as the Romantic portraitist of the Regency. Lawrence's love affairs were not happy (his tortuous relationships with Sally and Maria Siddons became the subject of several books) and, in spite of his success, he spent most of life deep in debt. He never married. At his death, Lawrence was the most fashionable portrait painter in Europe. His reputation waned during Victorian times, but has since been partially restored.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1420">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Holbein d. Ä., Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Holbein the Elder (c. 1460 – 1524) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nithart gen. Grünewald, Mathis Gothart">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1450/60">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pforr, Franz">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz Pforr (5 April 1788 – 16 June 1812) was a painter of the German Nazarene movement.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Oberrheinischer Meister um 1410/20">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Munch, Edvard">
				<description>Englisch description: Edvard Munch (/mʊŋk/; Norwegian: [ˈɛdvɑʈ muŋk]  ; 12 December 1863 – 23 January 1944) was a Norwegian painter and printmaker whose intensely evocative treatment of psychological themes built upon some of the main tenets of late 19th-century Symbolism and greatly influenced German Expressionism in the early 20th century. One of his most well-known works is The Scream of 1893.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schlemmer, Oskar">
				<description>Englisch description: Oskar Schlemmer (4 September 1888 – 13 April 1943) was a German painter, sculptor, designer and choreographer associated with the Bauhaus school. In 1923 he was hired as Master of Form at the Bauhaus theatre workshop, after working some time at the workshop of sculpture. His most famous work is "Triadisches Ballett," in which the actors are transfigured from the normal to geometrical shapes. Also in Slat Dance and Treppenwitz, the performers' costumes make them into living sculpture, as if part of the scenery.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berchem, Nicolaes">
				<description>Englisch description: Nicolaes Pieterszoon Berchem (1 October 1620 – 18 February 1683) was a highly esteemed and prolific Dutch Golden Age painter of pastoral landscapes, populated with mythological or biblical figures, but also of a number of allegories and genre pieces. He was a member of the second generation of "Dutch Italianate landscape" painters. These were artists who travelled to Italy, or aspired to, in order to soak up the romanticism of the country, bringing home sketchbooks full of drawings of classical ruins and pastoral imagery.His paintings, of which he produced an immense number, (Hofstede de Groot claimed around 850, although many are misattributed), were in great demand, as were his 80 etchings and 500 drawings. His landscapes, painted in the Italian style of idealized rural scenes, with hills, mountains, cliffs and trees in a golden dawn are sought after. Berchem also painted inspired and attractive human and animal figures (staffage) in works of other artists, like Allaert van Everdingen, Jan Hackaert, Gerrit Dou, Meindert Hobbema and Willem Schellinks.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Blechen, Carl">
				<description>Englisch description: Carl Eduard Ferdinand Blechen (29 July 1798, Cottbus - 23 July 1840, Berlin) was a German landscape painter and a Professor at the Academy of Arts, Berlin. His distinctive style was characteristic of the Romantic ideals of natural beauty.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Trübner, Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Wilhelm Trübner (February 3, 1851 – December 21, 1917) was a German realist painter of the circle of Wilhelm Leibl.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Keller, Albert von">
				<description>Englisch description: Albert von Keller (27 April 1844 – 14 July 1920) was a German historical and genre painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stuck, Franz von">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz Stuck (February 23, 1863 – August 30, 1928) was a German painter, sculptor, engraver, and architect. In 1906, Stuck was awarded the Verdienstorden der Bayerischen Krone and was henceforth known as Franz Ritter von Stuck.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Degas, Edgar">
				<description>Englisch description: Edgar Degas (US /deɪˈɡɑː/ or UK /ˈdeɪɡɑː/; born Hilaire-Germain-Edgar De Gas, French: [ilɛːʁ ʒɛʁmɛ̃ ɛdɡaʁ də ɡɑ]; 19 July 1834 – 27 September 1917) was a French artist famous for his paintings, sculptures, prints, and drawings. He is especially identified with the subject of dance; more than half of his works depict dancers. He is regarded as one of the founders of Impressionism, although he rejected the term, preferring to be called a realist. He was a superb draftsman, and particularly masterly in depicting movement, as can be seen in his rendition of dancers, racecourse subjects and female nudes. His portraits are notable for their psychological complexity and for their portrayal of human isolation. At the beginning of his career, Degas wanted to be a history painter, a calling for which he was well prepared by his rigorous academic training and close study of classic art. In his early thirties, he changed course, and by bringing the traditional methods of a history painter to bear on contemporary subject matter, he became a classical painter of modern life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brütt, Ferdinand">
				<description>Englisch description: Ferdinand Martin Cordt Brütt (13 July 1849, Hamburg - 6 November 1936, Bergen) was a German painter. He was a distant relative of the sculptor Adolf Brütt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cranach d. J., Lucas">
				<description>German description: Lucas Cranach der Jüngere (* 4. Oktober 1515 in Wittenberg; † 25. Januar 1586 ebenda) war ein bedeutender Maler und Porträtist der Renaissance. Er ist Sohn von Lucas Cranach dem Älteren.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rheinischer Meister um 1330">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bandell, Eugenie">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sérusier, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Sérusier (9 November 1864 – 7 October 1927) was a French painter who was a pioneer of abstract art and an inspiration for the avant-garde Nabis movement, Synthetism and Cloisonnism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rousseau, Henri">
				<description>Englisch description: Henri Julien Félix Rousseau (French: [ɑ̃ʁi ʒyljɛ̃ feliks ʁuso]; May 21, 1844 – September 2, 1910) was a French post-impressionist painter in the Naïve or Primitive manner. He was also known as Le Douanier (the customs officer), a humorous description of his occupation as a toll collector. Ridiculed during his lifetime by critics, he came to be recognized as a self-taught genius whose works are of high artistic quality. Rousseau's work exerted an extensive influence on several generations of avant-garde artists.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Roederstein, Ottilie W.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nürnberger Meister um 1350/60">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Stötteritzer Altars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Bartholomäusaltars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Codde, Pieter Jacobsz">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Uhde, Fritz von">
				<description>Englisch description: Fritz von Uhde (born Friedrich Hermann Carl Uhde; May 22, 1848 – February 25, 1911) was a German painter of genre and religious subjects. His style laying between Realism and Impressionism, he was once known as "Germany's outstanding impressionist" and he became one of the first painters who introduced en plein air art in his country.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Trautmann, Johann Georg">
				<description>German description: Johann Georg Trautmann ist der Name folgender Personen:

Johann Georg Trautmann (Maler) (1713–1769), deutscher Maler und Grafiker
Johann Georg Trautmann (Kaufmann) (1805–1888), deutscher Kaufmann und Politiker</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1400">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Altheim, Wilhelm">
				<description>German description: Wilhelm Altheim (* 2. August 1871 in Groß-Gerau; † 25. Dezember 1914  in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler und Radierer des 19. und 20. Jahrhunderts in Hessen.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Redon, Odilon">
				<description>Englisch description: Odilon Redon (born Bertrand-Jean Redon; French: [ʁədɔ̃]; April 20, 1840 – July 6, 1916) was a French symbolist painter, printmaker, draughtsman and pastellist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hodler, Ferdinand">
				<description>Englisch description: Ferdinand Hodler (March 14, 1853 – May 19, 1918) was one of the best-known Swiss painters of the nineteenth century.His early works were portraits, landscapes, and genre paintings in a realistic style. Later, he adopted a personal form of symbolism he called Parallelism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kollwitz, Käthe">
				<description>Englisch description: Käthe (Schmidt) Kollwitz (German pronunciation: [kɛːtə kɔlvɪt͡s]), (8 July 1867 – 22 April 1945) was a German artist, who worked with drawing, etching, lithography, woodcuts, painting, printmaking, and sculpture. Her most famous art cycles, including The Weavers and The Peasant War, depict the effects of poverty, hunger, and war on the working class. Despite the realism of her early works, her art is now more closely associated with Expressionism. Kollwitz was the first woman elected to the Prussian Academy of Arts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Freundlich, Otto">
				<description>Englisch description: Otto Freundlich (10 July 1878 – 9 March 1943) was a German painter and sculptor of Jewish origin and one of the first generation of abstract artists.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kolbe, Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: Georg Kolbe (15 April 1877 – 20 November 1947) was the leading German figure sculptor of his generation, in a vigorous, modern, simplified classical style similar to Aristide Maillol of France.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rodin, Auguste">
				<description>Englisch description: François Auguste René Rodin (12 November 1840 – 17 November 1917), known as Auguste Rodin (/oʊˈɡuːst roʊˈdæn/; French: [oɡyst ʁɔdɛ̃]), was a French sculptor. Although Rodin is generally considered the progenitor of modern sculpture, he did not set out to rebel against the past. He was schooled traditionally, took a craftsman-like approach to his work, and desired academic recognition, although he was never accepted into Paris's foremost school of art. Sculpturally, Rodin possessed a unique ability to model a complex, turbulent, deeply pocketed surface in clay. Many of his most notable sculptures were roundly criticized during his lifetime. They clashed with predominant figurative sculpture traditions, in which works were decorative, formulaic, or highly thematic. Rodin's most original work departed from traditional themes of mythology and allegory, modeled the human body with realism, and celebrated individual character and physicality. Rodin was sensitive to the controversy surrounding his work, but refused to change his style. Successive works brought increasing favor from the government and the artistic community. From the unexpected realism of his first major figure – inspired by his 1875 trip to Italy – to the unconventional memorials whose commissions he later sought, Rodin's reputation grew, such that he became the preeminent French sculptor of his time. By 1900, he was a world-renowned artist. Wealthy private clients sought Rodin's work after his World's Fair exhibit, and he kept company with a variety of high-profile intellectuals and artists. He married his lifelong companion, Rose Beuret, in the last year of both their lives. His sculptures suffered a decline in popularity after his death in 1917, but within a few decades, his legacy solidified. Rodin remains one of the few sculptors widely known outside the visual arts community.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meunier, Constantin">
				<description>Englisch description: Constantin Meunier (12 April 1831, Brussels – 4 April 1905, Ixelles) was a Belgian painter and sculptor. He made an important contribution to the development of modern art by elevating the image of the industrial worker, docker and miner to an icon of modernity. His work is a reflection of the industrial, social and political developments of his day and represents a compassionate and committed view of man and the world.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carstens, Asmus Jakob">
				<description>Englisch description: Asmus Jacob Carstens (or "Jakob", May 10, 1754 – May 25, 1798) was a Danish-German painter, one of the most committed artists of German Neoclassicism. His career was erratic, partly because of his difficult personality, and the majority of his large projects were left incomplete, or subsequently destroyed. Much of what survives is in the form of drawings, many using "a schematic, pale colouring as a timid and humble accessory to the dominating figure-drawing", that were planned for large fresco commissions that never materialized.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rossetti, Antonio">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Daumier, Honoré">
				<description>Englisch description: Honoré-Victorin Daumier (French: [ɔnɔʁe domje]; February 26, 1808 – February 10, 1879) was a French printmaker, caricaturist, painter, and sculptor, whose many works offer commentary on social and political life in France in the 19th century. Daumier produced over 500 paintings, 4000 lithographs, 1000 wood engravings, 1000 drawings and 100 sculptures. A prolific draughtsman, he was perhaps best known for his caricatures of political figures and satires on the behavior of his countrymen, although posthumously the value of his painting has also been recognized.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rembrandt Harmensz. van Rijn">
				<description>Englisch description: Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn (/ˈrɛmbrænt, -brɑːnt/; Dutch: [ˈrɛmbrɑnt ˈɦɑrmə(n)soːn vɑn ˈrɛin] ; 15 July 1606 – 4 October 1669) was a Dutch painter and etcher. He is generally considered one of the greatest painters and printmakers in European art and the most important in Dutch history. His contributions to art came in a period of great wealth and cultural achievement that historians call the Dutch Golden Age when Dutch Golden Age painting, although in many ways antithetical to the Baroque style that dominated Europe, was extremely prolific and innovative, and gave rise to important new genres in painting. Having achieved youthful success as a portrait painter, Rembrandt's later years were marked by personal tragedy and financial hardships. Yet his etchings and paintings were popular throughout his lifetime, his reputation as an artist remained high, and for twenty years he taught many important Dutch painters. Rembrandt's greatest creative triumphs are exemplified most notably in his portraits of his contemporaries, self-portraits and illustrations of scenes from the Bible. His self-portraits form a unique and intimate biography, in which the artist surveyed himself without vanity and with the utmost sincerity. In his paintings and prints he exhibited knowledge of classical iconography, which he molded to fit the requirements of his own experience; thus, the depiction of a biblical scene was informed by Rembrandt's knowledge of the specific text, his assimilation of classical composition, and his observations of Amsterdam's Jewish population. Because of his empathy for the human condition, he has been called "one of the great prophets of civilization."</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nürnberger Meister um 1410/20">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bergmüller, Johann Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Georg Bergmüller (15 April 1688 – 2 April 1762) was a painter, particularly of frescoes, of the Baroque.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Correggio">
				<description>Englisch description: Antonio Allegri da Correggio (August 1489 – March 5, 1534), usually known as Correggio (Italian: [korˈreddʒo]), was the foremost painter of the Parma school of the Italian Renaissance, who was responsible for some of the most vigorous and sensuous works of the 16th century. In his use of dynamic composition, illusionistic perspective and dramatic foreshortening, Correggio prefigured the Rococo art of the 18th century. He is considered a master of chiaroscuro.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Romano, Giulio">
				<description>Englisch description: Giulio Romano, also known as Giulio Pippi, (c. 1499 – 1 November 1546) was an Italian painter and architect. A pupil of Raphael, his stylistic deviations from high Renaissance classicism help define the 16th-century style known as Mannerism. Giulio's drawings have long been treasured by collectors; contemporary prints of them engraved by Marcantonio Raimondi were a significant contribution to the spread of 16th-century Italian style throughout Europe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Palma il Giovane, Jacopo">
				<description>Englisch description: Iacopo Negretti (1548/50 – 14 October 1628), best known as Jacopo or Giacomo Palma il Giovane or simply Palma Giovane ("Young Palma"), was an Italian Mannerist painter from Venice. After Tintoretto's death (1594), Palma became Venice's dominant artist perpetuating his style. Outside Venice, he received numerous commissions in the area of Bergamo, then part of the Venetian Domini di Terraferma, and in Central Europe, most prominently from the connoisseur emperor Rudolph II in Prague.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bandinelli, Baccio">
				<description>Englisch description: Bartolommeo (or Baccio) Bandinelli, actually Bartolommeo Brandini (17 October 1493 – shortly before 7 February 1560), was a Renaissance Italian sculptor, draughtsman and painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vasari, Giorgio">
				<description>Englisch description: Giorgio Vasari (Italian: [ˈdʒordʒo vaˈzaːri]; 30 July 1511 – 27 June 1574) was an Italian painter, architect, writer, and historian, most famous today for his Lives of the Most Excellent Painters, Sculptors, and Architects, considered the ideological foundation of art-historical writing.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mellan, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Claude Mellan (23 May 1598 – 9 September 1688) was a French draughtsman, engraver, and painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lorrain, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Claude Lorrain (French: [klod lɔ.ʁɛ̃]; born Claude Gellée [ʒəle], called le Lorrain in French; traditionally just Claude in English; c. 1600 – 23 November 1682) was a French painter, draughtsman and engraver of the Baroque era. He spent most of his life in Italy, and is one of the earliest important artists, apart from his contemporaries in Dutch Golden Age painting, to concentrate on landscape painting. His landscapes are usually turned into the more prestigious genre of history paintings by the addition of a few small figures, typically representing a scene from the bible or classical mythology. By the end of the 1630s he was established as the leading landscapist in Italy, and enjoyed high prices for his work. These gradually became larger, but with fewer figures, more carefully painted, and produced at a lower rate. He was not generally an innovator in landscape painting, except in introducing the sun into many paintings, which had been rare before. He is now thought of as a French painter, but was born in the independent Duchy of Lorraine, and almost all his painting was done in Italy; before the late 19th century he was regarded as a painter of the "Roman School". His patrons were also mostly Italian, but after his death he became very popular with English collectors, and the UK retains a high proportion of his works. He was a prolific creator of drawings in pen and very often monochrome watercolour "wash", usually brown but sometimes grey. Chalk is sometimes used for under-drawing, and white highlighting in various media may be employed, much less often other colours such as pink. These fall into three fairly distinct groups. Firstly there are large numbers of sketches, mostly of landscapes, and apparently very often done at the scene; these have been greatly admired, and influenced other artists. Then there are studies for paintings, of various degrees of finish, many clearly done before or during the process of painting, but others perhaps after that was complete. This was certainly the case for the last group, the 195 drawings recording finished paintings collected in his Liber Veritatis (now British Museum). He produced over 40 etchings, often simplified versions of paintings, mainly before 1642. These served various purposes for him, but are now regarded as much less important than his drawings. He painted frescoes in his early career, which played an important part in making his reputation, but are now nearly all lost.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schütz, Christian Georg">
				<description>German description: Christian Georg Schütz ist der Name folgender Personen:

Christian Georg Schütz der Ältere (1718–1791), deutscher Maler und Kupferstecher
Christian Georg Schütz der Vetter (1758–1823), deutscher Maler und Radierer
Christian Georg Schütz der Jüngere (1803–1821), deutscher Maler</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fragonard, Jean-Honoré">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Honoré Fragonard (French: [ʒã onoʀe fʀaɡonɑʀ]; 4 April 1732 – 22 August 1806) was a French painter and printmaker whose late Rococo manner was distinguished by remarkable facility, exuberance, and hedonism. One of the most prolific artists active in the last decades of the Ancien Régime, Fragonard produced more than 550 paintings (not counting drawings and etchings), of which only five are dated. Among his most popular works are genre paintings conveying an atmosphere of intimacy and veiled eroticism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moreau, Louis Gabriel">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Boissieu, Jean-Jacques de">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Jacques de Boissieu (Lyon November 30, 1736 – March 1, 1810 Lyon) was a French draughtsman, etcher and engraver Boissieu was born at Lyon, and studied at the École Gratuite de Dessin in his home town, but was mostly self-taught. He began making prints in the period 1758–64, then went to Italy in the retinue of the ambassador Louis Alexandre, Duc de la Rochefoucauld d'Enville (1743–1792); he met Voltaire on his way, and returned with a collection of landscape drawings. Jean-Jacques de Boissieu realised some plates for the Diderot-d'Alembert Encyclopédie. He continued to produce prints in Lyon, which earned him a reputation as the last representative of the older etching tradition. Boissieu made many etchings of the Roman and Dutch countryside, as well as the countryside around Lyon. He was also sought after as a reproductive engraver. His pupils included Louis Nicolas Philippe Auguste de Forbin and his nephew Claude Victor de Boissieu.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bourgeois, Constant">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mind, Gottfried">
				<description>Englisch description: Gottfried Mind (German pronunciation: [ˈɡɔtfriːd ˈmɪnd]; 25 September 1768 – 17 November 1814) was a Swiss autistic savant who specialized in drawing. He was called the Raphael of Cats because of the excellence with which he painted that animal.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Alt, Jakob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jakob Alt (27 September 1789 – 30 September 1872) was a German painter and lithographer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Reinermann, Friedrich Christian">
				<description>German description: Friedrich Christian Reinermann (* 5. Oktober 1764 in Wetzlar; † 7. Februar 1835 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein in Wetzlar tätiger deutscher Landschaftsmaler, Radierer und Professor an der Städelschule.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Clovio, Giulio">
				<description>Englisch description: Giorgio Giulio Clovio or Juraj Julije Klović (1498 – January 5, 1578) was a illuminator, miniaturist, and painter born in the Kingdom of Croatia, who was mostly active in Renaissance Italy. He is considered the greatest illuminator of the Italian High Renaissance, and arguably the last very notable artist in the long tradition of the illuminated manuscript, before some modern revivals.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Watteau, Jean-Antoine">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Antoine Watteau (French: [ʒan‿ɑ̃twan vato]; baptised October 10, 1684 – died July 18, 1721), better known as Antoine Watteau, was a French painter whose brief career spurred the revival of interest in colour and movement, as seen in the tradition of Correggio and Rubens. He revitalized the waning Baroque style, shifting it to the less severe, more naturalistic, less formally classical Rococo. Watteau is credited with inventing the genre of fêtes galantes, scenes of bucolic and idyllic charm, suffused with a theatrical air. Some of his best known subjects were drawn from the world of Italian comedy and ballet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Boucher, François">
				<description>Englisch description: François Boucher (French: [fʁɑ̃swa buʃe]; 29 September 1703 – 30 May 1770) was a French painter, draughtsman and etcher, who worked in the Rococo style. Boucher is known for his idyllic and voluptuous paintings on classical themes, decorative allegories, and pastoral scenes. He was perhaps the most celebrated painter and decorative artist of the 18th century. He also painted several portraits of his patroness, Madame de Pompadour.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morgenstern, Johann Ludwig Ernst">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Ludwig Ernst Morgenstern (born 22 September 1738 in Rudolstadt; died 13 November 1819 in Frankfurt am Main) was a German painting-restorer, etcher and painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Müntz, Johann Heinrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Heinrich Müntz (1727–1798) was an Alsatian-Swiss painter and architect, known when working in England as John Henry Muntz. He was in England for seven years, and at the heart of a group trying to adapt the rococo to architecture and interior design. He has been seen as a pioneer of the Gothic Revival.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Alt, Rudolf von">
				<description>Englisch description: Rudolf Ritter von Alt (; 28 August 1812 – 12 March 1905) was an Austrian landscape and architectural painter. Born as Rudolf Alt, he could call himself von Alt and bear the title of a Ritter (knight) after he gained nobility in 1889.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klenze, Leo von">
				<description>Englisch description: Leo von Klenze (Franz Karl Leopold von Klenze; 29 February 1784, Buchladen (Bockelah / Bocla) near Schladen – 26 January 1864, Munich) was a German neoclassicist architect, painter and writer. Court architect of Bavarian King Ludwig I, Leo von Klenze was one of the most prominent representatives of Greek revival style.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kobell, Wilhelm von">
				<description>Englisch description: Wilhelm von Kobell (6 April 1766 – 15 July 1853) was a German artist, a painter, printmaker and teacher.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nussbaum, Jakob">
				<description>German description: Jakob Nussbaum (* 8. Januar 1873 in Rhina, heute Teil der Gemeinde Haunetal, Kreis Hersfeld-Rotenburg in Hessen; † 19. Dezember 1936 in Kinneret am See Genezareth im damaligen Mandatsgebiet Palästina) war ein Maler des deutschen Impressionismus. Neben Paul Klimsch war er einer von zwei Frankfurter Künstlern in der Berliner Secession.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gheyn II, Jacques de">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob de Gheyn II (also Jacques de Gheyn II) (c. 1565 – March 29, 1629) was a Dutch painter and engraver, whose work shows the transition from Northern Mannerism to Dutch realism over the course of his career.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Huysum, Jan van">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan van Huysum, also spelled Huijsum (15 April 1682 – 8 February 1749), was a Dutch painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hendriks, Wybrand">
				<description>Englisch description: Wybrand Hendriks (June 24, 1744, Amsterdam – January 28, 1831, Haarlem), was a Dutch painter and the concierge of the Teylers Museum. He is primarily known because of his portraits.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rottmann, Carl">
				<description>Englisch description: Carl Anton Joseph Rottmann (11 January 1797 in Handschuhsheim – 7 July 1850, Munich) was a German landscape painter and the most famous member of the Rottmann family of painters. Rottmann belonged to the circle of artists around the Ludwig I of Bavaria, who commissioned large landscape paintings exclusively from him. He is best known for mythical and heroising landscapes. The landscape painter Karl Lindemann-Frommel belonged to his school.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Soutter, Louis">
				<description>Englisch description: Louis Soutter (1871–1942) was a Swiss engineer, architect, painter, and musician. Soutter studied engineering in Lausanne, architecture in Geneva, violin in Brussels, and painting in Lausanne and in Paris. In Brussels he met Madge Fursman, a young American whom he married, after which he moved to the United States, where he gave drawing and violin lessons before becoming director of the Department of Fine Arts at Colorado College. Soutter became depressed and in 1902 returned to Switzerland, where he became a violinist in the orchestra of the Grand Théâtre de Genève and the Symphonic Orchestra of Lausanne. In 1922, he was institutionalized in the hospital of Eclagnens and later in the retirement home (Asile de Jura) in Ballaigues, where he would spend the rest of his life. In 1927, his cousin Le Corbusier became interested in his drawings and began supporting him. He left "a remarkable body of work whose profound modernity has only recently come to light":The interest shown in his work by such important figures as Roberto Matta (1911-2002), and the impact it would have on the art of Arnulf Rainer (1929), Julian Schnabel (1951), A.R. Penck (1939) and Elmar Trenkwalder (1959), confirm him as an artist of the twentieth century whose work has its place in reflections by contemporary artists.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fohr, Carl Philipp">
				<description>Englisch description: Karl Philipp Fohr, a brother of Daniel Fohr, was born at Heidelberg in 1795, and studied at Munich, chiefly by himself from nature and the great masters. His paintings, which are to be met with at Karlsruhe, Darmstadt, and Frankfurt, display genius and grandeur of style. In the Städel Institute at Frankfurt are views of Tivoli and Heidelberg. His death occurred in 1818 at Rome, from bathing in the Tiber.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Eysen, Louis">
				<description>German description: Louis Eysen (* 23. November 1843 in Manchester; † 21. Juli 1899 in München) war ein deutscher Landschafts- und Porträtmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dyck, Anthonis van">
				<description>Englisch description: Sir Anthony van Dyck (Dutch pronunciation: [vɑn ˈdɛi̯k], many variant spellings; 22 March 1599 – 9 December 1641) was a Flemish Baroque artist who became the leading court painter in England, after enjoying great success in Italy and Flanders. He is most famous for his portraits of Charles I of England and his family and court, painted with a relaxed elegance that was to be the dominant influence on English portrait-painting for the next 150 years. He also painted biblical and mythological subjects, displayed outstanding facility as a draughtsman, and was an important innovator in watercolour and etching. The Van Dyke beard is named after him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goltzius, Hendrick">
				<description>Englisch description: Hendrick Goltzius (January or February 1558 – 1 January 1617), was a German-born Dutch printmaker, draftsman, and painter. He was the leading Dutch engraver of the early Baroque period, or Northern Mannerism, noted for his sophisticated technique and the "exuberance" of his compositions. According to A. Hyatt Mayor, Goltzius "was the last professional engraver who drew with the authority of a good painter and the last who invented many pictures for others to copy". In middle age he also began to produce paintings.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cuyp, Aelbert">
				<description>Englisch description: Aelbert Jacobsz Cuyp (October 20, 1620 – November 15, 1691) was one of the leading Dutch landscape painters of the Dutch Golden Age in the 17th century. The most famous of a family of painters, the pupil of his father Jacob Gerritsz Cuyp (1594–1651/52), he is especially known for his large views of the Dutch countryside in early morning or late afternoon light.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hessemer, Friedrich Maximilian">
				<description>Englisch description: Friedrich Maximilian Hessemer (24 February 1800 in Darmstadt – 1 December 1860 in Frankfurt am Main) was a German architect and author.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Burgkmair, Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Burgkmair the Elder (1473–1531) was a German painter and woodcut printmaker.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schongauer, Martin">
				<description>Englisch description: Martin Schongauer (c. 1445, Colmar – 2 February 1491, Breisach), known in Italy as Bel Martino or Martino d'Anversa, was a German engraver and painter. He was the most important German printmaker before Albrecht Dürer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moholy-Nagy, László">
				<description>Englisch description: László Moholy-Nagy (/məˌhoʊliˈnɒdʒ/; Hungarian: [ˈlaːsloː ˈmoholinɒɟ]; born László Weisz; July 20, 1895 – November 24, 1946) was a Hungarian painter and photographer as well as a professor in the Bauhaus school. He was highly influenced by constructivism and a strong advocate of the integration of technology and industry into the arts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Popova, Ljubov S.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sieneser (?) Meister der ersten Hälfte des 15. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guercino (Giovanni Francesco Barbieri)">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Atget, Eugène">
				<description>Englisch description: Eugène Atget (French: [adʒɛ]; 12 February 1857 – 4 August 1927) was a French flâneur and a pioneer of documentary photography, noted for his determination to document all of the architecture and street scenes of Paris before their disappearance to modernization. Most of his photographs were first published by Berenice Abbott after his death. An inspiration for the surrealists and other artists, his genius was only recognized by a handful of young artists in the last two years of his life, and he did not live to see the wide acclaim his work would eventually receive.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baldus, Édouard">
				<description>Englisch description: Édouard Baldus (June 5, 1813, Grünebach, Prussia – 1889, Arcueil) was a French landscape, architectural and railway photographer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cameron, Julia Margaret">
				<description>Englisch description: Julia Margaret Cameron (née Pattle; 11 June 1815 Calcutta – 26 January 1879 Kalutara, Ceylon) was a British photographer. She became known for her portraits of celebrities of the time, and for photographs with Arthurian and other legendary or heroic themes. Cameron's photographic career was short, spanning eleven years of her life (1864–1875). She took up photography at the relatively late age of 48, when she was given a camera as a present.Her style was not widely appreciated in her own day: her choice to use a soft focus and to treat photography as an art as well as a science, by manipulating the wet collodion process, caused her works to be viewed as "slovenly", "mistakes" and bad photography. She found more acceptance among pre-Raphaelite artists than among photographers. Her work has influenced modern photographers, especially her closely cropped portraits. Her house, Dimbola Lodge, on the Isle of Wight is open to the public.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carroll, Lewis">
				<description>Englisch description: Charles Lutwidge Dodgson (/ˈtʃɑːrlz ˈlʌtwɪdʒ ˈdɒdsən/; 27 January 1832 – 14 January 1898), better known by his pen name Lewis Carroll (/ˈkærəl/), was an English writer, mathematician, logician, Anglican deacon, and photographer. His most famous writings are Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, its sequel Through the Looking-Glass, which includes the poem "Jabberwocky", and the poem The Hunting of the Snark, all examples of the genre of literary nonsense. He is noted for his facility at word play, logic, and fantasy. There are societies in many parts of the world dedicated to the enjoyment and promotion of his works and the investigation of his life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fenton, Roger">
				<description>Englisch description: Roger Fenton (28 March 1819 – 8 August 1869) was a pioneering British photographer, one of the first war photographers.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Frith, Francis">
				<description>Englisch description: Francis Frith (also spelled Frances Frith, 7 October 1822 – 25 February 1898) was an English photographer of the Middle East and many towns in the United Kingdom.Frith was born in Chesterfield, Derbyshire, attending Quaker schools at Ackworth and Quaker Camp Hill in Birmingham (ca. 1828–1838), before he started in the cutlery business. He suffered a nervous breakdown in 1843, recuperating over the next two years. In 1850 he started a photographic studio in Liverpool, known as Frith &amp; Hayward. A successful grocer, and later, printer, Frith fostered an interest in photography, becoming a founding member of the Liverpool Photographic Society in 1853. Frith sold his companies in 1855 in order to dedicate himself entirely to photography. He journeyed to the Middle East on three occasions, the first of which was a trip to Egypt in 1856 with very large cameras (16" x 20"). He used the collodion process, a major technical achievement in hot and dusty conditions.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hill, David Octavius">
				<description>Englisch description: David Octavius Hill (20 May 1802 – 17 May 1870) was a Scottish painter and arts activist. He formed Hill &amp; Adamson studio with the engineer and photographer Robert Adamson between 1843 and 1847 to pioneer many aspects of photography in Scotland.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Marville, Charles">
				<description>Englisch description: Charles Marville, the pseudonym of Charles François Bossu (Paris 17 July 1813 – 1 June 1879 Paris), was a French photographer, who mainly photographed architecture, landscapes and the urban environment. He used both paper and glass negatives. He is most well known for taking pictures of ancient Parisian quarters before they were destroyed and rebuilt under "Haussmannization", Baron Haussmann's new plan for modernization of Paris. In 1862, he was named official photographer of Paris.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Salomon, Erich">
				<description>Englisch description: Erich Salomon (28 April 1886 – 7 July 1944) was a German-born news photographer known for his pictures in the diplomatic and legal professions and the innovative methods he used to acquire them. Born in Berlin, Salomon studied law, engineering, and zoology up to World War I. After the war, he worked in the promotion department of the Ullstein publishing empire designing their billboard advertisements. He first picked up a camera in 1927, when he was 41, to document some legal disputes and soon after hid an Ermanox camera usable in dim light in his bowler hat. By cutting a hole in the hat for the lens, Salomon snapped a photo of a police killer on trial in a Berlin criminal court. Beginning in 1928, Salomon worked for Ullstein's Berliner Illustrirte Zeitung as a photographer. With his multilingual ability and clever concealment, his reputation soared among the people of Europe. When the Kellogg-Briand Pact was signed in 1928, Salomon walked into the signing room and took the vacant seat of the Polish delegate, and took several photos. He is one of only two known persons to have photographed a session of the U.S. Supreme Court. After Adolf Hitler came to power in Germany, Salomon fled to the Netherlands with his wife and continued his photographic career in The Hague. Salomon declined an invitation from Life Magazine to move to the United States. He and his family were trapped in the Low Countries after Germany invaded in 1940. Salomon and his family were held in the Westerbork transit camp, then for almost five months in Theresienstadt concentration camp and were deported from there to the Theresienstadt Family Camp in May 1944. He died in Auschwitz on 7 July 1944. The Dr. Erich Salomon Award is a lifetime achievement award for photojournalists given by the Deutsche Gesellschaft für Fotografie (German society for photography).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sommer, Giorgio">
				<description>Englisch description: Giorgio Sommer (1834–1914) was born in Frankfurt am Main (in modern-day Germany), and became one of Europe’s most important and prolific photographers of the 19th century. Active from 1857 to 1888, he produced thousands of images of archeological ruins, landscapes, art objects and portraits. After studying business in Frankfurt, Sommer opened his first photography studio in Switzerland, where he made relief images of mountains for the Swiss government. In 1856 moved his business to Naples and later (1866) formed a partnership with fellow German photographer Edmund Behles (also known as Edmondo Behles) who owned a studio in Rome. Operating from their respective Naples and Rome studios, Sommer and Behles became one of the largest and most prolific photography concerns in Italy. He held studios in Naples at: 
*  Strada di Chiaia 168 
*  Via Monte di Dio 4 and 8 
*  Piazza della Vittoria Sommer’s catalog included images from the Vatican Museum, the National Archeological Museum at Naples, the Roman ruins at Pompeii, as well as street and architectural scenes of Naples, Florence, Rome, Capri and Sicily. Most notably, Sommer published his comprehensive album Dintorni di Napoli which contained over one hundred images of everyday scenes in Naples. In April 1872, he documented a very large eruption of Mount Vesuvius in a series of stunning photographs. Sommer and Behles exhibited extensively and earned numerous honors and prizes for their work (London 1862, Paris 1867, Vienna 1873, Nuremberg 1885). At one time, Sommer was appointed official photographer to King Victor Emmanuel II of Italy. Sommer was involved in every aspect of the photography business. He published his own images that he sold in his studios and to customers across Europe. In later years, he photographed custom images for book illustrations, as well as printing his own albums and postcards. Sommer worked in all the popular formats of his day: carte de visite, stereoview, and large albumen prints (approximately 8x10) which were sold individually and in bound albums. The partnership with Behles ended in 1874, after which each photographer continued his own business. In Naples, Sommer opened a total of four additional studios: at No. 4 and No. 8 Monte di Dio, No. 5 Magazzino S. Caterina, and a last at Piazza della Vittoria. Sommer died in Naples in 1914.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vogel, Hermann Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Hermann Wilhelm Vogel (March 26, 1834 – December 17, 1898)  was a German photochemist and photographer who discovered dye sensitization, which is of great importance to photography.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kühn, Heinrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Carl Christian Heinrich Kühn (25 February 1866 in Dresden – 14 September 1944 in Birgitz) was an Austrian–German photographer and photography pioneer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stieglitz, Alfred">
				<description>Englisch description: Alfred Stieglitz (January 1, 1864 – July 13, 1946) was an American photographer and modern art promoter who was instrumental over his fifty-year career in making photography an accepted art form. In addition to his photography, Stieglitz was known for the New York art galleries that he ran in the early part of the 20th century, where he introduced many avant-garde European artists to the U.S. He was married to painter Georgia O'Keeffe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vidal, Léon">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Diefenbach, Karl Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Karl Wilhelm Diefenbach (February 21, 1851, Hadamar, Duchy of Nassau – December 15, 1913, Capri) was a German painter and social reformer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Zwengauer, Anton">
				<description>Englisch description: Anton Zwengauer (11 October 1810 – 13 June 1884) was a German painter of the Biedermeier period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Raffael">
				<description>Englisch description: Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino (Italian: [raffaˈɛllo ˈsantsjo da urˈbiːno]; April 6 or March 28, 1483 – April 6, 1520), known as Raphael (/ˈræfeɪəl/, US /ˈræfiəl, ˌrɑːfaɪˈɛl/), was an Italian painter and architect of the High Renaissance. His work is admired for its clarity of form, ease of composition, and visual achievement of the Neoplatonic ideal of human grandeur. Together with Michelangelo and Leonardo da Vinci, he forms the traditional trinity of great masters of that period. Raphael was enormously productive, running an unusually large workshop and, despite his death at 37, leaving a large body of work. Many of his works are found in the Vatican Palace, where the frescoed Raphael Rooms were the central, and the largest, work of his career. The best known work is The School of Athens in the Vatican Stanza della Segnatura. After his early years in Rome much of his work was executed by his workshop from his drawings, with considerable loss of quality. He was extremely influential in his lifetime, though outside Rome his work was mostly known from his collaborative printmaking. After his death, the influence of his great rival Michelangelo was more widespread until the 18th and 19th centuries, when Raphael's more serene and harmonious qualities were again regarded as the highest models. His career falls naturally into three phases and three styles, first described by Giorgio Vasari: his early years in Umbria, then a period of about four years (1504–1508) absorbing the artistic traditions of Florence, followed by his last hectic and triumphant twelve years in Rome, working for two Popes and their close associates.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hammershøi, Vilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Vilhelm Hammershøi (), often written in English Vilhelm Hammershoi (15 May 1864 – 13 February 1916), was a Danish painter. He is known for his poetic, subdued portraits and interiors. In 1997, Denmark issued a postage stamp in his honour.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carrière, Eugène">
				<description>Englisch description: Eugène Anatole Carrière (16 January 1849 – 27 March 1906) was a French Symbolist artist of the Fin de siècle period. His paintings are best known for their brown monochrome palette. He was a close friend of the sculptor Rodin and his work influenced Picasso. Some see traces of Carrière's monochrome style in Picasso's Blue Period. He was born at Gournay-sur-Marne (Seine-Saint-Denis). He studied at the École des Beaux-Arts in Paris and later under Cabanel. During the Franco-Prussian War he passed some time as a prisoner in Dresden, where the art of Rubens made a lasting impression on him, as may be seen in the glowing colors of his early paintings. About 1890 he adopted the gray, misty-color scheme with contrasts of light and shadow, so characteristic of his art, but which no other artist has been able to imitate without affectation. His themes usually are scenes of his domestic life, and he repeatedly introduced the likeness of his wife in his paintings. The first of these, The Young Mother (1879), is now in the Musée des Beaux-Arts de Rouen. It was followed by, The Sick Child (Montargis), The First Communion (Toulon), and the highly praised 1887 portrait of the sculptor Louis-Henri Devillez. Carrière was one of the leaders in the secessionist movement, which led to the founding of the Société Nationale des Beaux-Arts. At the Société, Carrière exhibited, among other works, Sleep (1890), the celebrated portrait of Paul Verlaine (1891, Luxembourg), Maternity (1892, Luxembourg), Christ on the Cross (1897), and Madame Menard-Dorian (1906). Carrière played an influential role as an art teacher at Académie de La Palette. He also modeled a monument to Verlaine in the style of Rodin, and wrote gracefully and interestingly on art subjects. Several of his works may be found at the Musée d'Orsay in Paris and in National Museum of Serbia in Belgrade.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Watts, George Frederick">
				<description>Englisch description: Not to be confused with George Fiddes Watt. George Frederic Watts OM RA (London 23 February 1817 – 1 July 1904) was an English Victorian painter and sculptor associated with the Symbolist movement. He said "I paint ideas, not things." Watts became famous in his lifetime for his allegorical works, such as Hope and Love and Life. These paintings were intended to form part of an epic symbolic cycle called the "House of Life", in which the emotions and aspirations of life would all be represented in a universal symbolic language.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goya, Francisco de">
				<description>Englisch description: (This name uses Spanish naming customs: the first or paternal family name is Goya and the second or maternal family name is Lucientes.) Francisco José de Goya y Lucientes (/ˈɡɔɪə/; Spanish: [fɾanˈθisko xoˈse ðe ˈɣoʝa i luˈθjentes]; 30 March 1746 – 16 April 1828) was a Spanish romantic painter and printmaker. He is considered the most important Spanish artist of late 18th and early 19th centuries and throughout his long career was a commentator and chronicler of his era. Immensely successful in his lifetime, Goya is often referred to as both the last of the Old Masters and the first of the moderns. He was born to a modest family in 1746 in the village of Fuendetodos in Aragon. He studied painting from age 14 under José Luzán y Martinez and moved to Madrid to study with Anton Raphael Mengs. He married Josefa Bayeu in 1773; the couple's life together was characterised by an almost constant series of pregnancies and miscarriages. He became a court painter to the Spanish Crown in 1786 and this early portion of his career is marked by portraits of the Spanish aristocracy and royalty, and Rococo style tapestry cartoons designed for the royal palace. Goya was a guarded man and although letters and writings survive, we know comparatively little about his thoughts. He suffered a severe and undiagnosed illness in 1793 which left him completely deaf. After 1793 his work became progressively darker and pessimistic. His later easel and mural paintings, prints and drawings appear to reflect a bleak outlook on personal, social and political levels, and contrast with his social climbing. He was appointed Director of the Royal Academy in 1795, the year Manuel Godoy made an unfavorable treaty with France. In 1799 Goya became Primer Pintor de Cámara, the then highest rank for a Spanish court painter. In the late 1790s, commissioned by Godoy, he completed his La maja desnuda, a remarkably daring nude for the time and clearly indebted to Diego Velázquez. In 1801 he painted Charles IV of Spain and His Family. In 1807 Napoleon led the French army into Spain. He remained in Madrid during the Peninsular War, which seems to have affected him deeply. Although he did not vocalise his thoughts in public, they can be inferred from his "Disasters of War" series of prints (although published 35 years after his death) and his 1814 paintings The Second of May 1808 and The Third of May 1808. Other works from his mid period include the "Caprichos" and Los Disparates etching series, and a wide variety of paintings concerned with insanity, mental asylums, witches, fantastical creatures and religious and political corruption, all of which suggest that he feared for both his country's fate and his own mental and physical health. His late period culminates with the "Black Paintings" of 1819–1823, applied on oil on the plaster walls of his house the "Quinta del Sordo" (house of the deaf man) where, disillusioned by political and social developments in Spain he lived in near isolation. Goya eventually abandoned Spain in 1824 to retire to the French city of Bordeaux, accompanied by his much younger maid and companion, Leocadia Weiss, who may or may not have been his lover. There he completed his "La Tauromaquia" series and a number of other, major, canvases. Following a stroke which left him paralyzed on his right side, and suffering failing eyesight and poor access to painting materials, he died and was buried on 16 April 1828 aged 82. His body was later re-interred in Spain.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hasenpflug, Carl Georg Adolph">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ribera, Jusepe de">
				<description>Englisch description: José de Ribera (January 12, 1591 – September 2, 1652) was a Spanish Tenebrist painter and printmaker, better known as Jusepe de Ribera. He also was called Lo Spagnoletto ("the Little Spaniard") by his contemporaries and early writers. Ribera was a leading painter of the Spanish school, although his mature work was all done in Italy.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rosso, Medardo">
				<description>Englisch description: Medardo Rosso (Italian: [meˈdardo ˈrosso]; 20 or 21 June 1858, Turin, Italy – 31 March 1928, Milan) was an Italian sculptor. He is considered, like Auguste Rodin, a Post Impressionism artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Allori, Cristofano">
				<description>Englisch description: Cristofano Allori (17 October 1577 – 1 April 1621) was an Italian portrait painter of the late Florentine Mannerist school. Allori was born at Florence and received his first lessons in painting from his father, Alessandro Allori, but becoming dissatisfied with the hard anatomical drawing and cold coloring of the latter, he entered the studio of Gregorio Pagani, who was one of the leaders of the late Florentine school, which sought to unite the rich coloring of the Venetians with the Florentine attention to drawing. Allori also appears to have worked under Cigoli. His pictures are distinguished by their close adherence to nature and the delicacy and technical perfection of their execution. His technical skill is shown by the fact that several copies he made of Correggio's works were thought to be duplicates by Correggio himself. His extreme fastidiousness limited the number of his works. Several examples are to be seen at Florence and elsewhere. His most famous work, in his own day and now, is Judith with the Head of Holofernes. It exists in at least two versions by Allori, of which the prime version is perhaps that in the British Royal Collection, dated 1613, with various pentimenti. A version of 1620 in the Palazzo Pitti in Florence is the best known and there are several copies by studio and other hands. According to the near-contemporary biography by Filippo Baldinucci, the model for the Judith was his former mistress, the beautiful "La Mazzafirra", who is also represented in his Magdalene, the head of Holofernes is a self-portrait, and the maid is "La Mazzafirra"'s mother.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ribot, Théodule">
				<description>Englisch description: Théodule-Augustin Ribot (August 8, 1823 – September 11, 1891) was a French realist painter and printmaker. He was born in Saint-Nicolas-d'Attez, and studied at the École des Arts et Métiers de Châlons before moving to Paris in 1845. There he found work decorating gilded frames for a mirror manufacturer. Although he received a measure of artistic training while working as an assistant to Auguste-Barthélémy Glaize, Ribot was mostly self-taught as a painter. After a trip to Algeria around 1848, he returned in 1851 to Paris, where he continued to make his living as an artisan. In the late 1850s, working at night by lamplight, he began to paint seriously, depicting everyday subjects in a realistic style. He made his Salon debut in 1861 with four paintings of kitchen subjects. Collectors purchased the works, and his paintings in the Salons of 1864 and 1865 were awarded medals. Ribot painted domestic genre works, still-lifes, portraits, as well as religious scenes, such as his Salon success St. Sebastian, Martyr (1865). His preference was for painting directly from nature, emphasizing the contrasts of light and dark. His use of chiaroscuro to suggest psychological states grew from his admiration for Spanish and Dutch baroque masters such as Ribera and Rembrandt, an enthusiasm shared by his contemporaries Courbet and Bonvin. Members of Ribot's family are the likely models for many of his figure compositions, in which the subjects engage in humble activities, such as preparing meals or gathering in groups to read to each other. The light draws attention to faces and hands, which emerge sharply from dimly lit surroundings. Although the realism of Ribot's work aligns him with the most progressive artists of the generation preceding the Impressionists, he was no revolutionary, and his work met with a generally favorable response from the public and from critics. In 1878 Ribot received the Légion d'honneur. At about this time, in ill health, he stopped painting and moved to Colombes, where he died in 1891. 
* Gallery  
* Still Life with Apples and a Pomegranate', circa 1865 
* A Girl Arranging a Vase of Flowers 
* The Cook and the Cat 
* The Good Samaritan, before 1870</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schjerfbeck, Helene">
				<description>Englisch description: Helene Schjerfbeck (July 10, 1862 – January 23, 1946, pronounced IPA: [he'le:n 'ɧærvbek] in Standard Swedish and IPA: [helɛ:n ʃærvbek] in Finland Swedish) was a Finnish painter. She is most widely known for her realist works and self-portraits, and less well known for her landscapes and still lifes. Throughout her long life, her work changed dramatically. Her work starts with a dazzlingly skilled, somewhat melancholic version of late-19th-century academic realism…it ends with distilled, nearly abstract images in which pure paint and cryptic description are held in perfect balance. (Roberta Smith, New York Times, November 27th 1992)</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brandi, Giacinto">
				<description>Englisch description: Giacinto Brandi (1621 – 19 January 1691) was an Italian painter of the Baroque era, active mainly in Rome and Naples.</description>
			</Artist>
		</AllPerson>
	<Allstyle><style stylename="Baroque"><description>Englisch description: The Baroque (US /bəˈroʊk/ or UK /bəˈrɒk/) is often thought of as a period of artistic style that used exaggerated motion and clear, easily interpreted detail to produce drama, tension, exuberance, and grandeur in sculpture, painting, architecture, literature, dance, theater, and music. The style began around 1600 in Rome and Italy, and spread to most of Europe. The popularity and success of the Baroque style was encouraged by the Catholic Church, which had decided at the time of the Council of Trent, in response to the Protestant Reformation, that the arts should communicate religious themes in direct and emotional involvement. The aristocracy also saw the dramatic style of Baroque architecture and art as a means of impressing visitors and expressing triumph, power and control. Baroque palaces are built around an entrance of courts, grand staircases and reception rooms of sequentially increasing opulence. However, "baroque" has resonance and application that extend beyond a simple reduction to either style or period.</description></style><style stylename="Renaissance"><description>Englisch description: The Renaissance (UK /rᵻˈneɪsəns/, US /rɛnəˈsɑːns/) is a period in European history, from the 14th to the 17th century, regarded as the cultural bridge between the Middle Ages and modern history. It started as a cultural movement in Italy in the Late Medieval period and later spread to the rest of Europe, marking the beginning of the Early Modern Age. The intellectual basis of the Renaissance was its own invented version of humanism, derived from the rediscovery of classical Greek philosophy, such as that of Protagoras, who said that "Man is the measure of all things." This new thinking became manifest in art, architecture, politics, science and literature. Early examples were the development of perspective in oil painting and the recycled knowledge of how to make concrete. Although the invention of metal movable type sped the dissemination of ideas from the later 15th century, the changes of the Renaissance were not uniformly experienced across Europe. As a cultural movement, the Renaissance encompassed innovative flowering of Latin and vernacular literatures, beginning with the 14th-century resurgence of learning based on classical sources, which contemporaries credited to Petrarch; the development of linear perspective and other techniques of rendering a more natural reality in painting; and gradual but widespread educational reform. In politics, the Renaissance contributed to the development of the customs and conventions of diplomacy, and in science to an increased reliance on observation and inductive reasoning. Although the Renaissance saw revolutions in many intellectual pursuits, as well as social and political upheaval, it is perhaps best known for its artistic developments and the contributions of such polymaths as Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo, who inspired the term "Renaissance man". The Renaissance first began in Florence, in the 14th century. Various theories have been proposed to account for its origins and characteristics, focusing on a variety of factors including the social and civic peculiarities of Florence at the time: its political structure; the patronage of its dominant family, the Medici; and the migration of Greek scholars and texts to Italy following the Fall of Constantinople to the Ottoman Turks. Other major centres were northern Italian city-states such as Venice, Genoa, Milan, Bologna, and finally Rome during the Renaissance Papacy. The Renaissance has a long and complex historiography, and, in line with general scepticism of discrete periodizations, there has been much debate among historians reacting to the 19th-century glorification of the "Renaissance" and individual culture heroes as "Renaissance men", questioning the usefulness of Renaissance as a term and as a historical delineation. The art historian Erwin Panofsky observed of this resistance to the concept of "Renaissance": It is perhaps no accident that the factuality of the Italian Renaissance has been most vigorously questioned by those who are not obliged to take a professional interest in the aesthetic aspects of civilization—historians of economic and social developments, political and religious situations, and, most particularly, natural science—but only exceptionally by students of literature and hardly ever by historians of Art. Some observers have called into question whether the Renaissance was a cultural "advance" from the Middle Ages, instead seeing it as a period of pessimism and nostalgia for classical antiquity, while social and economic historians, especially of the longue durée, have instead focused on the continuity between the two eras, which are linked, as Panofsky observed, "by a thousand ties". The word Renaissance, literally meaning "Rebirth" in French, first appeared in English in the 1830s. The word also occurs in Jules Michelet's 1855 work, Histoire de France. The word Renaissance has also been extended to other historical and cultural movements, such as the Carolingian Renaissance and the Renaissance of the 12th century.</description></style><style stylename="Late Middle Ages"><description>Englisch description: The Late Middle Ages or late medieval period was the period of European history generally comprising the 14th and 15th centuries (c. 1301–1500). The Late Middle Ages followed the High Middle Ages and preceded the onset of the early modern era (and, in much of Europe, the Renaissance). Around 1300, centuries of prosperity and growth in Europe came to a halt. A series of famines and plagues, including the Great Famine of 1315–1317 and the Black Death, reduced the population to around half of what it was before the calamities. Along with depopulation came social unrest and endemic warfare. France and England experienced serious peasant uprisings, such as the Jacquerie and the Peasants' Revolt, as well as over a century of intermittent conflict in the Hundred Years' War. To add to the many problems of the period, the unity of the Catholic Church was shattered by the Western Schism. Collectively these events are sometimes called the Crisis of the Late Middle Ages. Despite these crises, the 14th century was also a time of great progress in the arts and sciences. Following a renewed interest in ancient Greek and Roman texts that took root in the High Middle Ages, the Italian Renaissance began. The absorption of Latin texts had started before the Renaissance of the 12th century through contact with Arabs during the Crusades, but the availability of important Greek texts accelerated with the capture of Constantinople by the Ottoman Turks, when many Byzantine scholars had to seek refuge in the West, particularly Italy. Combined with this influx of classical ideas was the invention of printing which facilitated dissemination of the printed word and democratized learning. These two things would later lead to the Protestant Reformation. Toward the end of the period, an era of discovery began (Age of Discovery). The rise of the Ottoman Empire, culminating in the Fall of Constantinople in 1453, eroded the last remnants of the Byzantine Empire and cut off trading possibilities with the east. Europeans were forced to seek new trading routes, leading to the expedition of Columbus to the Americas in 1492, and Vasco da Gama’s circumnavigation of India and Africa in 1498. Their discoveries strengthened the economy and power of European nations. The changes brought about by these developments have led many scholars to view this period as the end of the Middle Ages and beginning of modern history and early modern Europe. However, the division is somewhat artificial, since ancient learning was never entirely absent from European society. As a result there was developmental continuity between the ancient age (via classical antiquity) and the modern age. Some historians, particularly in Italy, prefer not to speak of the Late Middle Ages at all, but rather see the high period of the Middle Ages transitioning to the Renaissance and the modern era.</description></style><style stylename="romanticism"><description>Englisch description: Romanticism (also known as the Romantic era) was an artistic, literary, musical and intellectual movement that originated in Europe toward the end of the 18th century, and in most areas was at its peak in the approximate period from 1800 to 1850. Romanticism was characterized by its emphasis on emotion and individualism as well as glorification of all the past and nature, preferring the medieval rather than the classical.   It was partly a reaction to the Industrial Revolution, the aristocratic social and political norms of the Age of Enlightenment, and the scientific rationalization of nature—all components of modernity. It was embodied most strongly in the visual arts, music, and literature, but had a major impact on historiography, education, the social sciences, and the natural sciences. It had a significant and complex effect on politics, with romantic thinkers influencing liberalism, radicalism, conservatism and nationalism.The movement emphasized intense emotion as an authentic source of aesthetic experience, placing new emphasis on such emotions as apprehension, horror and terror, and awe—especially that experienced in confronting the new aesthetic categories of the sublimity and beauty of nature. It elevated folk art and ancient custom to something noble, but also spontaneity as a desirable characteristic (as in the musical impromptu). In contrast to the Rationalism and Classicism of the Enlightenment, Romanticism revived medievalism and elements of art and narrative perceived as authentically medieval in an attempt to escape population growth, early urban sprawl, and industrialism.
Although the movement was rooted in the German Sturm und Drang movement, which preferred intuition and emotion to the rationalism of the Enlightenment, the events and ideologies of the French Revolution were also proximate factors. Romanticism assigned a high value to the achievements of "heroic" individualists and artists, whose examples, it maintained, would raise the quality of society. It also promoted the individual imagination as a critical authority allowed of freedom from classical notions of form in art. There was a strong recourse to historical and natural inevitability, a Zeitgeist, in the representation of its ideas. In the second half of the 19th century, Realism was offered as a polar opposite to Romanticism. The decline of Romanticism during this time was associated with multiple processes, including social and political changes and the spread of nationalism.


</description></style><style stylename="classicism"><description>Englisch description: Classicism, in the arts, refers generally to a high regard for a classical period, classical antiquity in the Western tradition, as setting standards for taste which the classicists seek to emulate. The art of classicism typically seeks to be formal and restrained: of the Discobolus Sir Kenneth Clark observed, "if we object to his restraint and compression we are simply objecting to the classicism of classic art. A violent emphasis or a sudden acceleration of rhythmic movement would have destroyed those qualities of balance and completeness through which it retained until the present century its position of authority in the restricted repertoire of visual images." Classicism, as Clark noted, implies a canon of widely accepted ideal forms, whether in the Western canon that he was examining in The Nude (1956), or the literary Chinese classics or Chinese art, where the revival of classic styles is also a recurring feature.
Classicism is a force which is often present in post-medieval European and European influenced traditions; however, some periods felt themselves more connected to the classical ideals than others, particularly the Age of Enlightenment, when Neoclassicism was an important movement in the visual arts.
</description></style><style stylename="realism"><description>Englisch description: Realism, sometimes called naturalism, in the arts is generally the attempt to represent subject matter truthfully, without artificiality and avoiding artistic conventions, or implausible, exotic, and supernatural elements. Realism has been prevalent in the arts at many periods, and can be in large part a matter of technique and training, and the avoidance of stylization.

In the visual arts, illusionistic realism is the accurate depiction of lifeforms, perspective, and the details of light and colour. But realist or naturalist works of art may, as well or instead of illusionist realism, be "realist" in their subject-matter, and emphasize the mundane, ugly or sordid. This is typical of the 19th-century Realist movement that began in France in the 1850s, after the 1848 Revolution,[1] and also social realism, regionalism, or kitchen sink realism. The Realist painters rejected Romanticism, which had come to dominate French literature and art, with roots in the late 18th century.

There have been various movements invoking realism in the other arts, such as the opera style of verismo, literary realism, theatrical realism, and Italian neorealist cinema.</description></style><style stylename="Impressionism"><description>Englisch description: Impressionism is a 19th-century art movement that originated with a group of Paris-based artists whose independent exhibitions brought them to prominence during the 1870s and 1880s. Impressionist painting characteristics include relatively small, thin, yet visible brush strokes, open composition, emphasis on accurate depiction of light in its changing qualities (often accentuating the effects of the passage of time), ordinary subject matter, inclusion of movement as a crucial element of human perception and experience, and unusual visual angles. The Impressionists faced harsh opposition from the conventional art community in France. The name of the style derives from the title of a Claude Monet work, Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which provoked the critic Louis Leroy to coin the term in a satirical review published in the Parisian newspaper Le Charivari. The development of Impressionism in the visual arts was soon followed by analogous styles in other media that became known as impressionist music and impressionist literature.</description></style><style stylename="symbolism"><description>Englisch description: Symbolism was a late nineteenth-century art movement of French, Russian and Belgian origin in poetry and other arts.

In literature, the style originates with the 1857 publication of Charles Baudelaire's Les Fleurs du mal. The works of Edgar Allan Poe, which Baudelaire admired greatly and translated into French, were a significant influence and the source of many stock tropes and images. The aesthetic was developed by Stéphane Mallarmé and Paul Verlaine during the 1860s and 1870s. In the 1880s, the aesthetic was articulated by a series of manifestos and attracted a generation of writers. The name "symbolist" itself was first applied by the critic Jean Moréas, who invented the term to distinguish the Symbolists from the related Decadents of literature and of art.

Distinct from, but related to, the style of literature, symbolism in art is related to the gothic component of Romanticism and Impressionism.
</description></style><style stylename="Post-Impressionism"><description>Englisch description: Post-Impressionism (also spelled Postimpressionism) is a predominantly French art movement that developed roughly between 1886 and 1905, from the last Impressionist exhibition to the birth of Fauvism. Post-Impressionism emerged as a reaction against Impressionists' concern for the naturalistic depiction of light and colour. Due to its broad emphasis on abstract qualities or symbolic content, Post-Impressionism encompasses Neo-Impressionism, Symbolism, Cloisonnism, Pont-Aven School, and Synthetism, along with some later Impressionists' work. The movement was led by Paul Cézanne, Paul Gauguin, Vincent van Gogh, and Georges Seurat. The term Post-Impressionism was first used by art critic Roger Fry in 1906. Critic Frank Rutter in a review of the Salon d'Automne published in Art News, 15 October 1910, described Othon Friesz as a "post-impressionist leader"; there was also an advert for the show The Post-Impressionists of France. Three weeks later, Roger Fry used the term again when he organized the 1910 exhibition, Manet and the Post-Impressionists, defining it as the development of French art since Manet. Post-Impressionists extended Impressionism while rejecting its limitations: they continued using vivid colours, often thick application of paint, and real-life subject matter, but were more inclined to emphasize geometric forms, distort form for expressive effect, and use unnatural or arbitrary colour.</description></style><style stylename="expressionism"><description>Englisch description: Expressionism is a modernist movement, initially in poetry and painting, originating in Germany at the beginning of the 20th century. Its typical trait is to present the world solely from a subjective perspective, distorting it radically for emotional effect in order to evoke moods or ideas. Expressionist artists have sought to express the meaning of emotional experience rather than physical reality.Expressionism developed as an avant-garde style before the First World War. It remained popular during the Weimar Republic, particularly in Berlin. The style extended to a wide range of the arts, including expressionist architecture, painting, literature, theatre, dance, film and music.The term is sometimes suggestive of angst. In a historical sense, much older painters such as Matthias Grünewald and El Greco are sometimes termed expressionist, though the term is applied mainly to 20th-century works. The Expressionist emphasis on individual and subjective perspective has been characterized as a reaction to positivism and other artistic styles such as Naturalism and Impressionism.


</description></style><style stylename="Bauhaus"><description>Englisch description: The Bauhaus was founded by Walter Gropius in Weimar. In spite of its name and the fact that its founder was an architect, the Bauhaus, during the first years of existence, did not have an architecture department. Nonetheless, it was founded with the idea of creating a "total" work of art (Gesamtkunstwerk) in which all arts, including architecture, would eventually be brought together. The Bauhaus style later became one of the most influential currents in modern design, Modernist architecture and art, design and architectural education. The Bauhaus had a profound influence upon subsequent developments in art, architecture, graphic design, interior design, industrial design, and typography. The school existed in three German cities: Weimar from 1919 to 1925, Dessau from 1925 to 1932 and Berlin from 1932 to 1933, under three different architect-directors: Walter Gropius from 1919 to 1928, Hannes Meyer from 1928 to 1930 and Ludwig Mies van der Rohe from 1930 until 1933, when the school was closed by its own leadership under pressure from the Nazi regime, having been painted as a centre of communist intellectualism. Although the school was closed, the staff continued to spread its idealistic precepts as they left Germany and emigrated all over the world. The changes of venue and leadership resulted in a constant shifting of focus, technique, instructors, and politics. For example, the pottery shop was discontinued when the school moved from Weimar to Dessau, even though it had been an important revenue source; when Mies van der Rohe took over the school in 1930, he transformed it into a private school, and would not allow any supporters of Hannes Meyer to attend it.</description></style><style stylename="New Objectivity"><description>Englisch description: The New Objectivity (in German: Neue Sachlichkeit) was a movement in German art that arose during the 1920s as a reaction against expressionism. The term was coined by Gustav Friedrich Hartlaub, the director of the Kunsthalle in Mannheim, who used it as the title of an art exhibition staged in 1925 to showcase artists who were working in a post-expressionist spirit. As these artists—who included Max Beckmann, Otto Dix, and George Grosz—rejected the self-involvement and romantic longings of the expressionists, Weimar intellectuals in general made a call to arms for public collaboration, engagement, and rejection of romantic idealism. Although principally describing a tendency in German painting, the term took a life of its own, and came to characterize the attitude of public life in Weimar Germany as well as the art, literature, music, and architecture created to adapt to it. Rather than some goal of philosophical objectivity, it was meant to imply a turn towards practical engagement with the world—an all-business attitude, understood by Germans as intrinsically American. The movement essentially ended in 1933 with the fall of the Weimar Republic and the rise of the Nazis to power.</description></style><style stylename="Late Gothic"><description>Englisch description: International Gothic is a period of Gothic art which developed in Burgundy, France and northern Italy in the late 14th and early 15th century. It then spread very widely across Western Europe, hence the name for the period, which was introduced by the French art historian Louis Courajod at the end of the 19th century. Artists and portable works, such as illuminated manuscripts, traveled widely around the continent, leading to a common aesthetic among the royalty and higher nobility and considerably reducing the variation in national styles among works produced for the courtly elites. The main influences were northern France, the Duchy of Burgundy, the Imperial court in Prague, and Italy. Royal marriages such as that between Richard II of England and Anne of Bohemia helped to spread the style. It was initially a style of courtly sophistication, but somewhat more robust versions spread to art commissioned by the emerging mercantile classes and the smaller nobility. In Northern Europe "Late Gothic" continuations of the style, especially in its decorative elements, could still be found until the early 16th century, as no alternative decorative vocabulary emerged to replace it before Renaissance Classicism. Usage of the terms by art historians varies somewhat, with some using the term more restrictively than others. Some art historians feel the term is "in many ways ... not very helpful.. since it tends to skate over both differences and details of transmission."</description></style><style stylename="High Renaissance"><description>Englisch description: In art history, High Renaissance is the period denoting the apogee of the visual arts in the Italian Renaissance. The High Renaissance period is traditionally taken to begin in the 1490s, with Leonardo's fresco of the Last Supper in Milan and the death of Lorenzo de' Medici in Florence, and to have ended in 1527 with the sacking of Rome by the troops of Charles V. This term was first used in German (Hochrenaissance) in the early nineteenth century, and has its origins in the "High Style" of painting and sculpture described by Johann Joachim Winckelmann. Over the last twenty years, use of the term has been frequently criticized by academic art historians for oversimplifying artistic developments, ignoring historical context, and focusing only on a few iconic works.</description></style><style stylename="Late Renaissance"><description>Englisch description: The Renaissance (UK /rᵻˈneɪsəns/, US /rɛnəˈsɑːns/) is a period in European history, from the 14th to the 17th century, regarded as the cultural bridge between the Middle Ages and modern history. It started as a cultural movement in Italy in the Late Medieval period and later spread to the rest of Europe, marking the beginning of the Early Modern Age. The intellectual basis of the Renaissance was its own invented version of humanism, derived from the rediscovery of classical Greek philosophy, such as that of Protagoras, who said that "Man is the measure of all things." This new thinking became manifest in art, architecture, politics, science and literature. Early examples were the development of perspective in oil painting and the recycled knowledge of how to make concrete. Although the invention of metal movable type sped the dissemination of ideas from the later 15th century, the changes of the Renaissance were not uniformly experienced across Europe. As a cultural movement, the Renaissance encompassed innovative flowering of Latin and vernacular literatures, beginning with the 14th-century resurgence of learning based on classical sources, which contemporaries credited to Petrarch; the development of linear perspective and other techniques of rendering a more natural reality in painting; and gradual but widespread educational reform. In politics, the Renaissance contributed to the development of the customs and conventions of diplomacy, and in science to an increased reliance on observation and inductive reasoning. Although the Renaissance saw revolutions in many intellectual pursuits, as well as social and political upheaval, it is perhaps best known for its artistic developments and the contributions of such polymaths as Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo, who inspired the term "Renaissance man". The Renaissance first began in Florence, in the 14th century. Various theories have been proposed to account for its origins and characteristics, focusing on a variety of factors including the social and civic peculiarities of Florence at the time: its political structure; the patronage of its dominant family, the Medici; and the migration of Greek scholars and texts to Italy following the Fall of Constantinople to the Ottoman Turks. Other major centres were northern Italian city-states such as Venice, Genoa, Milan, Bologna, and finally Rome during the Renaissance Papacy. The Renaissance has a long and complex historiography, and, in line with general scepticism of discrete periodizations, there has been much debate among historians reacting to the 19th-century glorification of the "Renaissance" and individual culture heroes as "Renaissance men", questioning the usefulness of Renaissance as a term and as a historical delineation. The art historian Erwin Panofsky observed of this resistance to the concept of "Renaissance": It is perhaps no accident that the factuality of the Italian Renaissance has been most vigorously questioned by those who are not obliged to take a professional interest in the aesthetic aspects of civilization—historians of economic and social developments, political and religious situations, and, most particularly, natural science—but only exceptionally by students of literature and hardly ever by historians of Art. Some observers have called into question whether the Renaissance was a cultural "advance" from the Middle Ages, instead seeing it as a period of pessimism and nostalgia for classical antiquity, while social and economic historians, especially of the longue durée, have instead focused on the continuity between the two eras, which are linked, as Panofsky observed, "by a thousand ties". The word Renaissance, literally meaning "Rebirth" in French, first appeared in English in the 1830s. The word also occurs in Jules Michelet's 1855 work, Histoire de France. The word Renaissance has also been extended to other historical and cultural movements, such as the Carolingian Renaissance and the Renaissance of the 12th century.</description></style><style stylename="Italian Mannerism"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="rococo"><description>Englisch description: 


Rococo ( or ), less commonly roccoco, or "Late Baroque", is a highly ornamental and theatrical style of decoration which combines asymmetry, scrolling curves, gilding, white and pastel colors, sculpted molding, and trompe l'oeil frescoes to create the illusions of surprise, motion and drama. It first appeared in France and Italy in the 1730s and spread to Central Europe in the 1750s and 1760s.  It is often described as the final expression of the Baroque movement.The Rococo style began in France in the first part of the 18th century in the reign of Louis XV  as a reaction against the more formal and geometric Style Louis XIV. It was known as the style rocaille, or rocaille style. It soon spread to other parts of Europe, particularly northern Italy, Bavaria, Austria, other parts of Germany, and Russia. It also came to influence the other arts, particularly sculpture, furniture, silverware and glassware, painting,  music, and theatre.</description></style><style stylename="Late Baroque"><description>Englisch description: The Baroque (US /bəˈroʊk/ or UK /bəˈrɒk/) is often thought of as a period of artistic style that used exaggerated motion and clear, easily interpreted detail to produce drama, tension, exuberance, and grandeur in sculpture, painting, architecture, literature, dance, theater, and music. The style began around 1600 in Rome and Italy, and spread to most of Europe. The popularity and success of the Baroque style was encouraged by the Catholic Church, which had decided at the time of the Council of Trent, in response to the Protestant Reformation, that the arts should communicate religious themes in direct and emotional involvement. The aristocracy also saw the dramatic style of Baroque architecture and art as a means of impressing visitors and expressing triumph, power and control. Baroque palaces are built around an entrance of courts, grand staircases and reception rooms of sequentially increasing opulence. However, "baroque" has resonance and application that extend beyond a simple reduction to either style or period.</description></style><style stylename="Nazarene"><description>Englisch description: The epithet Nazarene was adopted by a group of early 19th century German Romantic painters who aimed to revive honesty and spirituality in Christian art. The name Nazarene came from a term of derision used against them for their affectation of a biblical manner of clothing and hair style.
</description></style><style stylename="art brut"><description>German description: Die Art brut (franz. [Aussprache: aʁ bʁyt] für „rohe Kunst“) ist ein Sammelbegriff für autodidaktische Kunst von Laien, Kindern, Menschen mit einer psychischen Erkrankung oder einer geistigen Behinderung. Die Bezeichnung ging vom französischen Maler Jean Dubuffet aus, der sich eingehend mit einer naiven und antiakademischen Ästhetik beschäftigte. Art brut beschreibt eine Kunst jenseits etablierter Formen und Strömungen. Im anglo-amerikanischen Sprachraum ist stattdessen der Begriff Outsider Art („Außenseiter-Kunst“) gebräuchlich.
</description></style><style stylename="Constructivism"><description>Englisch description: Constructivism was an artistic and architectural philosophy that originated in Russia beginning in 1913 by Vladimir Tatlin. This was a rejection of the idea of autonomous art. He wanted 'to construct' art. The movement was in favour of art as a practice for social purposes. Constructivism had a great effect on modern art movements of the 20th century, influencing major trends such as the Bauhaus and De Stijl movements. Its influence was widespread, with major effects upon architecture, sculpture, graphic design, industrial design, theatre, film, dance, fashion and to some extent music.
</description></style><style stylename="cubism"><description>Englisch description: Cubism is an early-20th-century avant-garde art movement that revolutionized European painting and sculpture, and inspired related movements in music, literature and architecture. Cubism has been considered the most influential art movement of the 20th century. The term is broadly used in association with a wide variety of art produced in Paris (Montmartre, Montparnasse, and Puteaux) during the 1910s and throughout the 1920s.
The movement was pioneered by Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque, joined by Jean Metzinger, Albert Gleizes, Robert Delaunay, Henri Le Fauconnier, and Fernand Léger. One primary influence that led to Cubism was the representation of three-dimensional form in the late works of Paul Cézanne. A retrospective of Cézanne's paintings had been held at the Salon d'Automne of 1904, current works were displayed at the 1905 and 1906 Salon d'Automne, followed by two commemorative retrospectives after his death in 1907. In Cubist artwork, objects are analyzed, broken up and reassembled in an abstracted form—instead of depicting objects from a single viewpoint, the artist depicts the subject from a multitude of viewpoints to represent the subject in a greater context.In France, offshoots of Cubism developed, including Orphism, Abstract art and later Purism. The impact of Cubism was far-reaching and wide-ranging. In other countries Futurism, Suprematism, Dada, Constructivism, De Stijl and Art Deco developed in response to Cubism. Early Futurist paintings hold in common with Cubism the fusing of the past and the present, the representation of different views of the subject pictured at the same time, also called multiple perspective, simultaneity or multiplicity, while Constructivism was influenced by Picasso's technique of constructing sculpture from separate elements. Other common threads between these disparate movements include the faceting or simplification of geometric forms, and the association of mechanization and modern life.
</description></style><style stylename="surrealism"><description>Englisch description: Surrealism is a cultural movement that began in the early 1920s, and is best known for its visual artworks and writings. Artists painted unnerving, illogical scenes with photographic precision, created strange creatures from everyday objects, and developed painting techniques that allowed the unconscious to express itself. Its aim was to "resolve the previously contradictory conditions of dream and reality into an absolute reality, a super-reality".Works of surrealism feature the element of surprise, unexpected juxtapositions and non sequitur; however, many surrealist artists and writers regard their work as an expression of the philosophical movement first and foremost, with the works being an artifact. Leader André Breton was explicit in his assertion that Surrealism was, above all, a revolutionary movement.
Surrealism developed out of the Dada activities during World War I and the most important center of the movement was Paris. From the 1920s onward, the movement spread around the globe, eventually affecting the visual arts, literature, film, and music of many countries and languages, as well as political thought and practice, philosophy, and social theory.
</description></style><style stylename="art photography"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="abstract sculpture"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="early Baroque"><description>No description</description></style></Allstyle></records>