<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<records>
		<AllPerson>
			<Artist name="Maes, Nicolaes">
				<description>German description: Nicolaes Maes (* Januar 1634 in Dordrecht; † vor 24. Dezember 1693 (beigesetzt) in Amsterdam) war ein holländischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schütz d. Ä., Christian Georg">
				<description>German description: Christian Georg Schütz der Ältere (* 24. September 1718 in Flörsheim am Main; † 3. Dezember 1791 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler und Kupferstecher.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deutscher Meister der zweiten Hälfte des 17. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hals, Frans">
				<description>German description: Frans Hals (* zwischen 1580 und 1585 in Antwerpen; † 10. August 1666 in Haarlem) war ein holländischer Maler. Er wird zu den bedeutendsten Porträtmalern gezählt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruysdael, Salomon van">
				<description>Englisch description: Salomon van Ruysdael (c. 1602, Naarden – buried November 3, 1670, Haarlem) was a Dutch Golden Age landscape painter. He was the uncle of Jacob van Ruisdael.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weenix, Jan">
				<description>German description: Jan Weenix (* 1642 in Amsterdam; † 20. September 1719 ebenda) war ein niederländischer Maler. Jan Weenix wusste nicht genau, wie alt er war. Als er 1679 in Amsterdam heiratete, behauptete er, er sei dreißig.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jordaens, Jacob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob Jordaens (19 May 1593 – 18 October 1678) was a Flemish painter, draughtsman and tapestry designer known for his history paintings, genre scenes and portraits. After Peter Paul Rubens and Anthony van Dyck, he was the leading Flemish Baroque painter of his day. Unlike those contemporaries he never travelled abroad to study Italian painting, and his career is marked by an indifference to their intellectual and courtly aspirations. In fact, except for a few short trips to locations in the Low Countries, he remained in Antwerp his entire life. As well as being a successful painter, he was a prominent designer of tapestries. Like Rubens, Jordaens painted altarpieces, mythological, and allegorical scenes, and after 1640—the year Rubens died—he was the most important painter in Antwerp for large-scale commissions and the status of his patrons increased in general. However, he is best known today for his numerous large genre scenes based on proverbs in the manner of his contemporary Jan Brueghel the Elder, depicting The King Drinks and As the Old Sing, So Pipe the Young. Jordaens' main artistic influences, besides Rubens and the Brueghel family, were northern Italian painters such as Jacopo Bassano, Paolo Veronese, and Caravaggio.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Velde, Adriaen van de">
				<description>Englisch description: Adriaen van de Velde (bapt. 30 November 1636, Amsterdam – bur. 21 January 1672, Amsterdam), was a Dutch animal and landscape painter, son of Willem van de Velde the Elder and brother of Willem van de Velde the Younger, the marine painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schalcken, Godfried">
				<description>German description: Godefridus Schalcken (* 1643 in Made bei Breda; † 16. November 1706 in Den Haag) war einer der führenden niederländischen Maler des späten 17. Jahrhunderts. In der Tradition der Leidener Feinmalerei schuf er äußerst illusionistische, minutiös gemalte Porträts, Genregemälde, biblische und mythologische Historien, vereinzelt auch Stillleben und Landschaften mit Staffage. Sein Markenzeichen war die Darstellung besonderer Lichteffekte, insbesondere des Kerzenscheins.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Keyser, Thomas de">
				<description>German description: Thomas de Keyser (* um 1596 in Amsterdam; begraben 7. Juni 1667 oder gestorben im November 1679 ebenda) war ein niederländischer Maler und Basaltsteinhändler. Der Sohn des Bildhauers Hendrick de Keyser war sein Leben lang als Maler, anfangs unter dem Einfluss von Dirck Hals und von Rembrandt van Rijn, in Amsterdam tätig. Obwohl über sein Leben und über seine Ausbildung wenig bekannt ist, gehört er mit Hals, Rembrandt und Bartholomeus van der Helst zu den ausgezeichnetsten Porträtmalern der holländischen Schule. Er verbindet außerordentliche Klarheit der Färbung und ein feines koloristisches Gefühl mit Energie der Auffassung und Schärfe der Zeichnung. Der Architekt Pieter de Keyser war sein Bruder.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Roos, Johann Heinrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Heinrich Roos (29 September 1631, Otterberg – 3 October 1685, Frankfurt) was a German Baroque era landscape painter and etcher.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Französischer Meister um 1550/1600">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Molenaer, Jan Miense">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Miense Molenaer (1610 – buried 19 September 1668), was a Dutch Golden Age genre painter whose style was a precursor to Jan Steen's work during Dutch Golden Age painting. He shared a studio with his wife, Judith Leyster, also a genre painter, as well as a portraitist and painter of still-life. Both Molenaer and Leyster may have been pupils of the successful Dutch painter, Frans Hals.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rubens, Peter Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Sir Peter Paul Rubens (/ˈruːbənz/; Dutch: [ˈrybə(n)s]; 28 June 1577 – 30 May 1640) was a Flemish Baroque painter. A proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality, Rubens is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces, portraits, landscapes, and history paintings of mythological and allegorical subjects. In addition to running a large studio in Antwerp that produced paintings popular with nobility and art collectors throughout Europe, Rubens was a classically educated humanist scholar and diplomat who was knighted by both Philip IV of Spain and Charles I of England. Rubens was a prolific artist. The catalogue of his works by Michael Jaffé lists 1,403 pieces, excluding numerous copies made in his workshop. His commissioned works were mostly "history paintings", which included religious and mythological subjects, and hunt scenes. He painted portraits, especially of friends, and self-portraits, and in later life painted several landscapes. Rubens designed tapestries and prints, as well as his own house. He also oversaw the ephemeral decorations of the royal entry into Antwerp by the Cardinal-Infante Ferdinand in 1635. His drawings are mostly extremely forceful but not overly detailed. He also made great use of oil sketches as preparatory studies. He was one of the last major artists to make consistent use of wooden panels as a support medium, even for very large works, but he used canvas as well, especially when the work needed to be sent a long distance. For altarpieces he sometimes painted on slate to reduce reflection problems.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Niederländischer Meister der zweiten Hälfte des 18. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Neer, Aert van der">
				<description>German description: Aert van der Neer (auch Aart oder Artus van der Neer; * 1603 oder 1604 in Gorinchem; † 9. November 1677 in Amsterdam) war ein niederländischer Landschaftsmaler. Seine Spezialität waren Landschaften im Winter und bei Nacht.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Steen, Jan">
				<description>German description: Jan Havickszoon Steen (* um 1626 in Leiden; begraben am 3. Februar 1679 in Leiden) war ein holländischer Maler, ein Meister des holländischen Genrebildes. Er wirkte in der Epoche des Goldenen Zeitalters der Niederlande, eine rund einhundert Jahre andauernde wirtschaftliche und kulturelle Blütezeit im 17. Jahrhundert, in der zahllose Meisterwerke der Malerei entstanden.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berckheyde, Job Andriesz">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruysch, Rachel">
				<description>Englisch description: Rachel Ruysch (3 June 1664 – 12 August 1750) was a still-life painter from the Northern Netherlands who specialized in flowers. She invented her own style and achieved international fame in her lifetime, being followed by Jan van Huysum who took flower painting to another degree of popularity. Due to her long and successful career that spanned over 6 decades, she became the best documented woman painter of the Dutch Golden Age.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pforr, Johann Georg">
				<description>German description: Johann Georg Pforr (* 14. Januar 1745 in Ulfen; † 9. Juni 1798 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein hessischer Maler der Goethezeit. Auf Grund seiner Spezialisierung auf die Pferdemalerei wurde er von seinen Zeitgenossen der deutsche Wouwerman genannt.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heyden, Jan van der">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan van der Heyden (5 March 1637, Gorinchem – 28 March 1712, Amsterdam) was a Dutch Baroque-era painter, glass painter, draughtsman and printmaker. Van der Heyden was one of the first Dutch painters to specialize in townscapes and became one of the leading architectural painters of the Dutch Golden Age. He painted a number of still lifes in the beginning and at the end of his career. Jan van der Heyden was also an engineer and inventor who made significant contributions to contemporary firefighting technology. He improved the fire hose in 1672, with his brother Nicolaes, who was a hydraulic engineer. He modified the manual fire engine, reorganised the volunteer fire brigade (1685) and wrote and illustrated the first firefighting manual (Brandspuiten-boek). A comprehensive street lighting scheme for Amsterdam, designed and implemented by van der Heyden, remained in operation from 1669 until 1840 and was adopted as a model by many other towns and abroad.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ochtervelt, Jacob">
				<description>German description: Jacob Lucasz Ochtervelt (* 1. Februar 1634 in Rotterdam; † 1682 in Amsterdam) war ein niederländischer Maler des Barock. Nach dem Kunsthistoriker Arnold Houbraken studierte Ochtervelt gemeinsam mit Pieter de Hooch vermutlich etwa zwischen 1646 und 1655 bei Nicolaes Berchem. 1655 heiratete Ochtervelt Dirkje Meesters in der niederländisch-reformierten Kirche in Rotterdam. Zahlreiche seiner Bilder sind heute in international renommierten Museen zu sehen.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Walscapelle, Jacob van">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacob van Walscapelle (1644, Dordrecht – 1727, Amsterdam), was a Dutch Golden Age flower painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Poelenburch, Cornelis van">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bega, Cornelis Pietersz">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis Pietersz Bega, or Cornelis Pietersz Begijn (1631/32 – 27 August 1664) was a Dutch Golden Age painter and engraver. Bega was born, lived and worked in Haarlem shake and was the son of sculptor and goldsmith Pieter Jansz. Begijn. His mother Maria was the illegitimate daughter of the Haarlem painter Cornelis van Haarlem. He assumed the name Bega when he started working professionally. He was a student of Adriaen van Ostade, and produced genre scenes of similar subjects, typically groups of a few peasant figures, often in interior settings, or fanciful figures such as The Alchemist (Malibu) or The Astrologer (London). From 1653 to 1654 he traveled by horse and boat on a Grand Tour with fellow painters Dirk Helmbreker, Vincent van der Vinne and Guillam Dubois through Germany, Switzerland and France. This trip was recorded in Vincent van der Vinne's diaries and gives an accurate view of the art in the cities they visited in those times. His dated works begin in 1652, and in 1654 he was accepted into the Haarlem Guild of St. Luke, dying only ten years later, which according to Houbraken was due to the plague. He was close friends with the Haarlem painter Leendert van der Cooghen. When he died he was buried in the grave of his grandfather Cornelis van Haarlem.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ermels, Johann Franciscus">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Verspronck, Jan Cornelisz.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heem, Cornelis de">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis de Heem (8 April 1631 (baptized) – 17 May 1695 (buried) ) was a still-life painter associated with both Flemish Baroque and Dutch Golden Age painting. He was a member of a large family of still-life specialists, of which his father, Jan Davidszoon de Heem (1606–1684), was the most significant. Cornelis was baptised in Leiden on 8 April 1631, and moved with his family to Antwerp in 1636. He appears to have been trained by his father in Antwerp, who, like him, was born in the Dutch Republic but died in the Southern Netherlands. Jan's subsequent career, like many painters—especially after the Peace of Westphalia in 1648—moved fluidly between the two traditionally-connected areas of the north and south Low Countries. He became a member of the Antwerp painters' guild in 1660, and from 1667 until the late 1680s he was variously active in Utrecht, IJsselstein, and The Hague. It is often not easy to distinguish the works of the different members of the family, which included his brother Jan Jansz., nephew Jan Jansz. II, and son David Cornelisz. (1663–after? 1718), who all painted mostly flower and fruit pieces in a similar style and probably often collaborated. Cornelis's works, however, tend to be small, display a preference for strong blues, and, over time, shifted away from the painterly style preferred by his father. He died in Antwerp, aged 64. 
*       
*       
*       
*       
* Pageantry Still Life with copulating sparrows, 1657, Städelsches Kunstinstitut</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ruisdael, Jacob Isaacksz. van">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Teniers d. Ä., David">
				<description>German description: David Teniers  der Ältere (* 1582 in Antwerpen; † 29. Juli 1649 ebenda) war ein flämischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vos, Cornelis de">
				<description>Englisch description: Cornelis de Vos (1584 – 9 May 1651) was a Flemish painter, draughtsman and art dealer. He was one of the leading portrait painters in Antwerp and is best known for his sensitive portraits, in particular of children and families. He was also successful in other genres including history, religious and genre painting. He was a regular collaborator with Rubens.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Massys, Quentin">
				<description>German description: Quentin Massys (als Vorname ist auch Quinten oder Kwinten, als Nachname Massijs, Matsijs, Matsys oder Metsys überliefert) (* ca. 1466 in Löwen; † 1530 in Antwerpen) war ein flämischer Maler und Medailleur und Mitbegründer der Antwerpener Malerschule.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hobbema, Meindert">
				<description>Englisch description: Meindert Hobbema (bapt. October 31, 1638 – December 7, 1709) was a Dutch Golden Age landscape painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Barnaba da Modena">
				<description>German description: Barnaba da Modena (* um 1328/1330 in Modena; † nach 1386) war ein italienischer Maler. Barnaba da Modena arbeitete vermutlich in Ligurien und Piemont. Er malte hauptsächlich im venezianisch-byzantinischen Stil, der ihm besonders vertraut war. Er blieb seinem Stil bis zu seinem letzten Werk, dem Fresko Das jüngste Gericht in der Kirche St. Agostino in Genua, welches noch vollkommen byzantinisch geprägt ist, treu.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lochner, Stefan">
				<description>Englisch description: Stefan Lochner (the Dombild Master or Master Stefan) (c. 1410–1451) was a German painter working in the late "soft style" of the International Gothic. His paintings combine that era's tendency towards long flowing lines and brilliant colours with the realism, virtuoso surface textures and innovative iconography of the early Northern Renaissance. Based in Cologne, a commercial and artistic hub of northern Europe, Lochner was one of the most important German painters before Albrecht Dürer. Extant works include single panel oil paintings, devotional polyptychs and illuminated manuscripts, which often feature fanciful and dark blue winged angels. Today some thirty-seven individual panels are attributed to him with confidence. Less is known of his life. Art historians associating the Dombild Master with the historical Stefan Lochner believe he was born in Meersburg in south-west Germany around 1410, and that he spent some of his apprenticeship in the Low Countries. Records indicate that his career developed quickly but was cut short by an early death. We know that he was commissioned around 1442 by the Cologne council to provide decorations for the visit of Emperor Frederick III, a major city occasion. Records from the following years indicate growing wealth and the purchase of a number of properties around the city. Thereafter he seems to have over-extended his finances and fallen into debt. Plague hit Cologne in 1451 and there, apart from the records of creditors, mention of Stephan Lochner ends; it is presumed he died that year, aged around 40. Lochner's identity and reputation were lost until a revival of 15th century art during the early 19th century romantic period. Despite extensive historical research, attribution remains difficult; for centuries a number of associated works were grouped and loosely attributed to the notname the Dombild Master, a name taken from the Dombild Altarpiece (in English cathedral picture, also known as the Altarpiece of the City's Patron Saints) still in Cologne Cathedral. One of Dürer's diary entries became key, 400 years later, in the 20th century establishment of Lochner's identity. Only two attributed works are dated, and none are signed. His influence on successive generations of northern artists was substantial. Apart from the many direct copies made in the later 15th century, echoes of his panels can be seen in works by Rogier van der Weyden and Hans Memling. Lochner's work was praised by Friedrich Schlegel and Goethe for its qualities, especially the "sweetness and grace" of his Madonnas.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Catena, Vincenzo">
				<description>German description: Vincenzo Catena (* um 1470/80 wahrscheinlich in Venedig; † zwischen dem 10. und 29. September 1531 ebenda; auch Vincenzo di Biagio) war ein italienischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jacopo del Casentino">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacopo del Casentino (c. 1297 – 1358) was an Italian painter, active mainly in Tuscany in the first half of the 14th century.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Perugino, Pietro">
				<description>Englisch description: Pietro Perugino (Italian: [ˈpjɛːtro peruˈdʒiːno]; c. 1446/1452 – 1523), born Pietro Vannucci, was an Italian Renaissance painter of the Umbrian school, who developed some of the qualities that found classic expression in the High Renaissance. Raphael was his most famous pupil.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der Stalburg-Bildnisse&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weyden, Rogier van der">
				<description>German description: Rogier van der Weyden, ehemals Rogier de la Pasture (* 1399/1400 in Tournai, in der damals zum Königreich Frankreich gehörenden Stadt in Flandern; † 18. Juni 1464 in Brüssel, damals Hauptstadt des Herzogtums Burgund), war ein flämischer Maler und gilt als einer der wichtigsten Vertreter der Altniederländischen Malerei.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Achenbach, Andreas">
				<description>German description: Andreas Achenbach (* 29. September 1815 in Kassel; † 1. April 1910 in Düsseldorf) war ein deutscher Landschaftsmaler der Romantik. Er wird der Düsseldorfer Malerschule zugerechnet. Thema seiner Landschaftsmalereien waren vor allem Seestücke. Sein Bruder Oswald Achenbach dagegen konzentrierte sich auf die Darstellung der Landschaft Italiens. Die beiden Brüder wurden deshalb auch scherzhaft als das „A und O der Landschaftsmalerei“ bezeichnet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Netscher, Caspar">
				<description>German description: Caspar Netscher (* 1639 in Heidelberg; † 15. Januar 1684 in Den Haag) war ein Porträt- und Genremaler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dürer, Albrecht">
				<description>Englisch description: Albrecht Dürer (/ˈdʊərər, ˈdjʊərər/; German: [ˈalbʁɛçt ˈdyːʁɐ]; 21 May 1471 – 6 April 1528) was a painter, printmaker and theorist of the German Renaissance. Born in Nuremberg, Dürer established his reputation and influence across Europe when he was still in his twenties, due to his high-quality woodcut prints.He was in communication with the major Italian artists of his time, including Raphael, Giovanni Bellini and Leonardo da Vinci, and from 1512 he was patronized by emperor Maximilian I. His vast body of work includes engravings, his preferred technique in his later prints, altarpieces, portraits and self-portraits, watercolours and books. The woodcuts, such as the Apocalypse series (1498), retain a more Gothic flavour than the rest of his work. His well-known engravings include the Knight, Death, and the Devil (1513), Saint Jerome in his Study (1514) and Melencolia I (1514), which has been the subject of extensive analysis and interpretation. His watercolours also mark him as one of the first European landscape artists, while his ambitious woodcuts revolutionized the potential of that medium. Dürer's introduction of classical motifs into Northern art, through his knowledge of Italian artists and German humanists, has secured his reputation as one of the most important figures of the Northern Renaissance. This is reinforced by his theoretical treatises, which involve principles of mathematics, perspective and ideal proportions.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carracci">
				<description>Englisch description: The Carracci were a family of Italian artists. Notable members include:


Agostino Carracci (1557–1602), Italian painter and printmaker
Annibale Carracci (1560–1609), Italian Baroque painter and brother of Agostino Carracci
Ludovico Carracci (1555–1619), Italian painter, etcher, printmaker, and cousin of Agostino and Annibale Carracci
Antonio Marziale Carracci (1583–1618), Italian painter and son of Agostino Carracci
Francesco Carracci (1595–1622), Italian painter and engraver, nephew of Agostino Carracci
Baldassare Aloisi (1578–1638), painter and engraver whose mother, Elena Zenzanini, was a cousin of Agostino and Annibale Carracci
Giovanni Francesco Grimaldi (1606–1680), painter, whose common law wife was Aloisi's daughter</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Veronese, Paolo">
				<description>Englisch description: Paolo Caliari, known as Paolo Veronese (1528–1588), was an Italian Renaissance painter, based in Venice, known for large-format history paintings of religion and mythology, such as The Wedding at Cana(1563) and The Feast in the House of Levi (1573). Included with Titian, a generation older, and Tintoretto, a decade senior, Veronese of the “great trio that dominated Venetian painting of the cinquecento” and the Late Renaissance in the 16th century. Known as a supreme colorist, and after an early period with Mannerism, Paolo Veronese developed naturalist style of painting, influenced by Titian. His most famous works are elaborate narrative cycles, executed in a dramatic and colorful style, full of majestic architectural settings and glittering pageantry. His large paintings of biblical feasts, crowded with figures, painted for the refectories of monasteries in Venice and Verona are especially famous, and he was also the leading Venetian painter of ceilings. Most of these works remain in situ, or at least in Venice, and his representation in most museums is mainly composed of smaller works such as portraits that do not always show him at his best or most typical. He has always been appreciated for "the chromatic brilliance of his palette, the splendor and sensibility of his brushwork, the aristocratic elegance of his figures, and the magnificence of his spectacle", but his work has been felt "not to permit expression of the profound, the human, or the sublime", and of the "great trio" he has often been the least appreciated by modern criticism. Nonetheless, "many of the greatest artists ... may be counted among his admirers, including Rubens, Watteau, Tiepolo, Delacroix and Renoir".</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schadow, Wilhelm von">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lessing, Carl Friedrich">
				<description>German description: Carl Friedrich Lessing (* 15. Februar 1808 in Breslau; † 5. Juni 1880 in Karlsruhe) war ein romantischer Maler des 19. Jahrhunderts. Er zählt zu den bedeutendsten Historien- und Landschaftsmalern der Düsseldorfer Schule.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Becker, Jakob">
				<description>German description: Jakob Becker (* 15. März 1810 in Dittelsheim bei Worms; † 22. Dezember 1872 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler, Radierer und Lithograf.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schwind, Moritz von">
				<description>German description: Moritz Ludwig von Schwind (* 21. Januar 1804 in Wien; † 8. Februar 1871 in Niederpöcking, Oberbayern) war ein österreichischer Maler und Zeichner der Spätromantik.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moretto da Brescia">
				<description>German description: Alessandro Moretto (* um 1490 oder 1498 in Brescia; † Dezember 1554 ebenda) war ein italienischer Maler und Freskant.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Franchoys II, Lucas">
				<description>Englisch description: From an alternative name: This is a redirect from a title that is another name such as a pseudonym, a nickname, or a synonym of the target, or of a name associated with the target.
This redirect leads to the title in accordance with the naming conventions for common names to aid searches and writing.  It is not necessary to replace these redirected links with a piped link.
If this redirect is an incorrect name for the target, then {{R from incorrect name}} should have been used instead.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bol, Ferdinand">
				<description>German description: Ferdinand Bo(e)l (* 1616 in Dordrecht; † 24. August 1680 in Amsterdam) war ein niederländischer Maler biblischer Szenen und Selbstporträts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Beham, Barthel">
				<description>Englisch description: Barthel Beham (or Bartel) (1502–1540) was a German engraver, miniaturist and painter. The younger brother of Hans Sebald Beham, he was born into a family of artists in Nuremberg. Learning his art from his elder brother, and Albrecht Dürer, he was particularly active as an engraver during the 1520s, creating tiny works of magnificent detail, positioning him in the German printmaking school known as the "Little Masters". He was also fascinated with antiquity and may have worked with Marcantonio Raimondi in Bologna and Rome at some time in his career. In 1525, along with his brother and Georg Pencz, the so-called "godless painters", he was banished from Lutheran Nuremberg for asserting his disbelief in baptism, Christ, or transubstantiation. Although later pardoned, he moved to Catholic Munich to work for the Bavarian dukes William IV and Ludwig X. Whilst there, his exceptional talent established him as one of Germany's principal portrait painters, favoured by distinguished patrons such as Emperor Charles V. According to Joachim von Sandrart, he died in Italy during a trip under the patronage of Duke William.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Christus, Petrus">
				<description>Englisch description: Petrus Christus (c. 1410/1420 – 1475/1476) was an Early Netherlandish painter active in Bruges from 1444, where, along with Hans Memling, he became the leading painter after the death of Jan van Eyck. He was influenced by van Eyck and Rogier van der Weyden and is noted for his innovations with linear perspective and a meticulous technique which seems derived from miniatures and manuscript illumination. Today, some 30 works are confidently attributed to him. The best-known include the 1446 Portrait of a Carthusian and c. 1470 Berlin Portrait of a Young Girl, both are highly innovative in presentation of the figure against detailed, rather than flat, backgrounds. Christus was an anonymous figure for centuries, his importance not established until the work of modern art historians. Giorgio Vasari barely mentions him in his biographies of painters, written in the Renaissance, and near contemporary records merely list him amongst many others. In the early to mid-nineteenth century, Gustav Waagen (who identified him in Francophile language as "Pierre Christophsen") and Johann David Passavant were important in establishing Christus's biographical details and in attributing works to him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rosso Fiorentino">
				<description>Englisch description: Giovanni Battista di Jacopo (8 March 1495 in Gregorian style, or 1494 according to the calculation of times in Florence where the year began on 25 March – 14 November 1540), known as Rosso Fiorentino (meaning "red Florentine" in Italian), or Il Rosso, was an Italian Mannerist painter, in oil and fresco, belonging to the Florentine school.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Garofalo">
				<description>Englisch description: Garofalo may refer to:

</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Savery, Roelant">
				<description>German description: Roelant Savery war Schüler seines Bruders Jakob zu Amsterdam, bildete sich daneben aber auch nach Jan Brueghel dem Älteren, machte Reisen in der Begleitung Kaiser Rudolfs II., hielt sich zwei Jahre in den Alpen auf und wurde 1619 in die Lukasgilde von Utrecht aufgenommen, wo er 1639 starb. Er malte zahlreiche, mit Menschen und Tieren reich staffierte Landschaften von großartiger Auffassung. Bilder von ihm befinden sich in den Galerien in Prag (Paradies, 1618), Wien, Berlin (Orpheus und die Tiere), Wiesbaden, Den Haag, Utrecht, Petersburg, Dresden und München.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Neroccio di Bartolomeo di Benedetto de' Landi">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ramboux, Johann Anton">
				<description>German description: Johann Anton Alban Ramboux (* 5. Oktober 1790 in Trier; † 2. Oktober 1866 in Köln) war ein deutscher Maler und Lithograf.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Olivier, Ferdinand">
				<description>German description: Johann Heinrich Ferdinand Olivier, gen. der Jüngere (* 1. April 1785 in Dessau; † 11. Februar 1841 in München) war ein deutscher Maler und Grafiker. Künstlerisch stand er den Nazarenern nahe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Paolo di Giovanni Fei">
				<description>German description: Paolo di Giovanni Fei (* 1345 wahrscheinlich in San Quirico d’Orcia; † 1411 in Siena) war ein italienischer Maler der Schule von Siena.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Niccolò di Buonaccorso">
				<description>Englisch description: Very little is known about this painter. It is believed his father was the painter Buonaccorso di Pace (fl c. 1348–c. 1362). In 1355 Niccolò di Buonaccorso enrolled in the Guild of Sienese painters. In May and June 1372 and in March and April 1376 the artist served in the government of Siena. In 1381 he was elected honorary Gonfaloniere in the parish of San Martino. Niccolò di Buonaccorso was commissioned to paint the capello over the high altar of Siena Cathedral in 1376 and a panel of the prophet Daniel for an altar in the Cathedral in 1383.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tiepolo, Giovanni Domenico">
				<description>German description: Giovanni Domenico Tiepolo (auch Giandomenico Tiepolo, * 30. August 1727 in Venedig; † 3. März 1804 in Venedig) war ein italienischer Maler des Barock. Giovanni Domenico Tiepolo war der älteste Sohn Giovanni Battista Tiepolos. Er war, wie auch sein jüngerer Bruder Lorenzo, Schüler, Gehilfe und Stecher in der Werkstatt seines Vaters. Später wurde er zunehmend gleichberechtigter Mitarbeiter, blieb gleichwohl lange Nachahmer seines berühmten Vaters, bis er 1747 im Oratorium von San Polo mit 14 Leinwänden zu den Stationen des Kreuzweges sein Debüt als selbstständiger Maler hatte. Diese kleinformatigen Darstellungen sind von historischem Interesse, weil in der Zeit ihrer Entstehung Christi Weg zum Kreuz in Rom zu einer besonderen Andachtsform erhoben wurde, und weil Domenicos Zyklus der erste dieser Art in Venedig war. Andere eigenständige Arbeiten gibt es im Kaisersaal und im Treppenhaus der Würzburger Residenz, wo er seinem Vater in den Jahren 1750 bis 1753 half. Mit den Szenen aus dem ländlichen Leben im Gästehaus der Villa Valmarana ai Nani bei Vicenza entwickelte Domenico Tiepolo schließlich einen wirklich eigenen Stil. Auch um die Villa seiner Familie in Zianigo, Ortsteil der Gemeinde Mirano, auszuschmücken, nutzte der Künstler seine eigentliche Begabung zur Darstellung der alltäglichen Wirklichkeit. Er schuf dort faszinierende Dekorationen zu Genrethemen, die sich heute im Museo Correr befinden, zum Beispiel das Gemälde Pulcinella und Saltimbanchi. Nach dem Tode seines Vaters in Madrid kehrte Domenico Tiepolo Ende 1770 nach Venedig zurück. In den 30 Jahren, die ihm verblieben, schuf er vornehmlich säkulare und religiöse Bilder. Er führte zwar den Stil seines Vaters fort, gab ihm aber eine andere Qualität, so zum Beispiel in dem Bild Abraham und die drei Engel. Die Genre- und Landschaftsdetails und der bäuerliche Abraham sind Elemente, die in Giambattistas religiösen Werken nicht zu finden sind. Zu Tiepolos Werk zählen auch zahlreiche Radierungen. Gegen Ende des Jahrhunderts gewann die Zeichnung bei ihm eine neue, bildmäßige Eigenständigkeit. Neben der Bearbeitung religiöser Themen wandte er sich dabei zunehmend Darstellungen aus den Salons und von den Freizeitvergnügungen der venezianischen Gesellschaft zu. Höhepunkt ist die berühmte Serie, in der er den Alltag seiner Zeit in die Welt Pulcinellas, der verschlagenen Dienerfigur der Commedia dell’arte, übertrug.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brouwer, Adriaen">
				<description>German description: Adriaen Brouwer (* 1605 oder 1606 wahrscheinlich in Oudenaarde, Belgien; † vor 1. Februar 1638 in Antwerpen) war ein flämischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Heem, Jan Davidsz. de">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Davidsz. de Heem or in-full Jan Davidszoon de Heem, also called Johannes de Heem or Johannes van Antwerpen (c. 17 April 1606, Utrecht – before 26 April 1684, Antwerp), was a still life painter who was active in Utrecht and Antwerp. He is a major representative of that genre in both Dutch and Flemish Baroque painting.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Velázquez, Diego">
				<description>German description: Diego Velázquez (vollständiger Name Diego Rodríguez de Silva y Velázquez, getauft 6. Juni 1599 in Sevilla; † 6. August 1660 in Madrid) war ein spanischer Maler des Barock, der zu den wichtigsten Porträtmalern seiner Zeit gehörte. Als Maler am Hof des spanischen Königs Philipp IV. porträtierte er zahlreiche Mitglieder der königlichen Familie und Angehörige des Hofes. Velázquez hat zahlreiche kunsthistorisch bedeutsame Gemälde geschaffen. Das wahrscheinlich bekannteste Bild von seiner Hand ist Las Meninas aus dem Jahre 1656. Seit dem frühen 19. Jahrhundert war Velázquez' Werk Vorbild für zahlreiche Maler, seine Gemälde beeinflussten unter anderem Francisco de Goya, den Impressionisten Édouard Manet. Maler des 20. Jahrhunderts, wie Pablo Picasso, Francis Bacon und Salvador Dalí, zollten Velázquez ihren Respekt, indem sie seine Gemälde malerisch neu interpretierten.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berckheyde, Gerrit Adriaensz.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Borch d. J., Gerard ter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Weenix, Jan Baptist">
				<description>Englisch description: Jan Baptist Weenix (1621–1660?) was a painter of the Dutch Golden Age. Despite his relatively brief career, he was a very productive and versatile painter. His favourite subjects were Italian landscapes with large figures among ruins, seaside views, and, later in life, large still life pictures of dead game or dogs. He was mainly responsible for introducing the Italian harbour scene into Dutch art, in mid-size paintings with a group of figures in the foreground.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stevens, Pieter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Holbein d. J., Hans">
				<description>German description: Hans Holbein der Jüngere (* 1497 oder 1498 wahrscheinlich in Augsburg; † 29. November 1543 in London) war ein deutscher Maler. Auf einem Selbstbildnis, das er kurz vor seinem Tod malte, bezeichnet er sich selbst als Basler, das Zunft- und Bürgerrecht der Stadt Basel hatte er 1519 erhalten. Er zählt zu den bedeutendsten Renaissance-Malern.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cranach d. Ä., Lucas">
				<description>Englisch description: From the same page name with diacritics: This is a redirect from a page name that has diacritical marks (accents, umlauts, etc.) to essentially the same page name without those marks or a "List of..." page anchored to a promising list item name without diacritics.
Apply this redirect (without piping) when the subject page concerns language translation or foreign language equivalents.  Other pages that use this redirect should be updated with a direct link to the redirect target (again, without piping).
Sort these redirects with {{DEFAULTSORT:(title without diacritics)}} and be sure to use a colon ( : ) rather than a pipe ( | ) to access the magic word directly.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goyen, Jan van">
				<description>German description: Jan Josephszoon van Goyen (* 13. Januar 1596 in Leiden; † 27. April 1656 in Den Haag) war ein niederländischer Landschaftsmaler. Neben Salomon van Ruysdael und Pieter de Molyn gilt Jan van Goyen als Hauptvertreter der sogenannten tonalen Landschaftsmalerei, die sich in den späten zwanziger Jahren des 17. Jahrhunderts entwickelte. Seine Hauptwerke bestechen durch sichere und spannungsgeladene, perspektivische Diagonalen gegen die Waagerechte des Horizonts ausspielende Kompositionen. Diese, sowie sein in den reiferen Werken sparsamer Farbauftrag, das Einbeziehen des durchscheinenden Malgrundes und seine Beschränkung auf eine fast monochrome Palette, machen seine Bilder auch in der unglaublichen Fülle hervorragender holländischer Landschaftsmalerei des 17. Jahrhunderts unverwechselbar.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fiorenzo di Lorenzo">
				<description>German description: Fiorenzo di Lorenzo (* um 1440 in Perugia; † 1522 ebenda) war ein italienischer Maler. Er wird der Umbrischen Schule zugerechnet, ein im Perugia seiner Zeit typischen Malstil der italienischen Renaissance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dou, Gerrit">
				<description>Englisch description: Gerrit Dou (7 April 1613 – 9 February 1675), also known as Gerard and Douw or Dow, was a Dutch Golden Age painter, whose small, highly polished paintings are typical of the Leiden fijnschilders. He specialised in genre scenes and is noted for his trompe l'oeil "niche" paintings and candlelit night-scenes with strong chiaroscuro. He was a student of Rembrandt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="David, Gerard">
				<description>German description: Gerard David (* um 1460 in Oudewater bei Gouda; † 13. August 1523 in Brügge) war ein altniederländischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Richter, Ludwig">
				<description>German description: Adrian Ludwig Richter (* 28. September 1803 in Dresden; † 19. Juni 1884 ebenda) war ein bedeutender Maler und Zeichner der Spätromantik und des Biedermeiers.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Reni, Guido">
				<description>German description: Guido Reni (* 4. November 1575 in Calvenzano; † 18. August 1642 in Bologna) war ein italienischer Maler und Radierer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Clouet, François">
				<description>Englisch description: François Clouet (c. 1510 – 22 December 1572), son of Jean Clouet, was a French Renaissance miniaturist and painter, particularly known for his detailed portraits of the French ruling family.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brueghel d. Ä., Jan">
				<description>German description: Jan Brueghel der Ältere [ˈbɾøːɣəl] (* 1568 in Brüssel; † 13. Januar 1625 in Antwerpen), auch genannt Samtbrueghel oder Blumenbrueghel, war ein erfolgreicher flämischer Maler und als Sohn Pieter Brueghel des Älteren (genannt Bauernbrueghel) und jüngerer Bruder Pieter Brueghel des Jüngeren war er Teil der Maler-Dynastie Brueghel.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Veit, Philipp">
				<description>German description: Philipp Veit (* 13. Februar 1793 in Berlin; † 18. Dezember 1877 in Mainz) war ein deutscher Maler, der Richtung der Nazarener angehörend.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tizian">
				<description>German description: Tizian (eigentlich Tiziano Vecellio, wahrscheinlich * um 1488 bis 1490 in Pieve di Cadore bei Belluno, damals Grafschaft Cadore; † 27. August 1576 in Venedig) gilt als der führende Vertreter der venezianischen Malerei des 16. Jahrhunderts und einer der Hauptmeister der italienischen Hochrenaissance. Zu Lebzeiten wurde er oft nach seinem Geburtsort Da Cadore genannt.
Sein Schaffen fiel in das Goldene Zeitalter der venezianischen Malerei, als die Serenissima ihre wirtschaftliche und kulturelle Blütezeit erlebte. Schon als neunjähriges Kind kam Tizian nach Venedig und wurde von den Brüdern Gentile und Giovanni Bellini ausgebildet. 1513 eröffnete er in San Samuele seine eigene Werkstatt und entwickelte sich zu einem europaweit gefeierten Künstler. 1533 wurde er von Kaiser Karl V. in den Adelsstand erhoben und zu dessen Hofmaler ernannt. 1545 reiste Tizian auf Einladung von Papst Paul III. nach Rom, 1548 und 1550 begleitete er Karl V. sowie dessen Sohn Philipp II. auf die Reichstage zu Augsburg. Als Tizian in hohem Alter 1576 an der Pest starb, war er der wohl erfolgreichste Maler der venezianischen Geschichte.
Von seinen Zeitgenossen als „die Sonne unter den Sternen“ bezeichnet, war Tizian einer der vielseitigsten und mit insgesamt 646 Werken auch produktivsten italienischen Maler seiner Zeit. Er malte sowohl Porträts als auch Landschaften, mythologische und religiöse Themen. Zu seinen bekanntesten Arbeiten zählen Himmlische und irdische Liebe, Mariä Verkündigung, Madonna der Familie Pesaro, Venus von Urbino und Toilette der Venus. Charakteristisch für seine Werke ist sein ausgeprägter Kolorismus, den er sein Leben lang beibehielt.
Gegen Ende seines langen Lebens vollzog er dann einen drastischen Stilbruch, der bereits zum Barock hinführt und den viele Kunsthistoriker als eine Rückkehr zu sich selbst sehen.
Bereits zu Lebzeiten waren Tizians Werke in allen wichtigen Sammlungen vertreten, wie etwa in den Vatikanischen Museen. Auch die Herrscherfamilien der Hocharistokratie, unter anderem die d’Este, Gonzaga, Farnese und die Habsburger, kauften zahlreiche Werke für ihre Sammlungen auf. Tizians Werke wurden, ebenso noch zu Lebzeiten, durch etliche Stiche und Kopien rezipiert. Namhafte Maler des 16. Jahrhunderts wie Lambert Sustris oder Jacopo Tintoretto wurden stark von Tizian beeinflusst. Seine Malweise und besonders seine Farbgebung sollten aber nicht nur auf seine Zeitgenossen, sondern auch auf zukünftige Generationen von Malern einen starken Einfluss haben. Der Bogen der von ihm beeinflussten Maler spannt sich dabei von Peter Paul Rubens über Antoine Watteau bis hin zu Eugène Delacroix.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kraus, Georg Melchior">
				<description>Englisch description: Georg Melchior Kraus (26 July 1737, in Frankfurt am Main – 5 November 1806, in Weimar) was a German painter. A student of Johann Heinrich Tischbein, he was also a teacher himself (his pupils included Ferdinand Jagemann), as well as an entrepreneur and friend of Goethe. He was a co-founder of the Fürstliche freie Zeichenschule Weimar with Friedrich Justin Bertuch in 1776.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bronzino, Agnolo">
				<description>German description: Agnolo di Cosimo di Mariano, auch Agnolo Tori, genannt Bronzino, (* 17. November 1503 in Monticelli, einem heutigen Stadtteil von Florenz; † 23. November 1572 in Florenz) war ein italienischer Maler des Manierismus.
Bronzino war ein Maler von Fresken, Altarbildern, Andachtsbildern und allegorischen und mythologischen Szenen. Er zeichnete sich jedoch vor allem als hervorragender Porträtmaler aus. Wie im Falle Raffaels konnten seine Werke durch die neuen Möglichkeiten der Druckgraphik verbreitet werden.
Bronzino war ein sehr gebildeter und belesener Maler, der die Werke der großen humanistischen Autoren des Jahrhunderts, wie zum Beispiel Dante, Pietro Bembo oder Petrarca gut kannte. Er war Autor von Gedichten und Mitglied der Florentiner Akademie.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fries, Ernst">
				<description>Englisch description: Ernst Fries (22 June 1801 – 11 October 1833) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vermeer, Johannes">
				<description>German description: Jan Vermeer van Delft (getauft 31. Oktober 1632 in Delft; begraben 15. Dezember 1675 in Delft; zeitgenössisch Joannis ver Meer, Joannis van der Meer) ist einer der bekanntesten holländischen Maler des Barock. Er wirkte in der Epoche des Goldenen Zeitalters der Niederlande, in der das Land eine politische, wirtschaftliche und kulturelle Blütezeit erlebte. Der Umfang des Gesamtwerkes von Jan Vermeer ist mit heute bekannten 37 Bildern sehr klein, wobei aus alten Auktionsaufzeichnungen weitere Titel überliefert sind. Die ersten Werke Vermeers waren Historienbilder, bekannt geworden ist er jedoch für seine Genreszenen, die einen Großteil seiner Arbeiten ausmachen. Die bekanntesten Werke sind durch die heutige Rezeption die Ansicht von Delft und Das Mädchen mit dem Perlenohrgehänge. Aufgrund der geringen Zahl bekannter Bilder wurden ihm im 19. Jahrhundert, einer Zeit gestiegenen Interesses der Forschung über Jan Vermeer und sein Werk, fälschlicherweise Bilder anderer Künstler zugeschrieben. Heute ist sein Werkumfang jedoch von der Forschung allgemein anerkannt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Feuerbach, Anselm">
				<description>German description: Anselm Feuerbach (* 12. September 1829 in Speyer; † 4. Januar 1880 in Venedig) war ein deutscher Maler. Er gehört zu den bedeutendsten deutschen Malern der zweiten Hälfte des 19. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morgenstern, Carl">
				<description>German description: Carl Morgenstern (* 25. Oktober 1811 in Frankfurt am Main; † 10. Januar 1893 ebenda) war ein deutscher Landschaftsmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Burnham-Meister&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Florentiner Meister um 1480">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baldung Grien, Hans">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deger, Ernst">
				<description>German description: Ernst Deger (* 15. April 1809 in Bockenem bei Hildesheim; † 27. Januar 1885 in Düsseldorf) war ein deutscher Maler. Durch seine im Stil der Nazarener gehaltenen religiösen Gemälde gilt er als ein Hauptvertreter der Düsseldorfer Malerschule auf dem Gebiet der christlichen Kunst.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Zick, Januarius">
				<description>German description: Johann Rasso Januarius Zick (* 6. Februar 1730 in München; † 14. November 1797 in Ehrenbreitstein, heute Stadtteil von Koblenz) war ein deutscher Maler und Architekt. Er gilt als Hauptmeister der deutschen Malerei des Spätbarocks.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nattier, Jean-Marc">
				<description>German description: Jean-Marc Nattier (* 17. März 1685 in Paris; † 7. November 1766 ebenda) war ein französischer Maler des Rokoko. Auf der Höhe seiner Karriere war er galanter Maler der Damen der Hofgesellschaft Ludwigs XV.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Willebeeck, Peter">
				<description>Englisch description: Peter Willebeeck or Petrus Willebeeck (fl. 1632–1648) was a Flemish still life painter who was active in Antwerp in the second quarter of the 17th century. He is known for his fruit still lifes, vanitas still lifes, pronkstillevens and banquet pieces executed in a very delicate manner.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brueghel d. J., Jan">
				<description>German description: Jan Brueghel der Jüngere [ˈbɾøːɣəl] (* 13. September 1601 in Antwerpen; † 1. September 1678 ebenda) war ein flämischer Landschafts-, Blumen- und Tiermaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Teniers d. J., David">
				<description>German description: David Teniers (getauft 15. Dezember 1610 in Antwerpen; † 25. April 1690 in Brüssel) war ein flämischer Maler, Zeichner und Kurator. Er war ein äußerst vielseitiger Künstler, der für seine umfangreich Produktion bekannt ist. Er war ein Erneuerer
in einer Vielzahl von Genres wie Historienmalerei, Genremalerei, Landschaft, Porträt und Stillleben. Er ist heute am meisten erinnert als der führende flämische Genremaler seiner Zeit. Teniers ist besonders bekannt für die Entwicklung des Bauerngenres, der Schenkstubenszene, Bilder von Kunstsammlungen und Szenen mit Alchimisten und Ärzten.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mieris d. Ä., Frans van">
				<description>German description: Frans van Mieris der Ältere (* 16. April 1635 in Leiden; † 12. März 1681 in Leiden, begraben in der St. Pieterskerk) war ein niederländischer Porträt-, Historien- und Genremaler. Er war ein Sohn des Goldschmieds und Diamantsetzers Jan Bastiansz. van Mieris und dessen Frau Christine Willemsdr. van Garbartijn. 
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Müller, Victor">
				<description>German description: Victor Müller, gelegentlich Viktor Müller, (* 29. März 1830 in Frankfurt am Main; † 21. Dezember 1871 in München) war ein deutscher Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Böcklin, Arnold">
				<description>Englisch description: Arnold Böcklin (16 October 1827 – 16 January 1901) was a Swiss symbolist painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Badalocchio, Sisto">
				<description>German description: Sisto Rosa (eigentlich Badalocchio; * um 1585 in Parma; † 1647 in Rom) war ein italienischer Maler. Rosa war Schüler Annibale Carraccis und Freund Giovanni Lanfrancos. Seine Gemälde (zu Reggio, Gualtieri, Parma etc.) sind in akademischer Manier gehalten, seine Stiche in Lanfrancos Geschmack behandelt. Mit dem letztern gemeinsam radierte er die biblischen Darstellungen Raffaels im Vatikan (Rom 1607, 23 Blätter), ferner allein sechs Blätter nach den Fresken Antonio da Correggios im Dom zu Parma, die vier Evangelisten nach Raffael, Amor und Pan nach Agostino Carracci, die Gruppe des Laokoon u. a.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Loeding, Harmen">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sassoferrato, Giovanni Battista Salvi gen.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Unterberger, Ignaz">
				<description>Englisch description: Ignaz Unterberger was an Italian and Austrian artist as a painter and printmaker, who was also a keen inventor. He was a member of a large dynasty of Tyrolian artists. Unterberger was probably born on 24 July 1748 in Cavalese, located in the County of Tyrol, today in Italy. His initial artistic instruction came from his uncle Franz Sebald Unterberger (1706-1776). Unterberger Senior taught his nephew the style of the Tyrol. This was High Baroque - famed for intricate church altarpieces, sculpture and frescoes. Artists working in Vienna and Salzburg found themselves training in Rome, including Ignaz's elder brother. Christoph Unterberger (1732-1798)'s influence as a member of the Accademia di San Luca provided Ignaz with access to a pivotal group of Italian artists when he arrived in Rome in 1769. His ability to capture the Italian style was such that his painting 'Maternal Love' was thought to have been Correggio's. Unterberger was a highly capable artist, with experience in creating frescoes, altarpiece paintings, bambocciata and marble work. The artist stated that he only painted for a livelihood, but printmaking was his real passion. Unterberger's printmaking is not particularly well-known, although some of his prints were included in the British Museum's 1994 exhibition and catalogue 'Printmaking in the Age of Goethe'. He did not engage in printmaking until he returned to Vienna from Rome in 1773, when he applied himself exclusively to the mezzotint. His inventions included an excavating machine for digging canals, a foot-pedal for the harp, and a machine for preparing mezzotint plates. Unterberger was never made a member of the Academy in Vienna, despite exhibiting there. Nevertheless his work was highly regarded, and the Imperial Chancellor Wenzel Anton, Prince of Kaunitz-Rietberg was a patron. His painting Hebe (1795) was a sensation for its lighting effects, and bought by Emperor Francis II for a large amount. He was also made a Royal and Imperial Court Painter. Unfortunately, he only benefited from this role for two years before heart failure lead to his death on 4 December 1797, leaving a widow and nine children.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Flämischer Meister um 1600">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Coninxloo, Gillis van">
				<description>German description: Sein Vater war der Künstler Jan II. van Coninxloo und seine Mutter Elisabeth Hasaert. Er ging bei den Malern Lenaert Kroes und Gillis Mostaert in die Lehre. Später reiste Coninxloo nach Frankreich und Italien, kehrte aber dann wieder nach Antwerpen zurück. 1570 trat er der St.-Lukas-Gilde bei und heiratete Maeyken Robroeck. Sie gebar ihm drei Kinder. Da Antwerpen 1585 von den Spaniern belagert wurde, entschied sich Coninxloo, die Stadt zu verlassen und nach Zeeland zu gehen. Schließlich ließ er sich 1587 in Frankenthal nieder. Er war der bedeutendste Vertreter der Frankenthaler Malergruppe, zu der auch Anton Mirou, Pieter Schoubroeck, Henrick Gijsmans und Hendrick van der Borcht gehörten. Im Jahre 1595 ging er nach Amsterdam. Dort bekam er das Bürgerrecht und wurde Mitglied der Rhetorikerkammer Twit Lavendel. 1603 heiratete er erneut, nämlich Geertgen van Eeden, mit der er einen Sohn hatte. In Amsterdam starb er, in Künstlerkreisen hoch angesehen, im Jahre 1607.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Romney, George">
				<description>Englisch description: George Romney may refer to:

George Romney (painter) (1734–1802), English portrait painter
George S. Romney (1874–1935), president of the college now known as Brigham Young University-Idaho
George W. Romney (1907–1995), businessman, Governor of Michigan, U.S. presidential candidate, Secretary of Housing &amp;amp; Urban Development, Mitt Romney's father
G. Scott Romney (born 1941), Michigan lawyer and politician, son of George W. Romney and brother of Mitt Romney
G. Ott Romney (1892–1973), American football player, coach and college athletics administrator</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Leibl, Wilhelm">
				<description>German description: Wilhelm Maria Hubertus Leibl (* 23. Oktober 1844 in Köln; † 4. Dezember 1900 in Würzburg) war als Maler ein bedeutender Vertreter des Realismus in Deutschland.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sisley, Alfred">
				<description>Englisch description: Alfred Sisley (/ˈsɪsli/; French: [sislɛ]; 30 October 1839 – 29 January 1899) was an Impressionist landscape painter who was born and spent most of his life in France, but retained British citizenship. He was the most consistent of the Impressionists in his dedication to painting landscape en plein air (i.e., outdoors). He deviated into figure painting only rarely and, unlike Renoir and Pissarro, found that Impressionism fulfilled his artistic needs. Among his important works are a series of paintings of the River Thames, mostly around Hampton Court, executed in 1874, and landscapes depicting places in or near Moret-sur-Loing. The notable paintings of the Seine and its bridges in the former suburbs of Paris are like many of his landscapes, characterized by tranquillity, in pale shades of green, pink, purple, dusty blue and cream. Over the years Sisley's power of expression and color intensity increased.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Liebermann, Max">
				<description>German description: Max Liebermann (* 20. Juli 1847 in Berlin; † 8. Februar 1935 ebenda) war ein deutscher Maler und Grafiker. Er gehört zu den bedeutendsten Vertretern des deutschen Impressionismus. Nach einer Ausbildung in Weimar und Aufenthalten in Paris und den Niederlanden schuf er zunächst naturalistische Werke mit sozialer Thematik. Durch die Beschäftigung mit den französischen Impressionisten fand er seit 1880 zu einer lichten Farbigkeit und einem schwungvollen Farbauftrag, der sein Hauptwerk prägt. Sein Schaffen steht symbolisch für den Übergang von der Kunst des 19. Jahrhunderts hin zur Klassischen Moderne zur Zeit des Wilhelminismus und der Weimarer Republik. Diesen Wandel förderte er als Präsident der Berliner Secession. Von 1920 bis 1932 war er Präsident, bis 1933 Ehrenpräsident der Preußischen Akademie der Künste, bevor er infolge der nationalsozialistischen Einflussnahme aus der Kunstpolitik zurücktrat. Seine letzten beiden Lebensjahre verbrachte er zurückgezogen in seiner Heimatstadt Berlin.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Spitzweg, Carl">
				<description>German description: Franz Carl Spitzweg (auch: Karl Spitzweg; * 5. Februar 1808 in Unterpfaffenhofen; † 23. September 1885 in München) war ein deutscher Maler. Im Kulturbetrieb des 19. Jahrhunderts nahm er eine Außenseiterposition ein.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pidoll, Karl von">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Chintreuil, Antoine">
				<description>Englisch description: Antoine Chintreuil (May 15, 1814 – August 8, 1873) was a French landscape painter. He was born in Pont-de-Vaux, Ain and grew up in Bresse. In 1838 he moved to Paris, where he began studying under Paul Delaroche in 1842. The following year he met Corot, who influenced him profoundly by encouraging him to paint landscape en plein air. Art historian Athena S. E. Leoussi suggests that Chintreuil's work can be divided into three periods: From c. 1846–1850 he painted Paris and its surroundings, particularly Montmartre; from 1850–1857 he lived in Igny and frequently painted in Barbizon, and from 1857 on he lived and worked in La Tournelle-Septeuil in the Seine valley. During this final period his work reached its fullest development, and he achieved critical recognition. In the breadth and simplicity of his execution, and in his attention to capturing light and atmosphere, Chintreuil can be placed alongside Eugène Boudin, Johan Barthold Jongkind, and the painters of the Barbizon school, as an important forerunner of Impressionism. He died in Septeuil, Seine-et-Oise in 1873.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Robert, Hubert">
				<description>Englisch description: Hubert Robert (22 May 1733 – 15 April 1808) was a French painter, noted for his landscape paintings and capriccio, or semi-fictitious picturesque depictions of ruins.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meyerheim, Paul">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Aertsen, Pieter">
				<description>Englisch description: Pieter Aertsen (Amsterdam, 1508 – 3 June 1575), called Lange Pier ("Tall Pete") because of his height, was a Dutch painter in the style of Northern Mannerism, who invented the monumental genre scene combining still life and genre painting, and very often also including a biblical scene in the background. He was born and died in Amsterdam, in his lifetime a relatively minor city, and painted there but mainly in Antwerp, then the centre of artistic life in the Netherlands. His genre scenes were influential on later Flemish Baroque painting, and also in Italy, and his peasant scenes preceded by a few years the much better-known paintings produced in Antwerp by Pieter Bruegel the Elder.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Monet, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Oscar-Claude Monet (/moʊˈneɪ/; French: [klod mɔnɛ]; 14 November 1840 – 5 December 1926) was a founder of French Impressionist painting, and the most consistent and prolific practitioner of the movement's philosophy of expressing one's perceptions before nature, especially as applied to plein-air landscape painting. The term "Impressionism" is derived from the title of his painting Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which was exhibited in 1874 in the first of the independent exhibitions mounted by Monet and his associates as an alternative to the Salon de Paris. Monet's ambition of documenting the French countryside led him to adopt a method of painting the same scene many times in order to capture the changing of light and the passing of the seasons. From 1883 Monet lived in Giverny, where he purchased a house and property, and began a vast landscaping project which included lily ponds that would become the subjects of his best-known works. In 1899 he began painting the water lilies, first in vertical views with a Japanese bridge as a central feature, and later in the series of large-scale paintings that was to occupy him continuously for the next 20 years of his life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Waldmüller, Ferdinand Georg">
				<description>German description: Ferdinand Georg Waldmüller (* 15. Jänner 1793 in Wien; † 23. August 1865 in Hinterbrühl bei Mödling) war einer der bedeutendsten österreichischen Maler in der Biedermeierzeit.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Blanche, Jacques-Émile">
				<description>Englisch description: Jacques-Émile Blanche (French: [blɑ̃ʃ]; 1 January 1861 – 20 September 1942) was a French artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Courbet, Gustave">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean Désiré Gustave Courbet (French: [ɡystav kuʁbɛ]; 10 June 1819 – 31 December 1877) was a French painter who led the Realist movement in 19th-century French painting. Committed to painting only what he could see, he rejected academic convention and the Romanticism of the previous generation of visual artists. His independence set an example that was important to later artists, such as the Impressionists and the Cubists. Courbet occupies an important place in 19th-century French painting as an innovator and as an artist willing to make bold social statements through his work. Courbet's paintings of the late 1840s and early 1850s brought him his first recognition. They challenged convention by depicting unidealized peasants and workers, often on a grand scale traditionally reserved for paintings of religious or historical subjects. Courbet's subsequent paintings were mostly of a less overtly political character: landscapes, seascapes, hunting scenes, nudes and still lifes. He was imprisoned for six months in 1871 for his involvement with the Paris Commune, and lived in exile in Switzerland from 1873 until his death. I am fifty years old and I have always lived in freedom; let me end my life free; when I am dead let this be said of me: 'He belonged to no school, to no church, to no institution, to no academy, least of all to any régime except the régime of liberty.'</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Millet, Jean François">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Palma il Vecchio, Jacopo">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Göbel, Angilbert">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gogh, Vincent van">
				<description>Englisch description: ("Van Gogh" redirects here. For other uses, see Van Gogh (disambiguation).) Vincent Willem van Gogh (Dutch: [ˈvɪnsɛnt ˈʋɪləm vɑn ˈɣɔx] ; 30 March 1853 – 29 July 1890) was a Dutch Post-Impressionist painter who is among the most famous and influential figures in the history of Western art. In just over a decade he created about 2100 artworks, including around 860 oil paintings, most of them in the last two years of his life. They include landscapes, still lifes, portraits and self-portraits, and are characterised by bold, symbolic colours, and dramatic, impulsive and highly expressive brushwork that contributed to the foundations of modern art. He sold only one painting during his lifetime and became famous after his suicide at age 37, which followed years of poverty and mental illness. Born into an upper-middle-class family, Van Gogh drew as a child and was serious, quiet and thoughtful, but showed signs of mental instability. As a young man he worked as an art dealer, often travelling, but became depressed after he was transferred to London. He turned to religion, and spent time as a missionary in southern Belgium. Later he drifted in ill health and solitude. He was keenly aware of modernist trends in art and, while back with his parents, took up painting in 1881. His younger brother, Theo, supported him financially, and the two kept up a long correspondence by letter. Van Gogh's early works, mostly still lifes and depictions of peasant labourers, contain few signs of the vivid colour that distinguished his later work. In 1886 he moved to Paris and became interested in the French Impressionists. As his work developed he created a new approach to still lifes and local landscapes. His paintings grew brighter in colour as he developed a style that became fully realised during his stay in Arles in the south of France in 1888. He lived there in the Yellow House and, with the French artist Paul Gauguin, developed a concept of colour that symbolised inner emotion. During this period he broadened his subject matter to include olive trees, cypresses, wheat fields and sunflowers. Van Gogh suffered from psychotic episodes and delusions and, though he worried about his mental stability, he often neglected his physical health, not eating properly and drinking heavily. His friendship with Gauguin came to an end after he threatened the Frenchman with a razor, and in a rage, cut off part of his own left ear. While in a psychiatric hospital in Saint-Rémy his condition stabilised, leading to one of the more productive periods of his life. He moved to the Auberge Ravoux in Auvers-sur-Oise near Paris under the care of the homeopathic doctor and artist, Paul Gachet. On 27 July 1890, Van Gogh shot himself in the chest with a revolver. He died from his injuries two days later. Considered a madman and a failure in his lifetime, Van Gogh exists in the public imagination as the quintessential misunderstood genius, the artist "where discourses on madness and creativity converge". His reputation began to grow in the early 20th century as elements of his painting style came to be incorporated by the Fauves and German Expressionists. He attained widespread critical, commercial and popular success over the ensuing decades, and is remembered as an important but tragic painter, whose troubled personality typifies the romantic ideal of the tortured artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Daubigny, Charles François">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Capella gen. Il Daggiù, Francesco">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Delacroix, Eugène">
				<description>German description: Ferdinand Victor Eugène Delacroix (* 26. April 1798 in Charenton-Saint-Maurice, einem Vorort von Paris; † 13. August 1863 in Paris) war einer der bedeutendsten französischen Maler und gilt wegen der Lebhaftigkeit seiner Vorstellungskraft und wegen seines großzügigen Umgangs mit den Farben als Wegbereiter des Impressionismus. Er stellte alljährlich im Pariser Salon Gemälde aus, deren leidenschaftliche Sujets Aufsehen erregten und nicht selten schockierten. Die Arbeiten Delacroix’ werden zwar der französischen Spätromantik zugeordnet, er lehnte es jedoch für sich ab, der populär werdenden Strömung der romantischen Schule zugeschlagen zu werden. Er wurde zum Vorbild vieler Impressionisten, die sich entschieden von der romantischen Schule und dem Klassizismus abgrenzten.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Manet, Édouard">
				<description>German description: Édouard Manet (* 23. Januar 1832 in Paris; † 30. April 1883 ebenda) war ein französischer Maler. Er gilt als einer der Wegbereiter der modernen Malerei.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Parmigianino">
				<description>German description: Parmigianino (* 11. Januar 1503 in Parma; † 24. August 1540 in Casalmaggiore, Parma; eigentlich Girolamo Francesco Maria Mazzola) war ein italienischer Maler und Radierer des Manierismus.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Corot, Camille">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Longhi, Pietro">
				<description>Englisch description: Pietro Longhi (1702 or November 5, 1701 – May 8, 1785) was a Venetian painter of contemporary genre scenes of life.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lanfranco, Giovanni">
				<description>German description: Giovanni Lanfranco (* 26. Januar 1582 in Parma; † 30. November 1647 in Rom) war ein italienischer Zeichner und Maler. Er ist ein bedeutender Vertreter der Freskenmalerei des Hochbarock. Daneben ist Lanfranco auch für seine Altarbilder bekannt.Lanfranco war hauptsächlich Freskant; seine Ölgemälde sind unbedeutend, seine Wandbilder dagegen zeigen eine kühne Phantasie und eine glänzende Farbe, sind jedoch meist oberflächliche Improvisationen. Er bildet den Übergang von der Schule der Carracci zur Manier des Pietro da Cortona. Er zeichnete über fünfzig Werke, meist Figuren- und Detailstudien in schwarzer Kreide auf graubraunem oder bläulichem Papier.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Tintoretto">
				<description>German description: Jacopo Robusti, gen. Jacopo Tintoretto (* 29. September 1518 in Venedig; † 31. Mai 1594 ebenda), war ein italienischer Maler. Sein Name Il Tintoretto („das Färberlein“) ist vom Handwerk seines Vaters abgeleitet. Sein Vater hieß, wie erst jüngst entdeckt wurde, wahrscheinlich Giovan Batista Comin und erhielt wegen der heldenhaften Verteidigung eines Stadttors von Padua 1509 den Ehrennamen Robusti. Jacopo Tintoretto war wiederum der Vater der Malerin Marietta Robusti, genannt „La Tintoretta“, und der Maler Domenico Tintoretto und Marco Tintoretto. Nachdem Marietta, Domenico und Marco Robusti gestorben waren, erbte deren Schwester Ottavia als Haupterbin die Werkstatt und heiratete auf Weisung ihrer Brüder den deutschstämmigen Maler Sebastian Casser, der in der Tintorettowerkstatt ausgebildet worden war.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Crespi gen. Il Cerano, Giovanni Battista">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Venezianischer Meister des 18. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Italienischer Meister um 1600/1610">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hackert, Jakob Philipp">
				<description>German description: Jakob Philipp Hackert, eigentlich Philipp Hackert (* 15. September 1737 in Prenzlau; † 28. April 1807 in San Piero di Careggio, heute Careggi, Ortsteil von Florenz) war ein deutscher Landschaftsmaler des Klassizismus.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Doré, Gustave">
				<description>German description: Paul Gustave Doré (* 6. Januar 1832 in Straßburg; † 23. Januar 1883 in Paris) war ein französischer Maler und Grafiker, der sich vor allem als Illustrator einen Namen machte.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Segantini, Giovanni">
				<description>German description: Giovanni Segantini (* 15. Januar 1858 in Arco (Tirol, Kaisertum Österreich); † 28. September 1899 auf dem Schafberg bei Pontresina, Kanton Graubünden, Schweiz; vollständiger Name Giovanni Battista Emanuele Maria Segatini) war ein im Welschtirol als österreichischer Staatsbürger geborener Maler des realistischen Symbolismus. Er galt als Meister der Hochgebirgslandschaft und begann früh mit der Freilichtmalerei. Segantini entwickelte eine eigene Version der pointillistischen Maltechnik, mit deren Hilfe er das ungebrochene Licht der Hochgebirgswelt wiedergeben und die naturalistische Wirkung seiner Bilder steigern konnte.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bosch, Hieronymus">
				<description>Englisch description: Hieronymus Bosch (/ˌhaɪ.əˈrɒnᵻməs ˈbɒʃ/; Dutch: [ɦijeːˈroːnimɵz ˈbɔs]; born Jheronimus van Aken [jeːˈroːnimɵs fɑn ˈaːkə(n)]; c. 1450 – 9 August 1516) was an Early Netherlandish painter. His work is known for its fantastic imagery, detailed landscapes, and illustrations of religious concepts and narratives. Within his lifetime his work was collected in the Netherlands, Austria, and Spain, and widely copied, especially his macabre and nightmarish depictions of hell. Little is known of Bosch's life, though there are some records. He spent most of it in the town of 's-Hertogenbosch, where he was born in his grandfather's house. The roots of his forefathers are in Nijmegen and Aachen (which is visible in his surname: Van Aken). His pessimistic and fantastical style cast a wide influence on northern art of the 16th century, with Pieter Bruegel the Elder being his best known follower. His paintings have been difficult to translate from a modern point of view; attempts to associate instances of modern sexual imagery with fringe sects or the occult have largely failed. Today he is seen as a hugely individualistic painter with deep insight into humanity's desires and deepest fears. Attribution has been especially difficult; today only about 25 paintings are confidently given to his hand along with 8 drawings. Approximately another half dozen paintings are confidently attributed to his workshop. His most acclaimed works consist of a few triptych altarpieces, the most outstanding of which is The Garden of Earthly Delights.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bloemaert, Abraham">
				<description>Englisch description: Abraham Bloemaert (1566 – 27 January 1651) was a Dutch painter and printmaker in etching and engraving. He was one of the "Haarlem Mannerists" from about 1585, but in the new century altered his style to fit new Baroque trends. He mostly painted history subjects and some landscapes. He was an important teacher, who trained most of the Utrecht Caravaggisti, at least for a period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Elsheimer, Adam">
				<description>German description: Adam Elsheimer (getauft am 18. März 1578 in Frankfurt am Main; † 11. Dezember 1610 in Rom) war ein bedeutender deutscher Barockmaler des frühen 17. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Juncker, Justus">
				<description>German description: Justus Juncker (* 24. Juli 1703 in Mainz; † 15. Juni 1767 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Genre- und Blumenmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Giordano, Luca">
				<description>Englisch description: Luca Giordano (18 October 1634 – 12 January 1705) was an Italian late Baroque painter and printmaker in etching. Fluent and decorative, he worked successfully in Naples and Rome, Florence and Venice, before spending a decade in Spain.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hoppner, John">
				<description>Englisch description: John Hoppner RA (4 April 1758 – 23 January 1810) was an English portrait painter, much influenced by Reynolds who achieved fame as a brilliant colourist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Steinle, Edward von">
				<description>German description: Edward Jakob von Steinle (auch Eduard von Steinle; * 2. Juli 1810 in Wien; † 19. September 1886 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein österreichischer Maler des 19. Jahrhunderts.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Singleton, Henry">
				<description>Englisch description: Henry Singleton may refer to:

Henry Singleton (judge), Irish judge
Henry Singleton (painter) (1766–1839), English painter
Henry Earl Singleton, American industrialist</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guigou, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Camille Guigou (15 February 1834 – 21 December 1871) was a French landscape painter. Guigou was born in Villars, Vaucluse in a wealthy family of farmers and notaries. He studied painting in Apt and later with Émile Loubon in Marseille. In 1851, he became clerk at Apt and in 1854 at Marseille where he also moved. Guigou painted mostly Provence landscapes using oil and watercolour. At his beginnings, he was influenced by Loubon, later by Barbizon school and Gustave Courbet. During his lifetime, he was not recognised and met with indifference of both jury and public exhibitions. Struggling with financial problems, he had to give painting lessons and write reviews. He died in Paris at the age of 37 from stroke. After his death, he and his works were mostly forgotten. Revival of interest in him began early in the 20th century at exhibitions in Paris and Marseille. Currently his works are highly valued at auctions.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guardi, Giacomo">
				<description>Englisch description: Giacomo Guardi (13 April 1764 – 3 November 1835) was an Italian painter from Venice. The son of famous veduta painter Francesco Guardi, he continued his father's line of work, though without the same level of renown. The majority of his works are quite small views of only minor artistic interest, more akin to postcards than to his father's grand scenes, but he produced several paintings showcasing a notable level of artistic skill as well. Evaluating his legacy is somewhat complicated due to the frequency with which paintings are misattributed to him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morland, George">
				<description>Englisch description: George Morland (26 June 1763 in London – 29 October 1804 in Brighton) was an English painter of animals and rustic scenes.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Urlaub, Georg Karl">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ziesenis, Johann Georg">
				<description>German description: Johann Georg Ziesenis d.J. (* 1716 in Kopenhagen; † 4. März 1776 in Hannover) war ein deutscher Porträtmaler. Er entstammt einer bedeutenden Kunsthandwerker- und Künstlerfamilie des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts, deren Werke zum Teil dem Hannoverschen Rokoko zugerechnet werden.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Faber von Kreuznach, Conrad">
				<description>German description: Conrad Faber von Kreuznach (* um 1500 (?) in Kreuznach; † zwischen dem 10. September 1552 und dem 15. Mai 1553 in Frankfurt am Main), früher Meister der Holzhausen-Bildnisse genannt, war ein deutscher Maler und Zeichner für den Holzschnitt und ein Meister des Renaissanceporträts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Uffenbach, Philipp">
				<description>German description: Philipp Uffenbach (* 15. Januar 1566 in Frankfurt am Main; † (begraben) 6. April 1636 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler, Zeichner, Aquarellist, Radierer und Kupferstecher in der Nachfolge von Matthias Grünewald und Albrecht Dürer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kaldenbach, Martin">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gentile da Fabriano">
				<description>German description: Gentile da Fabriano (eigentlich Gentile di Nicolò Massio, * um 1370 oder um 1385 in Fabriano; † 1. August 1427 in Rom) war ein italienischer Maler der Frührenaissance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Troger, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Troger (30 October 1698 – 20 July 1762) was an Austrian painter, draughtsman and printmaker of the late Baroque period. Troger's illusionistic ceiling paintings in fresco are notable for their dramatic vitality of movement and their palette of light colors. Paul Troger’s style, particularly in his frescoes, dominated Austrian painting until the end of the 18th century and profoundly influenced significant artists of the next generation, notably Franz Anton Maulbertsch, Josef Ignaz Mildorfer, Johann Wenzel Bergl and Johann Lucas Kracker.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Nürnberger Marienaltars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fränkisch-Schwäbischer Meister um 1440/50">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Khnopff, Fernand">
				<description>German description: Fernand-Edmond-Jean-Marie Khnopff (* 12. September 1858 in Grembergen bei Dendermonde, Flandern; † 12. November 1921 in Brüssel) war ein belgischer Maler, Grafiker, Bildhauer, Fotograf und Kunstschriftsteller. Er gilt neben James Ensor als Hauptvertreter des belgischen Symbolismus.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klinger, Max">
				<description>Englisch description: Max Klinger (18 February 1857 – 5 July 1920) was a German symbolist painter, sculptor, printmaker, and writer. Klinger was born in Leipzig and studied in Karlsruhe. An admirer of the etchings of Menzel and Goya, he shortly became a skilled and imaginative engraver in his own right. He began creating sculptures in the early 1880s. From 1883–1893 he lived in Rome, and became increasingly influenced by the Italian Renaissance and antiquity.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Evenepoel, Henri">
				<description>Englisch description: Henri-Jacques-Edouard Evenepoel (3 October 1872 in Nice – 27 December 1899 in Paris) was a Belgian artist whose most important works are associated with Fauvism.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lenbach, Franz von">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz von Lenbach (13 December 1836 – 6 May 1904) was a German painter of Realist style. He travelled to Italy and Spain and completed many notable portraits.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Friedrich, Caspar David">
				<description>Englisch description: Caspar David Friedrich (5 September 1774 – 7 May 1840) was a 19th-century German Romantic landscape painter, generally considered the most important German artist of his generation. He is best known for his mid-period allegorical landscapes which typically feature contemplative figures silhouetted against night skies, morning mists, barren trees or Gothic ruins. His primary interest as an artist was the contemplation of nature, and his often symbolic and anti-classical work seeks to convey a subjective, emotional response to the natural world. Friedrich's paintings characteristically set a human presence in diminished perspective amid expansive landscapes, reducing the figures to a scale that, according to the art historian Christopher John Murray, directs "the viewer's gaze towards their metaphysical dimension". Friedrich was born in the Pomeranian town of Greifswald at the Baltic Sea, where he began his studies in art as a young man. He studied in Copenhagen until 1798, before settling in Dresden. He came of age during a period when, across Europe, a growing disillusionment with materialistic society was giving rise to a new appreciation of spirituality. This shift in ideals was often expressed through a reevaluation of the natural world, as artists such as Friedrich, J. M. W. Turner (1775–1851) and John Constable (1776–1837) sought to depict nature as a "divine creation, to be set against the artifice of human civilization". Friedrich's work brought him renown early in his career, and contemporaries such as the French sculptor David d'Angers (1788–1856) spoke of him as a man who had discovered "the tragedy of landscape". Nevertheless, his work fell from favour during his later years, and he died in obscurity, and in the words of the art historian Philip B. Miller, "half mad". As Germany moved towards modernisation in the late 19th century, a new sense of urgency characterised its art, and Friedrich's contemplative depictions of stillness came to be seen as the products of a bygone age. The early 20th century brought a renewed appreciation of his work, beginning in 1906 with an exhibition of thirty-two of his paintings and sculptures in Berlin. By the 1920s his paintings had been discovered by the Expressionists, and in the 1930s and early 1940s Surrealists and Existentialists frequently drew ideas from his work. The rise of Nazism in the early 1930s again saw a resurgence in Friedrich's popularity, but this was followed by a sharp decline as his paintings were, by association with the Nazi movement, interpreted as having a nationalistic aspect. It was not until the late 1970s that Friedrich regained his reputation as an icon of the German Romantic movement and a painter of international importance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dahl, Johan Christian Clausen">
				<description>German description: Johan Christian Clausen Dahl (* 24. Februar 1788 in Bergen; † 14. Oktober 1857 in Dresden; oft I. C. Dahl oder J. C. Dahl genannt) war ein norwegischer Landschaftsmaler der Romantik und enger Freund von Caspar David Friedrich. Von 1818 bis 1857 lebte und wirkte er in Dresden. Dahl war Mitglied der Kunstakademien in Kopenhagen (seit 1827), Stockholm (seit 1832) und Berlin (seit 1834).
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Jawlensky, Alexej von">
				<description>German description: Alexej von Jawlensky (ursprünglich Alexei Georgijewitsch Jawlenski; russisch Алексей Георгиевич Явленский, wiss. Transliteration Alexej Georgievič Javlenskij; * 13. Märzjul./ 25. März 1865greg. oder 1864 in der Nähe von Torschok, Russisches Kaiserreich; † 15. März 1941 in Wiesbaden) war ein russisch-deutscher Maler. 1930 beantragte er die deutsche Staatsbürgerschaft, die er 1934 auch erhielt. Jawlensky zählt als Maler des Expressionismus zum Umfeld der von Wassily Kandinsky und Franz Marc initiierten Redaktionsgemeinschaft Der Blaue Reiter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pseudo-Félix Chrétien">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Burnitz, Karl Peter">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Deodato Orlandi">
				<description>Englisch description: Deodato Orlandi (active 1284-1315, died before 1331) was an Italian painter of Medieval art. Orlandi was active in Lucca and Pisa between 1284 and 1315. He primarily painted religious-themed works on commissions for churches. Some of his works show a Byzantine art style, and an influence of Giotto can also be seen. He painted frescos for the San Piero a Grado church which was commissioned by the Caetani family for the 1300 jubilee. In the lower part are Portraits of Popes, from St. Peter to John XVIII (1303); the intermediate portion has thirty panels with Histories of St. Peter's Life (as well of those of St. Paul, Constantine and St. Sylvester), similar to those in the Old St. Peter's Basilica and to Cimabue's work at San Francesco in Assisi. In the upper area are portrayed the Walls of the Heaven City, largely restored in the following centuries. A St John Evangelist Mourning attributed to Deodato is displayed in the Städel Gallery in Frankfurt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mayr, Johann Ulrich">
				<description>German description: Johann Ulrich Mayr (* 1630 in Augsburg; † 11. Juni 1704 ebenda) war ein deutscher Barockmaler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Thoma, Hans">
				<description>Englisch description: Hans Thoma (October 2, 1839 – November 7, 1924) was a German painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Macke, August">
				<description>Englisch description: August Macke (3 January 1887 – 26 September 1914) was one of the leading members of the German Expressionist group Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider). He lived during a particularly innovative time for German art: he saw the development of the main German Expressionist movements as well as the arrival of the successive avant-garde movements which were forming in the rest of Europe. Like a true artist of his time, Macke knew how to integrate into his painting the elements of the avant-garde which most interested him.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fantin-Latour, Henri">
				<description>Englisch description: Henri Fantin-Latour (14 January 1836 – 25 August 1904) was a French painter and lithographer best known for his flower paintings and group portraits of Parisian artists and writers.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Murillo, Bartolomé Esteban">
				<description>Englisch description: Bartolomé Esteban Murillo (born late December 1617, baptized January 1, 1618 – April 3, 1682) was a Spanish Baroque painter. Although he is best known for his religious works, Murillo also produced a considerable number of paintings of contemporary women and children. These lively, realist portraits of flower girls, street urchins, and beggars constitute an extensive and appealing record of the everyday life of his times.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Flegel, Georg">
				<description>German description: Georg Flegel (* 1566 in Olmütz; † 23. März 1638 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein bedeutender Stilllebenmaler des frühen 17. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Michau, Theobald">
				<description>Englisch description: To the same page name with diacritics: This is a redirect from a page name that does not have diacritical marks (accents, umlauts, etc.) to essentially the same page name with diacritical marks or a "List of..." page anchored to a promising list item name with diacritics.
This redirect aids in searches and may be applied (without piping) when the subject page concerns language translation or foreign language equivalents.  Other pages that use this redirect should be updated with a direct link to the redirect target (again, without piping).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meister aus dem Umkreis Friedrich Herlins">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Corinth, Lovis">
				<description>German description: Lovis Corinth (* 21. Juli 1858 in Tapiau, Ostpreußen; † 17. Juli 1925 in Zandvoort, Niederlande; eigentlich Franz Heinrich Louis Corinth) war ein deutscher Maler. Er zählt neben Max Liebermann, Ernst Oppler und Max Slevogt zu den wichtigsten und einflussreichsten Vertretern des deutschen Impressionismus. Seine späten Werke werden häufig als eine Synthese aus impressionistischem und expressionistischem Schaffen angesehen.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig">
				<description>German description: Ernst Ludwig Kirchner (* 6. Mai 1880 in Aschaffenburg; † 15. Juni 1938 in Frauenkirch-Wildboden bei Davos/Schweiz) war ein deutscher Maler und Grafiker und zählt zu den wichtigsten Vertretern des Expressionismus. Kirchner war ein Gründungsmitglied der Künstlergruppe Brücke. 1937 wurde sein Werk durch die Nationalsozialisten als „entartet“ gebrandmarkt. Über 600 dieser Werke wurden daraufhin verkauft oder zerstört. Ein Jahr darauf nahm er sich mit einer Schusswaffe das Leben.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ammon, Hans">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der Madonna von Covarrubias&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Marc, Franz">
				<description>Englisch description: Franz Marc (February 8, 1880 – March 4, 1916) was a German painter and printmaker, one of the key figures of the German Expressionist movement. He was a founding member of Der Blaue Reiter (The Blue Rider), a journal whose name later became synonymous with the circle of artists collaborating in it.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kern, Anton">
				<description>German description: Anton Kern ist der Name folgender Personen:

Anton Kern (Maler) (1710–1747), deutscher Maler
Anton Kern (Bibliothekar) (1883–1956), österreichischer Bibliothekswissenschafter
Anton Kern (Politiker) (* 1951), deutscher Politiker (CSU), MdL Bayern</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kalf, Willem">
				<description>German description: Willem Kalf (getauft 3. November 1619 Rotterdam; † 31. Juli 1693 Amsterdam) war einer der bedeutendsten Stilllebenmaler der Niederlande im 17. Jahrhundert.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klee, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Klee (German: [paʊ̯l ˈkleː]; 18 December 1879 – 29 June 1940) was a Swiss-German artist. His highly individual style was influenced by movements in art that included Expressionism, Cubism, and Surrealism. Klee was a natural draftsman who experimented with and eventually deeply explored color theory, writing about it extensively; his lectures Writings on Form and Design Theory (Schriften zur Form und Gestaltungslehre), published in English as the Paul Klee Notebooks, are held to be as important for modern art as Leonardo da Vinci's A Treatise on Painting for the Renaissance. He and his colleague, Russian painter Wassily Kandinsky, both taught at the Bauhaus school of art, design and architecture. His works reflect his dry humor and his sometimes childlike perspective, his personal moods and beliefs, and his musicality.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Chardin, Jean-Baptiste Siméon">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bril, Paul">
				<description>Englisch description: Paul Bril (1554 – 7 October 1626) was a Flemish painter and printmaker principally known for his landscapes. He spent most of his active career in Rome. His Italianate landscapes had a major influence on landscape painting in Italy and Northern Europe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cipper gen. Il Todeschini, Giacomo Francesco">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Modersohn-Becker, Paula">
				<description>Englisch description: Paula Modersohn-Becker (February 8, 1876 – November 21, 1907) was a German painter and one of the most important representatives of early expressionism. In a brief career, cut short by an embolism at the age of 31, she created a number of groundbreaking images of great intensity. She is becoming recognized as the first female painter to paint female nudes. Using bold forays into subject matter and chromatic color choices, she and fellow-artists Picasso and Matisse introduced the world to modernism at the start of the twentieth century.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bock d. Ä., Hans">
				<description>German description: Hans Bock der Ältere (* um 1550 in Zabern; † 16. März 1624 in Basel) war ein Maler, Zeichner, Restaurator und Geometer. 
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baburen, Dirck van">
				<description>German description: Dirck van Baburen (* 1595 in Utrecht (Niederlande); † 1624 ebenfalls in Utrecht) war ein holländischer Maler religiöser Motive, Historienstücken und Genre-Szenen. Er zählte zu den Anhängern Caravaggios und wird als einer der Utrechter Caravaggisten bezeichnet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister der von Grooteschen Anbetung&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Katz, Hanns Ludwig">
				<description>German description: Hanns Ludwig Katz (geboren 24. Juli 1892 in Karlsruhe; gestorben 17. November 1940 in Johannesburg) war ein deutscher expressionistischer Maler und Grafiker jüdischer Abstammung.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Umbrischer Meister um 1500">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goes, Hugo van der">
				<description>German description: Hugo van der Goes (* etwa 1435/1440 vermutlich in Gent; † 1482 in Oudergem bei Brüssel) war ein flämischer Maler und Hauptmeister der altniederländischen Malerei in der 2. Hälfte des 15. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brügger (?) Meister um 1485/90">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Macrino d'Alba">
				<description>Englisch description: Macrino d'Alba (c. 1460–1465 – c. 1510–1520) was an Italian painter of the Renaissance period, active mainly in Piedmont, who is known for his altarpieces and portraits. His birth name was Gian Giacomo de' Alladio.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lorenzetti, Pietro">
				<description>German description: Pietro Lorenzetti (* um 1280 in Siena; † wahrscheinlich 1348 ebenda) war ein italienischer Maler und der ältere Bruder von Ambrogio Lorenzetti. Er gilt als Nachfolger Giottos, da er den Freskenzyklus der Unterkirche der Basilika San Francesco in Assisi ab etwa 1325 fertigstellte. Im Palazzo Pubblico von Siena malte er mit seinem Bruder Ambrogio drei Wände der Sala dei Nove in einem Großauftrag aus. Die Fresken dort stellen in politisch schulmeisterlicher Manier allegorisch  Die gute und die schlechte Regierung, mit ihren Auswirkungen auf die Bevölkerung in Stadt und Land dar (gemalt zwischen 1337 und 1339, im unteren Abschnitt heute schwer beschädigt). Vorbilder waren für ihn u. a. Duccio di Buoninsegna, Giotto und Giovanni Pisano. Von Duccio übernahm er die Figurendarstellung wie z. B. im Retabel der Pfarrkirche von Arezzo, von Giotto lernte er Raumdarstellung und Verkürzung und von Pisano die Leidenschaftlichkeit des Vortrags. Da nach 1348 jegliche Nachrichten über die Brüder Lorenzetti fehlen, wurden sie sehr wahrscheinlich Opfer der Pestepidemie von 1348.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lawrence, Thomas">
				<description>Englisch description: Sir Thomas Lawrence PRA FRS (13 April 1769 – 7 January 1830) was a leading English portrait painter and the fourth president of the Royal Academy. Lawrence was a child prodigy. He was born in Bristol and began drawing in Devizes, where his father was an innkeeper. At the age of ten, having moved to Bath, he was supporting his family with his pastel portraits. At eighteen he went to London and soon established his reputation as a portrait painter in oils, receiving his first royal commission, a portrait of Queen Charlotte, in 1790. He stayed at the top of his profession until his death, aged 60, in 1830. Self-taught, he was a brilliant draughtsman and known for his gift of capturing a likeness, as well as his virtuoso handling of paint. He became an associate of the Royal Academy in 1791, a full member in 1794, and president in 1820. In 1810 he acquired the generous patronage of the Prince Regent, was sent abroad to paint portraits of allied leaders for the Waterloo chamber at Windsor Castle, and is particularly remembered as the Romantic portraitist of the Regency. Lawrence's love affairs were not happy (his tortuous relationships with Sally and Maria Siddons became the subject of several books) and, in spite of his success, he spent most of life deep in debt. He never married. At his death, Lawrence was the most fashionable portrait painter in Europe. His reputation waned during Victorian times, but has since been partially restored.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1420">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Holbein d. Ä., Hans">
				<description>German description: Hans Holbein der Ältere (* um 1465 in Augsburg; † um 1524 in Basel oder Isenheim) war ein deutscher Maler der Renaissance. Er war der Senior einer berühmten Malerfamilie, zu der auch sein Bruder Sigmund sowie seine Söhne Ambrosius und Hans Holbein der Jüngere gehörten.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nithart gen. Grünewald, Mathis Gothart">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1450/60">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Pforr, Franz">
				<description>German description: Franz Pforr war der Sohn von Johann Georg Pforr und von Johanna Christiane Pforr, geborene Tischbein. Sein Vater war ein auf Pferde spezialisierter Kunstmaler, der in Frankfurt hoch angesehen war. Im Alter von 12 Jahren verlor Franz Pforr seine Eltern und ein Jahr später seinen einzigen Bruder. Sein Onkel Johann Heinrich Tischbein, Maler, Kupferstecher und Inspector der Gemäldegalerie des Landgrafen von Hessen–Kassel, nahm ihn 1801 in Kassel in seine Obhut, förderte seine Ausbildung und unterstützte seine Bewerbung an der Wiener Kunstakademie, wo er 1805 aufgenommen wurde. Diese Institution wurde zu jener Zeit im Geiste eines strengen Klassizismus von Heinrich Friedrich Füger geleitet. Ebenso wie einige Freunde und Studienkollegen, darunter Friedrich Overbeck, Konrad Hottinger und Ludwig Vogel, war er unzufrieden mit der Ausbildung an der Akademie. Die Studenten vermissten in der vernunftdurchdrungenen, streng an der äußeren klassischen Form orientierten Kunst, wie sie die Akademie vermittelte, die seelische Tiefe. Sie suchten ihren eigenen Weg und fanden ihn in der Anlehnung an die Vergangenheit. Wir fanden zwar, dass, je weiter wir fort gingen, wir uns immer mehr von den Grundsätzen der Akademie entfernten, dagegen fanden wir, dass wir uns der Art der alten Maler immer mehr näherten. Der künstlerische Gegensatz zur Akademie führte schließlich zu schweren äußeren Konflikten. 1809 kam es einerseits zum Ausschluss aus der Akademie, andererseits zur Gründung des Lukasbundes durch die jungen Künstler. Overbeck, Hottinger, Vogel und Pforr verließen 1810 Wien, um zum Studium alter italienische Meister und zur Weiterentwicklung ihrer Malkunst nach Rom zu ziehen. Dort schufen sie eine Kunstrichtung, die später unter dem Namen nazarenische Kunst bekannt wurde und die als wichtige Strömung innerhalb der romantischen Kunst die erste Hälfte des 19. Jahrhunderts maßgeblich mit bestimmen sollte. Pforr selbst war es nicht vergönnt, den Durchbruch seiner Kunst zur allgemeinen Anerkennung mitzuerleben. Im Alter von 24 Jahren starb er an der Tuberkulose.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Oberrheinischer Meister um 1410/20">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Munch, Edvard">
				<description>Englisch description: Edvard Munch (/mʊŋk/; Norwegian: [ˈɛdvɑʈ muŋk]  ; 12 December 1863 – 23 January 1944) was a Norwegian painter and printmaker whose intensely evocative treatment of psychological themes built upon some of the main tenets of late 19th-century Symbolism and greatly influenced German Expressionism in the early 20th century. One of his most well-known works is The Scream of 1893.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schlemmer, Oskar">
				<description>Englisch description: Oskar Schlemmer (4 September 1888 – 13 April 1943) was a German painter, sculptor, designer and choreographer associated with the Bauhaus school. In 1923 he was hired as Master of Form at the Bauhaus theatre workshop, after working some time at the workshop of sculpture. His most famous work is "Triadisches Ballett," in which the actors are transfigured from the normal to geometrical shapes. Also in Slat Dance and Treppenwitz, the performers' costumes make them into living sculpture, as if part of the scenery.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Berchem, Nicolaes">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Blechen, Carl">
				<description>Englisch description: Carl Eduard Ferdinand Blechen (29 July 1798, Cottbus - 23 July 1840, Berlin) was a German landscape painter and a Professor at the Academy of Arts, Berlin. His distinctive style was characteristic of the Romantic ideals of natural beauty.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Trübner, Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Wilhelm Trübner (February 3, 1851 – December 21, 1917) was a German realist painter of the circle of Wilhelm Leibl.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Keller, Albert von">
				<description>Englisch description: Albert von Keller (27 April 1844 – 14 July 1920) was a German historical and genre painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stuck, Franz von">
				<description>German description: Franz Stuck, seit 1906 Ritter von Stuck (* 23. Februar 1863 in Tettenweis, Landkreis Passau, Niederbayern; † 30. August 1928 in München), war ein deutscher Zeichner, Maler und Bildhauer des Jugendstils und des Symbolismus.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Degas, Edgar">
				<description>German description: Edgar Degas, bürgerlich Hilaire Germain Edgar de Gas (* 19. Juli 1834 in Paris; † 27. September 1917 ebenda), war ein französischer Maler und Bildhauer. Er wird häufig zu den Impressionisten gezählt, mit denen er gemeinsam ausstellte. Seine Gemälde unterscheiden sich jedoch von denen des Impressionismus unter anderem durch die exakte Linienführung und die klar strukturierte Bildkomposition. Einerseits schuf Degas zahlreiche Porträts, andererseits konzentrierte er sich auf einige wenige Bildthemen, die er immer wieder variierte: das Ballett, Jockeys und Pferde, das Pariser Nachtleben sowie Frauen bei der Körperpflege. Er widmete sich der Ölmalerei und grafischen Techniken ebenso wie der Pastellmalerei, in der er es zu außergewöhnlicher Meisterschaft brachte. Seine Plastiken zeigen eine neue Auffassung von Skulptur.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brütt, Ferdinand">
				<description>Englisch description: Ferdinand Martin Cordt Brütt (13 July 1849, Hamburg - 6 November 1936, Bergen) was a German painter. He was a distant relative of the sculptor Adolf Brütt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cranach d. J., Lucas">
				<description>German description: Lucas Cranach der Jüngere (* 4. Oktober 1515 in Wittenberg; † 25. Januar 1586 ebenda) war ein bedeutender Maler und Porträtist der Renaissance. Er ist Sohn von Lucas Cranach dem Älteren.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rheinischer Meister um 1330">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bandell, Eugenie">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sérusier, Paul">
				<description>German description: Paul Sérusier (* 9. November 1864 in Paris; † 7. Oktober 1927 in Morlaix, Finistère) war ein französischer Maler. Als Schüler von Paul Gauguin rief er die symbolistische Künstlergruppe Nabis (hebräisch: Propheten) ins Leben.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rousseau, Henri">
				<description>German description: Henri Julien Félix Rousseau, genannt „Le Douanier“ (* 21. Mai 1844 in Laval; † 2. September 1910 in Paris) war ein autodidaktischer französischer Maler, dessen Stil dem Postimpressionismus und der Naiven Kunst zugeordnet wird. Er gilt als einer der Wegbereiter des Surrealismus.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Roederstein, Ottilie W.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nürnberger Meister um 1350/60">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Stötteritzer Altars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="&quot;Meister des Bartholomäusaltars&quot;">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Codde, Pieter Jacobsz">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Uhde, Fritz von">
				<description>German description: Fritz von Uhde (* 22. Mai 1848 im Gutsbezirk Wolkenburg, Sachsen; † 25. Februar 1911 in München; gebürtig Friedrich Hermann Carl Uhde) war ein sächsischer Kavallerieoffizier und Maler. Sein Stil lag zwischen Realismus und Impressionismus. Er malte auch religiöse Bilder.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Trautmann, Johann Georg">
				<description>German description: Johann Georg Trautmann ist der Name folgender Personen:

Johann Georg Trautmann (Maler) (1713–1769), deutscher Maler und Grafiker
Johann Georg Trautmann (Kaufmann) (1805–1888), deutscher Kaufmann und Politiker</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mittelrheinischer Meister um 1400">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Altheim, Wilhelm">
				<description>German description: Wilhelm Altheim (* 2. August 1871 in Groß-Gerau; † 25. Dezember 1914  in Frankfurt am Main) war ein deutscher Maler und Radierer des 19. und 20. Jahrhunderts in Hessen.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Redon, Odilon">
				<description>German description: Odilon Redon, geboren als Bertrand-Jean Redon, (* 22. April 1840 in Bordeaux; † 6. Juli 1916 in Paris) war ein französischer Grafiker und Maler des Symbolismus und Mitbegründer der Société des Artistes Indépendants. Das Werk des Künstlers gliedert sich in eine frühe schwarze und eine (späte) farbige Phase.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hodler, Ferdinand">
				<description>German description: Ferdinand Hodler (* 14. März 1853 in Bern; † 19. Mai 1918 in Genf; Bürger von Gurzelen BE) war ein Schweizer Maler des Symbolismus und des Jugendstils. Er ist heute der bekannteste Schweizer Maler des 19. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kollwitz, Käthe">
				<description>Englisch description: Käthe (Schmidt) Kollwitz (German pronunciation: [kɛːtə kɔlvɪt͡s]), (8 July 1867 – 22 April 1945) was a German artist, who worked with drawing, etching, lithography, woodcuts, painting, printmaking, and sculpture. Her most famous art cycles, including The Weavers and The Peasant War, depict the effects of poverty, hunger, and war on the working class. Despite the realism of her early works, her art is now more closely associated with Expressionism. Kollwitz was the first woman elected to the Prussian Academy of Arts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Freundlich, Otto">
				<description>Englisch description: Otto Freundlich (10 July 1878 – 9 March 1943) was a German painter and sculptor of Jewish origin and one of the first generation of abstract artists.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kolbe, Georg">
				<description>German description: Georg Kolbe (* 15. April 1877 in Waldheim, Sachsen; † 20. November 1947 in Berlin) war ein figürlicher Bildhauer und Medailleur. Nach ihm sind der Georg-Kolbe-Preis und das Georg Kolbe Museum benannt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rodin, Auguste">
				<description>Englisch description: François Auguste René Rodin (12 November 1840 – 17 November 1917), known as Auguste Rodin (/oʊˈɡuːst roʊˈdæn/; French: [oɡyst ʁɔdɛ̃]), was a French sculptor. Although Rodin is generally considered the progenitor of modern sculpture, he did not set out to rebel against the past. He was schooled traditionally, took a craftsman-like approach to his work, and desired academic recognition, although he was never accepted into Paris's foremost school of art. Sculpturally, Rodin possessed a unique ability to model a complex, turbulent, deeply pocketed surface in clay. Many of his most notable sculptures were roundly criticized during his lifetime. They clashed with predominant figurative sculpture traditions, in which works were decorative, formulaic, or highly thematic. Rodin's most original work departed from traditional themes of mythology and allegory, modeled the human body with realism, and celebrated individual character and physicality. Rodin was sensitive to the controversy surrounding his work, but refused to change his style. Successive works brought increasing favor from the government and the artistic community. From the unexpected realism of his first major figure – inspired by his 1875 trip to Italy – to the unconventional memorials whose commissions he later sought, Rodin's reputation grew, such that he became the preeminent French sculptor of his time. By 1900, he was a world-renowned artist. Wealthy private clients sought Rodin's work after his World's Fair exhibit, and he kept company with a variety of high-profile intellectuals and artists. He married his lifelong companion, Rose Beuret, in the last year of both their lives. His sculptures suffered a decline in popularity after his death in 1917, but within a few decades, his legacy solidified. Rodin remains one of the few sculptors widely known outside the visual arts community.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Meunier, Constantin">
				<description>German description: Constantin Émile Meunier (* 12. April 1831 in Etterbeek bei Brüssel; † 4. April 1905 in Ixelles) war ein belgischer Bildhauer und Maler. Sein Werk ist dem Naturalismus zuzuordnen.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carstens, Asmus Jakob">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rossetti, Antonio">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Daumier, Honoré">
				<description>Englisch description: Honoré-Victorin Daumier (French: [ɔnɔʁe domje]; February 26, 1808 – February 10, 1879) was a French printmaker, caricaturist, painter, and sculptor, whose many works offer commentary on social and political life in France in the 19th century. Daumier produced over 500 paintings, 4000 lithographs, 1000 wood engravings, 1000 drawings and 100 sculptures. A prolific draughtsman, he was perhaps best known for his caricatures of political figures and satires on the behavior of his countrymen, although posthumously the value of his painting has also been recognized.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rembrandt Harmensz. van Rijn">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nürnberger Meister um 1410/20">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bergmüller, Johann Georg">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Georg Bergmüller (15 April 1688 – 2 April 1762) was a painter, particularly of frescoes, of the Baroque.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Correggio">
				<description>German description: Correggio steht für:

Correggio (Emilia-Romagna), eine italienische Stadt in der Provinz Reggio EmiliaCorreggio ist der Familienname folgender Personen:

Antonio da Correggio (eigentlich Antonio Allegri; 1489–1534) italienischer, aus Corregio stammender Maler
Josef Correggio (1810–1891), deutscher Maler und Opernsänger
Joseph Kaspar Correggio (1870–1962), deutscher Maler
Ludwig Correggio (* 1846; † 1920 oder 1930), deutscher Landschaftsmaler
Max Correggio (1854–1908), deutscher Tier- und Landschaftsmaler</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Romano, Giulio">
				<description>German description: Giulio Romano (* 1499 in Rom; † 1. November 1546 in Mantua; auch Giulio Pippi; eigentlich Giulio di Pietro Gianuzzi) war ein italienischer Maler, Architekt und Baumeister des Manierismus. Seine durch die Spätwerke Raffaels und Michelangelos inspirierte Malweise und seine freie und persönliche Interpretation der architektonischen Formensprache der Renaissance machten ihn zu einem Meister des Manierismus in Italien. Kenntnisse über sein Werk waren durch Marcantonio Raimondis Kupferstiche auch im übrigen Europa verbreitet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Palma il Giovane, Jacopo">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bandinelli, Baccio">
				<description>German description: Baccio Bandinelli, eigentlich Bartolommeo Brandini, (* 7. Oktober 1488 oder 12. November 1493 in Florenz; † kurz vor dem 7. Februar 1560 ebenda) war ein italienischer Bildhauer.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vasari, Giorgio">
				<description>German description: Giorgio Vasari (* 30. Juli 1511 in Arezzo; † 27. Juni 1574 in Florenz) war ein italienischer Architekt, Hofmaler der Medici und Biograph italienischer Künstler, darunter Leonardo da Vinci, Raffael und Michelangelo. Er gilt durch seine Schriften über das Leben und Werk zeitgenössischer Meister als einer der ersten Kunsthistoriker. Vasari führte den Begriff der Gotik ein, allerdings abwertend: Als Verehrer der Ästhetik der antiken Kunst empfand er diesen mittelalterlichen Kunststil als fremdartig, barbarisch, wirr (italienisch gotico). Auch die Stilbezeichnung Manierismus geht auf ihn zurück. In seinen Beschreibungen der italienischen Künstler verwendete Vasari 1550 zudem als Erster das Wort rinascita (Renaissance).</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mellan, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Claude Mellan (23 May 1598 – 9 September 1688) was a French draughtsman, engraver, and painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Lorrain, Claude">
				<description>Englisch description: Claude Lorrain (French: [klod lɔ.ʁɛ̃]; born Claude Gellée [ʒəle], called le Lorrain in French; traditionally just Claude in English; c. 1600 – 23 November 1682) was a French painter, draughtsman and engraver of the Baroque era. He spent most of his life in Italy, and is one of the earliest important artists, apart from his contemporaries in Dutch Golden Age painting, to concentrate on landscape painting. His landscapes are usually turned into the more prestigious genre of history paintings by the addition of a few small figures, typically representing a scene from the bible or classical mythology. By the end of the 1630s he was established as the leading landscapist in Italy, and enjoyed high prices for his work. These gradually became larger, but with fewer figures, more carefully painted, and produced at a lower rate. He was not generally an innovator in landscape painting, except in introducing the sun into many paintings, which had been rare before. He is now thought of as a French painter, but was born in the independent Duchy of Lorraine, and almost all his painting was done in Italy; before the late 19th century he was regarded as a painter of the "Roman School". His patrons were also mostly Italian, but after his death he became very popular with English collectors, and the UK retains a high proportion of his works. He was a prolific creator of drawings in pen and very often monochrome watercolour "wash", usually brown but sometimes grey. Chalk is sometimes used for under-drawing, and white highlighting in various media may be employed, much less often other colours such as pink. These fall into three fairly distinct groups. Firstly there are large numbers of sketches, mostly of landscapes, and apparently very often done at the scene; these have been greatly admired, and influenced other artists. Then there are studies for paintings, of various degrees of finish, many clearly done before or during the process of painting, but others perhaps after that was complete. This was certainly the case for the last group, the 195 drawings recording finished paintings collected in his Liber Veritatis (now British Museum). He produced over 40 etchings, often simplified versions of paintings, mainly before 1642. These served various purposes for him, but are now regarded as much less important than his drawings. He painted frescoes in his early career, which played an important part in making his reputation, but are now nearly all lost.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schütz, Christian Georg">
				<description>German description: Christian Georg Schütz ist der Name folgender Personen:

Christian Georg Schütz der Ältere (1718–1791), deutscher Maler und Kupferstecher
Christian Georg Schütz der Vetter (1758–1823), deutscher Maler und Radierer
Christian Georg Schütz der Jüngere (1803–1821), deutscher Maler</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fragonard, Jean-Honoré">
				<description>German description: Jean-Honoré Fragonard [ʒã onoˈʀe fʀaɡoˈnɑʀ] (* 5. April 1732 in Grasse (Alpes-Maritimes); † 22. August 1806 in Paris) war ein französischer Maler, Zeichner und Radierer des Rokoko zur Zeit des Ancien Régime. Er war Schüler François Bouchers und entwickelte dessen Malstil konzeptionell weiter. Fragonard bildete sich dann in Rom weiter aus und wurde nach seiner Rückkehr durch sein Bild Koresos und Kallirrhoe Mitglied der Akademie. Dem herrschenden Geschmack entsprechend, verließ er das Fach der historischen Malerei ganz und wurde zu einem Maler der Erotik und des heiteren Lebensgenusses im Stil von Antoine Watteau. Neben Boucher und Watteau gehört er zu den drei Meistern des französischen Rokoko. In der Französischen Revolution verlor er sein durch zahlreiche Staffelei- und Dekorationsmalereien erworbenes Vermögen und starb, da er sich der neuen klassizistischen Richtung nicht mit Erfolg anzuschließen vermochte, in Armut und Vergessenheit. Seine Bilder wurden von den bekanntesten Kupferstechern seiner Zeit reproduziert; zudem schuf er selbst Kupferstiche nach eigenen Motiven und nach Tintoretto, Giovanni Lanfranco, Sebastiano Ricci, Annibale Carracci, Giovanni Battista Tiepolo und anderen. Sein Sohn Alexandre-Évariste Fragonard wurde Bildhauer und Maler, sein Cousin Honoré Fragonard war Anatom und Präparator. Fragonards Arbeitsstil zeichnet sich durch eine flockige und lockere Malweise aus (ähnlich Tiepolo). Dadurch wirken seine Figuren weniger porzellanhaft und lebendiger als die Bouchers. Teilweise erinnert seine grobe Pinselführung an Werke von Frans Hals und ist wie bei diesem vorausweisend auf den Impressionismus. Der Asteroid (8235) Fragonard ist seit 1999 nach ihm benannt.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moreau, Louis Gabriel">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Boissieu, Jean-Jacques de">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Jacques de Boissieu (Lyon November 30, 1736 – March 1, 1810 Lyon) was a French draughtsman, etcher and engraver Boissieu was born at Lyon, and studied at the École Gratuite de Dessin in his home town, but was mostly self-taught. He began making prints in the period 1758–64, then went to Italy in the retinue of the ambassador Louis Alexandre, Duc de la Rochefoucauld d'Enville (1743–1792); he met Voltaire on his way, and returned with a collection of landscape drawings. Jean-Jacques de Boissieu realised some plates for the Diderot-d'Alembert Encyclopédie. He continued to produce prints in Lyon, which earned him a reputation as the last representative of the older etching tradition. Boissieu made many etchings of the Roman and Dutch countryside, as well as the countryside around Lyon. He was also sought after as a reproductive engraver. His pupils included Louis Nicolas Philippe Auguste de Forbin and his nephew Claude Victor de Boissieu.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Bourgeois, Constant">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Mind, Gottfried">
				<description>Englisch description: Gottfried Mind (German pronunciation: [ˈɡɔtfriːd ˈmɪnd]; 25 September 1768 – 17 November 1814) was a Swiss autistic savant who specialized in drawing. He was called the Raphael of Cats because of the excellence with which he painted that animal.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Alt, Jakob">
				<description>Englisch description: Jakob Alt (27 September 1789 – 30 September 1872) was a German painter and lithographer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Reinermann, Friedrich Christian">
				<description>German description: Friedrich Christian Reinermann (* 5. Oktober 1764 in Wetzlar; † 7. Februar 1835 in Frankfurt am Main) war ein in Wetzlar tätiger deutscher Landschaftsmaler, Radierer und Professor an der Städelschule.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Clovio, Giulio">
				<description>Englisch description: Giorgio Giulio Clovio or Juraj Julije Klović (1498 – January 5, 1578) was a illuminator, miniaturist, and painter born in the Kingdom of Croatia, who was mostly active in Renaissance Italy. He is considered the greatest illuminator of the Italian High Renaissance, and arguably the last very notable artist in the long tradition of the illuminated manuscript, before some modern revivals.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Watteau, Jean-Antoine">
				<description>Englisch description: Jean-Antoine Watteau (French: [ʒan‿ɑ̃twan vato]; baptised October 10, 1684 – died July 18, 1721), better known as Antoine Watteau, was a French painter whose brief career spurred the revival of interest in colour and movement, as seen in the tradition of Correggio and Rubens. He revitalized the waning Baroque style, shifting it to the less severe, more naturalistic, less formally classical Rococo. Watteau is credited with inventing the genre of fêtes galantes, scenes of bucolic and idyllic charm, suffused with a theatrical air. Some of his best known subjects were drawn from the world of Italian comedy and ballet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Boucher, François">
				<description>Englisch description: François Boucher (French: [fʁɑ̃swa buʃe]; 29 September 1703 – 30 May 1770) was a French painter, draughtsman and etcher, who worked in the Rococo style. Boucher is known for his idyllic and voluptuous paintings on classical themes, decorative allegories, and pastoral scenes. He was perhaps the most celebrated painter and decorative artist of the 18th century. He also painted several portraits of his patroness, Madame de Pompadour.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Morgenstern, Johann Ludwig Ernst">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Ludwig Ernst Morgenstern (born 22 September 1738 in Rudolstadt; died 13 November 1819 in Frankfurt am Main) was a German painting-restorer, etcher and painter.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Müntz, Johann Heinrich">
				<description>Englisch description: Johann Heinrich Müntz (1727–1798) was an Alsatian-Swiss painter and architect, known when working in England as John Henry Muntz. He was in England for seven years, and at the heart of a group trying to adapt the rococo to architecture and interior design. He has been seen as a pioneer of the Gothic Revival.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Alt, Rudolf von">
				<description>German description: Rudolf Ritter von Alt (* 28. August 1812 in der Alservorstadt, heute Wien; † 12. März 1905 in Wien) war ein österreichischer Maler und Aquarellist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Klenze, Leo von">
				<description>Englisch description: Leo von Klenze (Franz Karl Leopold von Klenze; 29 February 1784, Buchladen (Bockelah / Bocla) near Schladen – 26 January 1864, Munich) was a German neoclassicist architect, painter and writer. Court architect of Bavarian King Ludwig I, Leo von Klenze was one of the most prominent representatives of Greek revival style.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kobell, Wilhelm von">
				<description>German description: Wilhelm Alexander Wolfgang Kobell, seit 1818 Ritter von Kobell (* 6. April 1766 in Mannheim; † 15. Juli 1853 in München) war ein deutscher Landschafts-, Tier- und Schlachtenmaler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Nussbaum, Jakob">
				<description>German description: Jakob Nussbaum (* 8. Januar 1873 in Rhina, heute Teil der Gemeinde Haunetal, Kreis Hersfeld-Rotenburg in Hessen; † 19. Dezember 1936 in Kinneret am See Genezareth im damaligen Mandatsgebiet Palästina) war ein Maler des deutschen Impressionismus. Neben Paul Klimsch war er einer von zwei Frankfurter Künstlern in der Berliner Secession.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Gheyn II, Jacques de">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Huysum, Jan van">
				<description>German description: Jan van Huysum (* 15. April 1682 in Amsterdam; † 8. Februar 1749 ebenda) war ein niederländischer Maler, dessen Werke im 18. Jahrhundert sehr gefragt waren.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hendriks, Wybrand">
				<description>German description: Wybrand Hendriks (* 24. Juni 1744 in Amsterdam; † 28. Januar 1831 in Haarlem) war ein niederländischer Maler und Kustos des Teylers Museums in Haarlem. 
Wybrand Hendriks wurde in einer Bildhauerfamilie als Sohn des Bildhauers Hendrik Hendriksz (ca. 1704–1782) und seiner Frau Aaltje Claasdr geboren. Beide seine Brüder (Hendrik der Jüngere und Frans) wurden auch Bildhauer. Seine einzige Schwester, Cornelia, heiratete den Bildhauer Rijk Rijke.
Wybrand Hendriks erlernte das Malerhandwerk bei der Arbeit in der Tapetenfabrik von Johannes Remmers in Amsterdam. 1772 kaufte er eine Tapetenfirma von Anthony Palthe. Im Jahr 1775 heiratete er Palthes Witwe Agatha Ketel. Im gleichen Jahr besuchte er England und Belgien.
In den 1780er Jahren war er fünf Jahre lang einer der Direktoren der Haarlemer Zeichenakademie. Von 1786 bis 1819 war er Kurator der Teyler-Stiftung in Haarlem und wohnte im "Fundatiehuis".
Wybrand Hendricks kümmerte sich um die Bereicherung der Museumssammlungen. Er erwarb 1790 eine bedeutende Sammlung von 1700 italienischen Zeichnungen aus der Sammlung der Königin Christina von Schweden (Sammlung Odescalchi) mit Werken von Michelangelo und Raphael.
Nach dem Tode seiner Ehefrau Agatha Ketel 1802 heiratete sie 1806 Geertruid Harmsen, die 1817 starb.
Zwei Jahre später zog er in ein Haus am Oude Gracht, wo er 1831 im Alter von 86 Jahren starb.
Er schuf hauptsächlich Porträts, u. a. des Arztes und Wissenschaftlers Martinus van Marum, sowie Landschaften und Stillleben.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rottmann, Carl">
				<description>German description: Carl Anton Joseph Rottmann (* 11. Januar 1797 in Handschuhsheim (heute zu Heidelberg); † 7. Juli 1850 in München) war ein deutscher Landschaftsmaler und berühmtester Vertreter der Malerfamilie Rottmann (etwa zwischen 1770 und 1880). Rottmann gehörte dem Künstlerkreis um den bayerischen König Ludwig I. an und wurde von ihm exklusiv mit der Erstellung großformatiger Landschaftsgemälde beauftragt. Er ist für mythisch-heroisierende Landschaftsmalerei bekannt. Der Griechenlandzyklus gilt als sein Hauptwerk. Zu seinen Schülern gehörten die Landschaftsmaler Karl Lindemann-Frommel, Karl Ludwig Seeger und August Löffler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Soutter, Louis">
				<description>Englisch description: Louis Soutter (1871–1942) was a Swiss engineer, architect, painter, and musician. Soutter studied engineering in Lausanne, architecture in Geneva, violin in Brussels, and painting in Lausanne and in Paris. In Brussels he met Madge Fursman, a young American whom he married, after which he moved to the United States, where he gave drawing and violin lessons before becoming director of the Department of Fine Arts at Colorado College. Soutter became depressed and in 1902 returned to Switzerland, where he became a violinist in the orchestra of the Grand Théâtre de Genève and the Symphonic Orchestra of Lausanne. In 1922, he was institutionalized in the hospital of Eclagnens and later in the retirement home (Asile de Jura) in Ballaigues, where he would spend the rest of his life. In 1927, his cousin Le Corbusier became interested in his drawings and began supporting him. He left "a remarkable body of work whose profound modernity has only recently come to light":The interest shown in his work by such important figures as Roberto Matta (1911-2002), and the impact it would have on the art of Arnulf Rainer (1929), Julian Schnabel (1951), A.R. Penck (1939) and Elmar Trenkwalder (1959), confirm him as an artist of the twentieth century whose work has its place in reflections by contemporary artists.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fohr, Carl Philipp">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Eysen, Louis">
				<description>German description: Louis Eysen (* 23. November 1843 in Manchester; † 21. Juli 1899 in München) war ein deutscher Landschafts- und Porträtmaler.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Dyck, Anthonis van">
				<description>German description: Sir Anthonis van Dyck, flämisch Antoon van Dyck (* 22. März 1599 in Antwerpen; † 9. Dezember 1641 in London), war ein flämischer Maler (insbesondere Porträts) und Grafiker des flämischen Barocks und freier Mitarbeiter von Peter Paul Rubens. Weitere Versionen seines Namens sind Anton van Dyck und Anthony van Dyck.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goltzius, Hendrick">
				<description>German description: Hendrick Goltzius (* Januar oder Februar 1558 in Bracht, heute Ortsteil von Brüggen im Kreis Viersen –  bei Venlo; † 29. Dezember 1616 oder 1. Januar 1617 in Haarlem) war ein niederländischer Maler und Kupferstecher. Sein Werk ist dem Manierismus zuzuordnen.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cuyp, Aelbert">
				<description>German description: Aelbert Jacobsz. Cuyp (* in Dordrecht, getauft Ende Oktober 1620; † ebenda, begraben 15. November 1691) war einer der bedeutendsten niederländischen Landschaftsmaler des 17. Jahrhunderts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hessemer, Friedrich Maximilian">
				<description>Englisch description: Friedrich Maximilian Hessemer (24 February 1800 in Darmstadt – 1 December 1860 in Frankfurt am Main) was a German architect and author.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Burgkmair, Hans">
				<description>German description: Hans Burgkmair der Ältere (* 1473 in Augsburg; † 1531 ebenda) war ein bedeutender Maler,Zeichner und Entwerfer für den Holzschnitt zu Beginn des 16. Jahrhunderts. Er gilt neben Hans Holbein dem Älteren und Hans Holbein dem Jüngeren als wichtigster Augsburger Künstler zwischen Spätgotik und Renaissance.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schongauer, Martin">
				<description>German description: Martin Schongauer (* um 1445/1450 in Colmar, Elsass; † 2. Februar 1491 in Breisach am Rhein) war ein deutscher Kupferstecher und Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Moholy-Nagy, László">
				<description>Englisch description: László Moholy-Nagy (/məˌhoʊliˈnɒdʒ/; Hungarian: [ˈlaːsloː ˈmoholinɒɟ]; born László Weisz; July 20, 1895 – November 24, 1946) was a Hungarian painter and photographer as well as a professor in the Bauhaus school. He was highly influenced by constructivism and a strong advocate of the integration of technology and industry into the arts.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Popova, Ljubov S.">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sieneser (?) Meister der ersten Hälfte des 15. Jahrhunderts">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Guercino (Giovanni Francesco Barbieri)">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Atget, Eugène">
				<description>Englisch description: Eugène Atget (French: [adʒɛ]; 12 February 1857 – 4 August 1927) was a French flâneur and a pioneer of documentary photography, noted for his determination to document all of the architecture and street scenes of Paris before their disappearance to modernization. Most of his photographs were first published by Berenice Abbott after his death. An inspiration for the surrealists and other artists, his genius was only recognized by a handful of young artists in the last two years of his life, and he did not live to see the wide acclaim his work would eventually receive.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Baldus, Édouard">
				<description>German description: Édouard Baldus (* 5. Juni 1813 als Eduard Baldus in Grünebach; † 22. Dezember 1889 in Arcueil-Cachan) war ein deutsch-französischer Fotograf. Er ist einer der Pioniere der Fotografie und gilt als erster professioneller Architekturfotograf. Sein Werk Chemin de fer de Paris à Lyon et à la Méditerranée aus dem Jahr 1863 gehört zu den bedeutendsten Fotobüchern der Geschichte. Außerdem erfand er 1855 ein eigenes Verfahren zur Fotogravur (Héliogravure), das die Grundlage für eine umfangreiche verlegerische Tätigkeit wurde.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Cameron, Julia Margaret">
				<description>Englisch description: Julia Margaret Cameron (née Pattle; 11 June 1815 Calcutta – 26 January 1879 Kalutara, Ceylon) was a British photographer. She became known for her portraits of celebrities of the time, and for photographs with Arthurian and other legendary or heroic themes. Cameron's photographic career was short, spanning eleven years of her life (1864–1875). She took up photography at the relatively late age of 48, when she was given a camera as a present.Her style was not widely appreciated in her own day: her choice to use a soft focus and to treat photography as an art as well as a science, by manipulating the wet collodion process, caused her works to be viewed as "slovenly", "mistakes" and bad photography. She found more acceptance among pre-Raphaelite artists than among photographers. Her work has influenced modern photographers, especially her closely cropped portraits. Her house, Dimbola Lodge, on the Isle of Wight is open to the public.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carroll, Lewis">
				<description>German description: Lewis Carroll (* 27. Januar 1832 in Daresbury im County Cheshire; † 14. Januar 1898 in Guildford im County Surrey; eigentlich Charles Lutwidge Dodgson) war ein britischer Schriftsteller des viktorianischen Zeitalters, Fotograf, Mathematiker und Diakon. Er ist der Autor der berühmten Kinderbücher Alice im Wunderland, Alice hinter den Spiegeln (oder Alice im Spiegelland) und The Hunting of the Snark. Mit seiner Befähigung für Wortspiel, Logik und Fantasie schaffte er es, weite Leserkreise zu fesseln. Seine Werke, als sogenannte Nonsense-Literatur bezeichnet, sind bis heute populär geblieben und haben nicht nur die Kinderliteratur, sondern ebenso Schriftsteller wie James Joyce, die Surrealisten wie André Breton und den Maler und Bildhauer Max Ernst oder den Kognitionswissenschaftler Douglas R. Hofstadter beeinflusst. Bekannt wurde Carroll auch als Fotograf: Wie Julia Margaret Cameron und Oscar Gustave Rejlander betrieb er bereits ab der Mitte des 19. Jahrhunderts Fotografie als Kunst.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Fenton, Roger">
				<description>Englisch description: Roger Fenton (28 March 1819 – 8 August 1869) was a pioneering British photographer, one of the first war photographers.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Frith, Francis">
				<description>German description: Francis Frith, manchmal auch Frances Frith, (* 31. Oktober 1822 in Chesterfield, Derbyshire; † 25. Februar 1898 in Cannes, Frankreich) war ein englischer Photograph, der durch seine Aufnahmen aus dem Orient und vieler britischer Städte berühmt wurde.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hill, David Octavius">
				<description>Englisch description: David Octavius Hill (20 May 1802 – 17 May 1870) was a Scottish painter and arts activist. He formed Hill &amp; Adamson studio with the engineer and photographer Robert Adamson between 1843 and 1847 to pioneer many aspects of photography in Scotland.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Marville, Charles">
				<description>Englisch description: Charles Marville, the pseudonym of Charles François Bossu (Paris 17 July 1813 – 1 June 1879 Paris), was a French photographer, who mainly photographed architecture, landscapes and the urban environment. He used both paper and glass negatives. He is most well known for taking pictures of ancient Parisian quarters before they were destroyed and rebuilt under "Haussmannization", Baron Haussmann's new plan for modernization of Paris. In 1862, he was named official photographer of Paris.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Salomon, Erich">
				<description>German description: Erich Franz Emil Salomon (* 28. April 1886 in Berlin; † 7. Juli 1944 in Auschwitz) war ein deutscher Jurist, Fotograf und Bildjournalist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Sommer, Giorgio">
				<description>German description: Giorgio Sommer (* 2. September 1834 in Frankfurt am Main; † 7. August 1914 in Neapel) war ein deutscher Fotograf, der hauptsächlich in Italien arbeitete.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vogel, Hermann Wilhelm">
				<description>German description: Hermann Wilhelm Vogel (* 26. März 1834 in Dobrilugk; † 17. Dezember 1898 in Charlottenburg) war ein deutscher Fotochemiker und Entdecker der Farbsensibilatoren für die naturgetreue Farbwiedergabe von Fotografien.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Kühn, Heinrich">
				<description>German description: Carl Christian Heinrich Kühn (* 25. Februar 1866 in Dresden; † 14. September 1944 in Birgitz) war ein deutsch-österreichischer Fotograf und Fotopionier.Er war mit Hans Watzek und Hugo Henneberg in der Künstlergruppe Wiener Kleeblatt zusammengeschlossen.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Stieglitz, Alfred">
				<description>Englisch description: Alfred Stieglitz (January 1, 1864 – July 13, 1946) was an American photographer and modern art promoter who was instrumental over his fifty-year career in making photography an accepted art form. In addition to his photography, Stieglitz was known for the New York art galleries that he ran in the early part of the 20th century, where he introduced many avant-garde European artists to the U.S. He was married to painter Georgia O'Keeffe.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Vidal, Léon">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Diefenbach, Karl Wilhelm">
				<description>Englisch description: Karl Wilhelm Diefenbach (February 21, 1851, Hadamar, Duchy of Nassau – December 15, 1913, Capri) was a German painter and social reformer.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Zwengauer, Anton">
				<description>Englisch description: Anton Zwengauer (11 October 1810 – 13 June 1884) was a German painter of the Biedermeier period.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Raffael">
				<description>German description: Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino, auch Raffael da Urbino, Raffaello Santi [rafːaˈɛlːo ˈsanti], Raffaello Sanzio [ˈsantsi̯o] oder kurz Raffael (* 6. April oder 28. März 1483 in Urbino; † 6. April 1520 in Rom) war ein italienischer Maler und Architekt. Er gilt als einer der bedeutendsten Künstler der italienischen Hochrenaissance.
Raffael erlangte vor allem als Maler für seine harmonischen und ausgewogenen Kompositionen und lieblichen Madonnenbilder Berühmtheit. Zu Lebzeiten genoss er das Privileg, nur unter seinem Vornamen bekannt zu sein, und noch heute kennen die wenigsten seinen Nachnamen. Bis weit in das 19. Jahrhundert hinein galt er als der größte Maler aller Zeiten. Neben seiner Laufbahn als Maler in Florenz und am päpstlichen Hof in Rom wurde er auch Bauleiter des Petersdoms und Aufseher über die römischen Antiken.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hammershøi, Vilhelm">
				<description>German description: Vilhelm Hammershøi (* 15. Mai 1864 in Kopenhagen; † 13. Februar 1916 in Kopenhagen) war ein dänischer Maler und gilt als Vertreter des Symbolismus. Seine melancholischen Interieurs, Porträts, Landschafts- und Architekturdarstellungen erinnern an den US-amerikanischen Maler James McNeill Whistler, den Hammershøi sehr verehrte. Dem auch als „dänischer Vermeer“ bezeichneten Maler wurden, seit seiner „Wiederentdeckung“ in den 1990er Jahren, Retrospektiven im Musée d’Orsay und im Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum gewidmet.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Carrière, Eugène">
				<description>German description: Eugène Carrière (* 18. Januar 1849 in Gournay-sur-Marne; † 27. März 1906 in Paris) war ein französischer Maler und Lithograf. Der Symbolist ist bekannt für seine Porträts von Künstlern und Dichtern seiner Zeit sowie für düstere, schemenhaften Gemälde von Frauen und Kindern.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Watts, George Frederick">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Goya, Francisco de">
				<description>German description: Francisco José de Goya y Lucientes (* 30. März 1746 in Fuendetodos, Aragón, Spanien; † 16. April 1828 in Bordeaux) war ein spanischer Maler und Grafiker des ausgehenden 18. und frühen 19. Jahrhunderts.
</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Hasenpflug, Carl Georg Adolph">
				<description>No description</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ribera, Jusepe de">
				<description>Englisch description: José de Ribera (January 12, 1591 – September 2, 1652) was a Spanish Tenebrist painter and printmaker, better known as Jusepe de Ribera. He also was called Lo Spagnoletto ("the Little Spaniard") by his contemporaries and early writers. Ribera was a leading painter of the Spanish school, although his mature work was all done in Italy.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Rosso, Medardo">
				<description>Englisch description: Medardo Rosso (Italian: [meˈdardo ˈrosso]; 20 or 21 June 1858, Turin, Italy – 31 March 1928, Milan) was an Italian sculptor. He is considered, like Auguste Rodin, a Post Impressionism artist.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Allori, Cristofano">
				<description>German description: Cristofano Allori, auch Bronzino der Jüngere (* 17. Oktober 1577 in Florenz; † 2. April 1621 ebenda) war ein italienischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Ribot, Théodule">
				<description>German description: Augustin Théodule Ribot (* 8. August 1823 in Saint-Nicolas-d'Attez, Eure; † 11. September 1891 in Colombes, Hauts-de-Seine) war ein französischer Maler.</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Schjerfbeck, Helene">
				<description>Englisch description: Helene Schjerfbeck (July 10, 1862 – January 23, 1946, pronounced IPA: [he'le:n 'ɧærvbek] in Standard Swedish and IPA: [helɛ:n ʃærvbek] in Finland Swedish) was a Finnish painter. She is most widely known for her realist works and self-portraits, and less well known for her landscapes and still lifes. Throughout her long life, her work changed dramatically. Her work starts with a dazzlingly skilled, somewhat melancholic version of late-19th-century academic realism…it ends with distilled, nearly abstract images in which pure paint and cryptic description are held in perfect balance. (Roberta Smith, New York Times, November 27th 1992)</description>
			</Artist>
			<Artist name="Brandi, Giacinto">
				<description>Englisch description: Giacinto Brandi (1621 – 19 January 1691) was an Italian painter of the Baroque era, active mainly in Rome and Naples.</description>
			</Artist>
		</AllPerson>
	<Allstyle><style stylename="Baroque"><description>Englisch description: The Baroque (US /bəˈroʊk/ or UK /bəˈrɒk/) is often thought of as a period of artistic style that used exaggerated motion and clear, easily interpreted detail to produce drama, tension, exuberance, and grandeur in sculpture, painting, architecture, literature, dance, theater, and music. The style began around 1600 in Rome and Italy, and spread to most of Europe. The popularity and success of the Baroque style was encouraged by the Catholic Church, which had decided at the time of the Council of Trent, in response to the Protestant Reformation, that the arts should communicate religious themes in direct and emotional involvement. The aristocracy also saw the dramatic style of Baroque architecture and art as a means of impressing visitors and expressing triumph, power and control. Baroque palaces are built around an entrance of courts, grand staircases and reception rooms of sequentially increasing opulence. However, "baroque" has resonance and application that extend beyond a simple reduction to either style or period.</description></style><style stylename="Renaissance"><description>Englisch description: The Renaissance (UK /rᵻˈneɪsəns/, US /rɛnəˈsɑːns/) is a period in European history, from the 14th to the 17th century, regarded as the cultural bridge between the Middle Ages and modern history. It started as a cultural movement in Italy in the Late Medieval period and later spread to the rest of Europe, marking the beginning of the Early Modern Age. The intellectual basis of the Renaissance was its own invented version of humanism, derived from the rediscovery of classical Greek philosophy, such as that of Protagoras, who said that "Man is the measure of all things." This new thinking became manifest in art, architecture, politics, science and literature. Early examples were the development of perspective in oil painting and the recycled knowledge of how to make concrete. Although the invention of metal movable type sped the dissemination of ideas from the later 15th century, the changes of the Renaissance were not uniformly experienced across Europe. As a cultural movement, the Renaissance encompassed innovative flowering of Latin and vernacular literatures, beginning with the 14th-century resurgence of learning based on classical sources, which contemporaries credited to Petrarch; the development of linear perspective and other techniques of rendering a more natural reality in painting; and gradual but widespread educational reform. In politics, the Renaissance contributed to the development of the customs and conventions of diplomacy, and in science to an increased reliance on observation and inductive reasoning. Although the Renaissance saw revolutions in many intellectual pursuits, as well as social and political upheaval, it is perhaps best known for its artistic developments and the contributions of such polymaths as Leonardo da Vinci and Michelangelo, who inspired the term "Renaissance man". The Renaissance first began in Florence, in the 14th century. Various theories have been proposed to account for its origins and characteristics, focusing on a variety of factors including the social and civic peculiarities of Florence at the time: its political structure; the patronage of its dominant family, the Medici; and the migration of Greek scholars and texts to Italy following the Fall of Constantinople to the Ottoman Turks. Other major centres were northern Italian city-states such as Venice, Genoa, Milan, Bologna, and finally Rome during the Renaissance Papacy. The Renaissance has a long and complex historiography, and, in line with general scepticism of discrete periodizations, there has been much debate among historians reacting to the 19th-century glorification of the "Renaissance" and individual culture heroes as "Renaissance men", questioning the usefulness of Renaissance as a term and as a historical delineation. The art historian Erwin Panofsky observed of this resistance to the concept of "Renaissance": It is perhaps no accident that the factuality of the Italian Renaissance has been most vigorously questioned by those who are not obliged to take a professional interest in the aesthetic aspects of civilization—historians of economic and social developments, political and religious situations, and, most particularly, natural science—but only exceptionally by students of literature and hardly ever by historians of Art. Some observers have called into question whether the Renaissance was a cultural "advance" from the Middle Ages, instead seeing it as a period of pessimism and nostalgia for classical antiquity, while social and economic historians, especially of the longue durée, have instead focused on the continuity between the two eras, which are linked, as Panofsky observed, "by a thousand ties". The word Renaissance, literally meaning "Rebirth" in French, first appeared in English in the 1830s. The word also occurs in Jules Michelet's 1855 work, Histoire de France. The word Renaissance has also been extended to other historical and cultural movements, such as the Carolingian Renaissance and the Renaissance of the 12th century.</description></style><style stylename="Late Middle Ages"><description>German description: Als Spätmittelalter wird der Zeitraum der europäischen Geschichte von der Mitte des 13. bis zum Ende des 15. oder Anfang des 16. Jahrhunderts bezeichnet (also ca. 1250 bis 1500). Sie stellt die Endphase des Mittelalters dar, auf welche die Frühe Neuzeit folgt. Eine generelle zeitliche Eingrenzung des Übergangs vom Spätmittelalter in die Renaissance ist nicht möglich, da letztere wesentlich aus der kulturphilosophischen und kunstgeschichtlichen Entwicklung heraus definiert ist. Je nachdem, wie offen die jeweiligen Gelehrten und Mäzene in den europäischen Kulturzentren der neuen Entwicklung gegenüberstanden, breitete sich die Renaissance in den europäischen Regionen unterschiedlich schnell aus. Das Spätmittelalter wurde in der älteren Forschung aufgrund von bestimmten Erscheinungen in Kunst und Kultur, Agrarproblemen sowie politischen Veränderungen im römisch-deutschen Reich oft als Krisenzeit betrachtet. Diese negative Bewertung betraf vor allem die deutsche Mediävistik, weil dort die Abfolge des Mittelalters in drei Stufen prägend war und man für das Spätmittelalter nicht zuletzt eine politische Krisenzeit festzustellen glaubte, eine „Verfallszeit“. In Italien oder Frankreich wurde keine derartig scharfe Trennung vorgenommen. In der neueren deutschsprachigen Forschung wird ebenfalls sehr viel differenzierter geurteilt, vor allem aufgrund neuer Forschungsansätze und neuer Quellenbefunde: Bei allen auftretenden Problemen war das Spätmittelalter geprägt von einer gestiegenen Mobilität und Internationalität, Veränderungen in diversen Lebensbereichen und schließlich dem Übergang in die Frühmoderne. Insofern hat ein deutlicher Paradigmenwechsel in der deutschen Spätmittelalterforschung stattgefunden.</description></style><style stylename="romanticism"><description>Englisch description: Romanticism (also known as the Romantic era) was an artistic, literary, musical and intellectual movement that originated in Europe toward the end of the 18th century, and in most areas was at its peak in the approximate period from 1800 to 1850. Romanticism was characterized by its emphasis on emotion and individualism as well as glorification of all the past and nature, preferring the medieval rather than the classical.   It was partly a reaction to the Industrial Revolution, the aristocratic social and political norms of the Age of Enlightenment, and the scientific rationalization of nature—all components of modernity. It was embodied most strongly in the visual arts, music, and literature, but had a major impact on historiography, education, the social sciences, and the natural sciences. It had a significant and complex effect on politics, with romantic thinkers influencing liberalism, radicalism, conservatism and nationalism.The movement emphasized intense emotion as an authentic source of aesthetic experience, placing new emphasis on such emotions as apprehension, horror and terror, and awe—especially that experienced in confronting the new aesthetic categories of the sublimity and beauty of nature. It elevated folk art and ancient custom to something noble, but also spontaneity as a desirable characteristic (as in the musical impromptu). In contrast to the Rationalism and Classicism of the Enlightenment, Romanticism revived medievalism and elements of art and narrative perceived as authentically medieval in an attempt to escape population growth, early urban sprawl, and industrialism.
Although the movement was rooted in the German Sturm und Drang movement, which preferred intuition and emotion to the rationalism of the Enlightenment, the events and ideologies of the French Revolution were also proximate factors. Romanticism assigned a high value to the achievements of "heroic" individualists and artists, whose examples, it maintained, would raise the quality of society. It also promoted the individual imagination as a critical authority allowed of freedom from classical notions of form in art. There was a strong recourse to historical and natural inevitability, a Zeitgeist, in the representation of its ideas. In the second half of the 19th century, Realism was offered as a polar opposite to Romanticism. The decline of Romanticism during this time was associated with multiple processes, including social and political changes and the spread of nationalism.


</description></style><style stylename="classicism"><description>Englisch description: Classicism, in the arts, refers generally to a high regard for a classical period, classical antiquity in the Western tradition, as setting standards for taste which the classicists seek to emulate. The art of classicism typically seeks to be formal and restrained: of the Discobolus Sir Kenneth Clark observed, "if we object to his restraint and compression we are simply objecting to the classicism of classic art. A violent emphasis or a sudden acceleration of rhythmic movement would have destroyed those qualities of balance and completeness through which it retained until the present century its position of authority in the restricted repertoire of visual images." Classicism, as Clark noted, implies a canon of widely accepted ideal forms, whether in the Western canon that he was examining in The Nude (1956), or the literary Chinese classics or Chinese art, where the revival of classic styles is also a recurring feature.
Classicism is a force which is often present in post-medieval European and European influenced traditions; however, some periods felt themselves more connected to the classical ideals than others, particularly the Age of Enlightenment, when Neoclassicism was an important movement in the visual arts.
</description></style><style stylename="realism"><description>Englisch description: Realism, Realistic, or Realists may refer to:

Philosophical realism, belief that reality exists independently of observers. Related positions include:
Aesthetic realism (metaphysics)
Agential realism (Barad)
Australian realism
Austrian realism
Conceptualist realism (Wiggins)
Critical realism (disambiguation)
Dialectical realism (Hacking)
Direct realism
Empirical realism
Entity realism
Hermeneutic realism (Heidegger)
Internal realism (Putnam)
Local realism, a term used by Einstein in the context of the principle of locality
Logical realism, the conviction the rules of logic are mind-independent
Metaphysical realism
Modal realism
Model-dependent realism (Hawking and Mlodinow)
Moderate realism
Moral realism
Naïve realism
New realism (philosophy)
Peircean realism
Platonic realism
Quasi-realism
Realistic rationalism (Katz)
Referential realism
Romantic realism
Scientific realism
Musgrave's scientific realism
Scotistic realism
Semantic realism (epistemology) (a position criticized by Dummett)
Semantic realism (philosophy of science) (Psillos)
Semirealism (Chakravartty)
Set-theoretic realism (Maddy)
Speculative realism
Structuralism (philosophy of science)
Transcendental realism (Schelling, Schopenhauer, Bhaskar)
Truth-value link realism (a position criticized by Dummett)Realist views in the social sciences include:
Ethnographic realism, a writing style that narrates the author's anthropological observations as if they were first-hand
Legal realism, the view that jurisprudence should emulate the methods of natural science, i.e., rely on empirical evidence
Realism (international relations), the view that world politics is driven by competitive self-interest
Neorealism (international relations)
Structural realism, in international relationsRealism (arts), the general attempt to depict subjects truthfully. Related movements include:
Literary realism, a movement from the mid 19th to the early 20th century
Neorealism (art)
Italian neorealism (film)
Indian neorealism (film)
New realism, a movement founded in 1960
Realism (art movement), 19th-century painting group
Theatrical realism, one of the many types of theatre such as Naturalism
Vienna School of Fantastic Realism, an art movement</description></style><style stylename="Impressionism"><description>Englisch description: Impressionism is a 19th-century art movement that originated with a group of Paris-based artists whose independent exhibitions brought them to prominence during the 1870s and 1880s. Impressionist painting characteristics include relatively small, thin, yet visible brush strokes, open composition, emphasis on accurate depiction of light in its changing qualities (often accentuating the effects of the passage of time), ordinary subject matter, inclusion of movement as a crucial element of human perception and experience, and unusual visual angles. The Impressionists faced harsh opposition from the conventional art community in France. The name of the style derives from the title of a Claude Monet work, Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which provoked the critic Louis Leroy to coin the term in a satirical review published in the Parisian newspaper Le Charivari. The development of Impressionism in the visual arts was soon followed by analogous styles in other media that became known as impressionist music and impressionist literature.</description></style><style stylename="symbolism"><description>Englisch description: Symbolism or symbolist may refer to:
</description></style><style stylename="Post-Impressionism"><description>Englisch description: Post-Impressionism (also spelled Postimpressionism) is a predominantly French art movement that developed roughly between 1886 and 1905, from the last Impressionist exhibition to the birth of Fauvism. Post-Impressionism emerged as a reaction against Impressionists' concern for the naturalistic depiction of light and colour. Due to its broad emphasis on abstract qualities or symbolic content, Post-Impressionism encompasses Neo-Impressionism, Symbolism, Cloisonnism, Pont-Aven School, and Synthetism, along with some later Impressionists' work. The movement was led by Paul Cézanne, Paul Gauguin, Vincent van Gogh, and Georges Seurat. The term Post-Impressionism was first used by art critic Roger Fry in 1906. Critic Frank Rutter in a review of the Salon d'Automne published in Art News, 15 October 1910, described Othon Friesz as a "post-impressionist leader"; there was also an advert for the show The Post-Impressionists of France. Three weeks later, Roger Fry used the term again when he organized the 1910 exhibition, Manet and the Post-Impressionists, defining it as the development of French art since Manet. Post-Impressionists extended Impressionism while rejecting its limitations: they continued using vivid colours, often thick application of paint, and real-life subject matter, but were more inclined to emphasize geometric forms, distort form for expressive effect, and use unnatural or arbitrary colour.</description></style><style stylename="expressionism"><description>Englisch description: Expressionism was a modernist movement, initially in poetry and painting, originating in Germany at the beginning of the 20th century. Its typical trait is to present the world solely from a subjective perspective, distorting it radically for emotional effect in order to evoke moods or ideas. Expressionist artists sought to express the meaning of emotional experience rather than physical reality.Expressionism was developed as an avant-garde style before the First World War. It remained popular during the Weimar Republic, particularly in Berlin. The style extended to a wide range of the arts, including expressionist architecture, painting, literature, theatre, dance, film and music.The term is sometimes suggestive of angst. In a general sense, painters such as Matthias Grünewald and El Greco are sometimes termed expressionist, though the term is applied mainly to 20th-century works. The Expressionist emphasis on individual perspective has been characterized as a reaction to positivism and other artistic styles such as Naturalism and Impressionism.</description></style><style stylename="Bauhaus"><description>Englisch description: The Bauhaus was founded by Walter Gropius in Weimar. In spite of its name and the fact that its founder was an architect, the Bauhaus, during the first years of existence, did not have an architecture department. Nonetheless, it was founded with the idea of creating a "total" work of art (Gesamtkunstwerk) in which all arts, including architecture, would eventually be brought together. The Bauhaus style later became one of the most influential currents in modern design, Modernist architecture and art, design and architectural education. The Bauhaus had a profound influence upon subsequent developments in art, architecture, graphic design, interior design, industrial design, and typography. The school existed in three German cities: Weimar from 1919 to 1925, Dessau from 1925 to 1932 and Berlin from 1932 to 1933, under three different architect-directors: Walter Gropius from 1919 to 1928, Hannes Meyer from 1928 to 1930 and Ludwig Mies van der Rohe from 1930 until 1933, when the school was closed by its own leadership under pressure from the Nazi regime, having been painted as a centre of communist intellectualism. Although the school was closed, the staff continued to spread its idealistic precepts as they left Germany and emigrated all over the world. The changes of venue and leadership resulted in a constant shifting of focus, technique, instructors, and politics. For example, the pottery shop was discontinued when the school moved from Weimar to Dessau, even though it had been an important revenue source; when Mies van der Rohe took over the school in 1930, he transformed it into a private school, and would not allow any supporters of Hannes Meyer to attend it.</description></style><style stylename="New Objectivity"><description>Englisch description: The New Objectivity (in German: Neue Sachlichkeit) was a movement in German art that arose during the 1920s as a reaction against expressionism. The term was coined by Gustav Friedrich Hartlaub, the director of the Kunsthalle in Mannheim, who used it as the title of an art exhibition staged in 1925 to showcase artists who were working in a post-expressionist spirit. As these artists—who included Max Beckmann, Otto Dix, and George Grosz—rejected the self-involvement and romantic longings of the expressionists, Weimar intellectuals in general made a call to arms for public collaboration, engagement, and rejection of romantic idealism. Although principally describing a tendency in German painting, the term took a life of its own, and came to characterize the attitude of public life in Weimar Germany as well as the art, literature, music, and architecture created to adapt to it. Rather than some goal of philosophical objectivity, it was meant to imply a turn towards practical engagement with the world—an all-business attitude, understood by Germans as intrinsically American. The movement essentially ended in 1933 with the fall of the Weimar Republic and the rise of the Nazis to power.</description></style><style stylename="Late Gothic"><description>Englisch description: Late Gothic may refer to:

A period of Gothic art also known as International Gothic
A period of Gothic architecture</description></style><style stylename="High Renaissance"><description>Englisch description: In art history, High Renaissance is the period denoting the apogee of the visual arts in the Italian Renaissance. The High Renaissance period is traditionally taken to begin in the 1490s, with Leonardo's fresco of the Last Supper in Milan and the death of Lorenzo de' Medici in Florence, and to have ended in 1527 with the sacking of Rome by the troops of Charles V. This term was first used in German (Hochrenaissance) in the early nineteenth century, and has its origins in the "High Style" of painting and sculpture described by Johann Joachim Winckelmann. Over the last twenty years, use of the term has been frequently criticized by academic art historians for oversimplifying artistic developments, ignoring historical context, and focusing only on a few iconic works.</description></style><style stylename="Late Renaissance"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="Italian Mannerism"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="rococo"><description>Englisch description: 


Rococo ( or ), less commonly roccoco, or "Late Baroque", was a highly ornamental and theatrical style of decoration which combined asymmetry, scrolling curves, gilding, white and pastel colors, sculpted molding, and trompe l'oeil frescoes to create the illusions of surprise, motion and drama. It first appeared in France and Italy in the 1730s and spread to Central Europe in the 1750s and 1760s. It is often described as the final expression of the Baroque movement.The Rococo style began in France in the first part of the 18th century in the reign of Louis XV  as a reaction against the more formal and geometric Style Louis XIV. It was known as the style rocaille, or rocaille style. It soon spread other parts of Europe, particularly northern Italy, Bavaria, Austria, other parts of Germany, and Russia. It also came to influence the other arts, particularly sculpture, furniture, silverware and glassware, painting,  music, and theatre.</description></style><style stylename="Late Baroque"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="Nazarene"><description>Englisch description: Nazarene may refer to:
</description></style><style stylename="art brut"><description>German description: Die Art brut (franz. [Aussprache: aʁ bʁyt] für „rohe Kunst“) ist ein Sammelbegriff für autodidaktische Kunst von Laien, Kindern, Menschen mit einer psychischen Erkrankung oder einer geistigen Behinderung. Die Bezeichnung ging vom französischen Maler Jean Dubuffet aus, der sich eingehend mit einer naiven und antiakademischen Ästhetik beschäftigte. Art brut beschreibt eine Kunst jenseits etablierter Formen und Strömungen. Im anglo-amerikanischen Sprachraum ist stattdessen der Begriff Outsider Art („Außenseiter-Kunst“) gebräuchlich.
</description></style><style stylename="Constructivism"><description>Englisch description: Constructivism may refer to:

Constructive theology
Constructivism (art), an early 20th-century artistic movement that extols art as a practice for social purposes
Constructivism (international relations), a theory that stresses the socially constructed character of international relations
Constructivism (philosophy of education), a theory about the nature of learning that focuses on how humans make meaning from their experiences
Constructivism in science education
Constructivist teaching methods, based on constructivist learning theory
Constructivism (philosophy of mathematics), a philosophical view that asserts the necessity of constructing a mathematical object to prove that it exists
Constructivism (psychological school), a psychological approach that assumes that human knowledge is active and constructive
Constructivist architecture, an architectural movement in Russia in the 1920s and 1930s
Constructivist epistemology, a philosophy maintaining that science consists of mental constructs created as the result of measuring the natural world
Social constructivism, a theory that human development is socially situated and knowledge is constructed through interaction with others
Constructivist institutionalism
Constructivist type theory</description></style><style stylename="cubism"><description>Englisch description: Cubism is an early-20th-century art movement which brought European painting and sculpture historically forward toward 20th century Modern art. Cubism in its various forms inspired related movements in literature and architecture. Cubism has been considered to be among the most influential art movements of the 20th century. The term is broadly used in association with a wide variety of art produced in Paris (Montmartre, Montparnasse and Puteaux) during the 1910s and throughout the 1920s.
The movement was pioneered by Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque, joined by Jean Metzinger, Albert Gleizes, Robert Delaunay, Henri Le Fauconnier, and Fernand Léger. One primary influence that led to Cubism was the representation of three-dimensional form in the late works of Paul Cézanne. A retrospective of Cézanne's paintings had been held at the Salon d'Automne of 1904, current works were displayed at the 1905 and 1906 Salon d'Automne, followed by two commemorative retrospectives after his death in 1907. In Cubist artwork, objects are analyzed, broken up and reassembled in an abstracted form—instead of depicting objects from a single viewpoint, the artist depicts the subject from a multitude of viewpoints to represent the subject in a greater context.The impact of Cubism was far-reaching and wide-ranging. In other countries Futurism, Suprematism, Dada, Constructivism, De Stijl and Art Deco developed in response to Cubism. Early Futurist paintings hold in common with Cubism the fusing of the past and the present, the representation of different views of the subject pictured at the same time, also called multiple perspective, simultaneity or multiplicity, while Constructivism was influenced by Picasso's technique of constructing sculpture from separate elements. Other common threads between these disparate movements include the faceting or simplification of geometric forms, and the association of mechanization and modern life.
</description></style><style stylename="surrealism"><description>Englisch description: Surrealism is a cultural movement that began in the early 1920s, and is best known for its visual artworks and writings. Artists painted unnerving, illogical scenes with photographic precision, created strange creatures from everyday objects, and developed painting techniques that allowed the unconscious to express itself. Its aim was to "resolve the previously contradictory conditions of dream and reality into an absolute reality, a super-reality".Surrealist works feature the element of surprise, unexpected juxtapositions and non sequitur; however, many surrealist artists and writers regard their work as an expression of the philosophical movement first and foremost, with the works being an artifact. Leader André Breton was explicit in his assertion that Surrealism was, above all, a revolutionary movement.
Surrealism developed out of the Dada activities during World War I and the most important center of the movement was Paris. From the 1920s onward, the movement spread around the globe, eventually affecting the visual arts, literature, film, and music of many countries and languages, as well as political thought and practice, philosophy, and social theory.
</description></style><style stylename="art photography"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="abstract sculpture"><description>No description</description></style><style stylename="early Baroque"><description>No description</description></style></Allstyle></records>